<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="FixToFix" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.conversions.FixToFix">
  <description>
This actor converts a FixToken into another FixToken with a specified&#10; precision. Note that this conversion may be lossy, in that the output&#10; may be an approximation of the input. The approximation can be&#10; constructed using a variety of rounding and overflow strategies,&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The precision of the output is given by the &lt;i&gt;precision&lt;/i&gt; parameter,&#10; which is an integer matrix of the form [&lt;i&gt;m&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;], where&#10; the total number of bits in the output is &lt;i&gt;m&lt;/i&gt;, of which&#10; &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; are integer bits. The default precision is [16, 2], which means&#10; that an output has 16 bits, of which 2 bits represent the&#10; integer part.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The rounding strategy is defined by the &lt;i&gt;rounding&lt;/i&gt; parameter and&#10; defaults to &lt;i&gt;nearest&lt;/i&gt; (or &lt;i&gt;half_floor&lt;/i&gt;), selecting the nearest&#10; representable value. The floor value nearer to minus infinity is used&#10; for values half way between representable values. Other strategies&#10; such as &lt;i&gt;truncate&lt;/i&gt; are described under ptolemy.math.Rounding.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The overflow strategy is defined by the &lt;i&gt;overflow&lt;/i&gt; parameter and&#10; defaults to &lt;i&gt;saturate&lt;/i&gt; (or &lt;i&gt;clip&lt;/i&gt;). Out of range values are&#10; saturated to the nearest representable value. Other strategies&#10; such as &lt;i&gt;modulo&lt;/i&gt; are described under ptolemy.math.Overflow.  </description>
  <author>Bart Kienhuis, Edward A. Lee, Ed Willink</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (pwhitake)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Green (pwhitake)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="precision">The precision of the output fix-point number, represented by an&#10;     integer matrix.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute-->
    <property name="rounding">The rounding strategy used, such as &quot;nearest&quot; or &quot;truncate&quot;.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute-->
    <property name="overflow">The overflow strategy used to convert a double into a fix point,&#10;     such as &quot;saturate&quot; or &quot;to_zero&quot;.</property>
</doc>
