<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="TerrainProperty" class="ptolemy.domains.wireless.lib.TerrainProperty">
  <description>
This actor models an obstacle that attenuates signals that&#10; traverse it. The obstacle has a geometry given by the &lt;i&gt;xyPoints&lt;/i&gt;&#10; parameter. By default, the attenuation is infinite, meaning&#10; that the obstacle completely blocks a signal. By increasing&#10; the &lt;i&gt;attenuationDepth&lt;/i&gt; parameter you can specify partial&#10; attenuation that depends on the geometry of the obstacle.&#10; If &lt;i&gt;attenuationDepth&lt;/i&gt; has value &lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt; and the signal&#10; traverses distance &lt;i&gt;y&lt;/i&gt; through the obstacle, then the&#10; power of the signal is reduced by a factor of&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10;   exp(log(0.5) * y / x)&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; Thus, if &lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt; = &lt;i&gt;y&lt;/i&gt;, then the power is reduced to&#10; half (3dB).  The algorithm used here only works for convex&#10; obstacle shapes.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor implements the PropertyTransformer interface.&#10; It register itself with the wireless channel specified by&#10; the &lt;i&gt;channelName&lt;/i&gt; parameter. The channel may call it&#10; getProperty() method to get the property.  </description>
  <author>Yang Zhao and William Douglas (contributor: Edward A. Lee)</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (pjb2e)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="channelName">The name of the channel.  The default name is &quot;TerrainChannel&quot;.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="attenuationDepth">The width of material that will attenuate a signal power by&#10;  50% (3dB).  This has the same units as the xyPoints parameter,&#10;  which specifies the geometry of the obstacle.&#10;  The default value is 0.0, which means infinite attenuation&#10;  (no signal gets through).</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="xyPoints">The x/y coordinates of the obstacle. This is an array&#10;  of integers specifying a geometry. The icon will have&#10;  the same geometry.&#10;  The default value is an array of integer pairs:&#10;  {{0, 0}, {0, 5}, {20, 5}, {20, 0}}</property>
</doc>
