<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="ArrayPlotter" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.gui.ArrayPlotter">
  <description>
&lt;p&gt;A plotter that plots a sequence of arrays of doubles.&#10; This plotter contains an instance of the Plot&#10; class from the Ptolemy plot package as a public member. Data at&#10; the input, which can consist of any number of channels, are plotted&#10; on this instance.  Each input channel is plotted as a separate data set.&#10; Each input token is an array of doubles.&lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The &lt;i&gt;iterationsPerUpdate&lt;/i&gt; parameter can be used to fine tune&#10; the display.  It can be quite expensive to generate the display, and&#10; by default, this actor generates it on every firing.  If&#10; &lt;i&gt;iterationsPerUpdate&lt;/i&gt; is set to some integer greater than&#10; one, then it specifies how many iterations should be executed&#10; between updates. Thus, if &lt;i&gt;iterationsPerUpdate&lt;/i&gt; = 2, then every&#10; second time this actor fires, it will update the display. That is,&#10; it will update its display on the first firing, the third, the&#10; fifth, etc. It will, however, consume its inputs on every firing.&#10; The plot is always updated in the wrapup() method.&lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Note that this can be used to generate live plots, like SequenceScope,&#10; but it has fewer drawing artifacts than SequenceScope since it does&#10; not use XOR drawing mode.&lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 3.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="input">Input port, which receives an array of doubles.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="iterationsPerUpdate">The number of iterations between updates of the display&#10;  on the screen.&#10;  This parameter has type IntToken, with default value 1.&#10;  Its value must be non-negative.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="xUnit">The increment of the X axis.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="xInit">The start point of the X axis.</property>
</doc>
