<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="MACActorBase" class="ptolemy.domains.wireless.lib.network.mac.MACActorBase">
  <description>
This is a base class designed for the MAC actors. Since these actors&#10; largely share a set of parameters, we would like to declare them here&#10; to avoid repeatly do the same amount of work in every MAC actor.&#10; FIXME: Currently, the parameters in this actor are extracted from&#10; the ChannelState component...&#10;&#10; This actor also defines a set of constant that are widely used in&#10; the OMNET c++ classes.&#10;&#10; Based on this, it is relatively easy to translate a OMNET class&#10; to a actor here.  </description>
  <author>Yang Zhao</author>
  <version>MACActorBase.java,v 1.22 2004/04/22 19:46:17 ellen_zh Exp</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (pjb2e)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="aSifsTime">The parameter for SIFS (Short Inter Frame Space). This time&#10;  is used to separate transmissions belong to a single dialog.&#10;  This Value is fixed per PHY and is calculated base on&#10;  the time that takes for the transmitting part to switch back&#10;  to receive mode.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="aPreambleLength">The size of the Preamble header in a frame. The Preamble&#10;  header contains synchronization information and timing&#10;  information for the frame.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="aPlcpHeaderLength">The size of the PLCP header in a frame. The PLCP header&#10;  contains logical information for the physical layer to&#10;  decode the frame.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="aRxTxTurnaroundTime">Time needed for a transceiver to go from receiving to transmitting</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="sAckCtsLng">The size of a CTS/Ack message</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="mBrate">The radio data rate in the unit of Mbps</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="aSlotTime">The time unit for the backoff time</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="aRxRfDelay">The nominal time between the end of a symbol at the air interface to&#10;  the issuance of a PMD-DATA.indicate to the PLCP.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="aRxPlcpDelay">The nominal time that the PLCP uses to deliver a bit from the PMD&#10;  receive path to the MAC.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="aCWmin">The minimum size of the contention window, in units of aSlotTime.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="aCWmax">The maximum size of the contention window, in units of aSlotTime.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="dot11ShortRetryLimit">The maximum number of retransmissions for MPDUs</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="dot11LongRetryLimit">The maximum number of retransmissions for RTS</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="dotllRTSThreshold">The threshold for the length of a MPDU, below which a RTS is not&#10;  necessary.</property>
</doc>
