<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="TxCoordination" class="ptolemy.domains.wireless.lib.network.mac.TxCoordination">
  <description>
TXCoordination class is responsible for initiating a session. After a packet&#10; arrives from the network layer, TXCoordination will generate RTS if the packet&#10; is long enough. It will send RTS to the destination and wait for CTS. If CTS&#10; is received within a specified interval, data will be sent after SIFS seconds.&#10; If ACK is received within a given time after the data is sent, the session&#10; is complete. TXCoordination will go to backoff before handling the next packet&#10; in the queue.If the network packet is not long enough, RTS/CTS will not be used&#10; to reduce overhead. In either case, Carrier sense is only done for the first&#10; message in the sequence, which is RTS, retransmitted data or data if RTS is not&#10; used. TXCoordination gets the channel status by sending a backoff signal with&#10; count 0 to the Backoff process in the Transmission block.If the channel turns&#10; to be busy, TXCoordination will send another backoff signal with count -1 to&#10; start the real backoff. If CTS or ACK is not received in time, the corresponding&#10; RTS or data will neeed to be retransmitted. TXCoordination will increase the&#10; corresponding retry counters. The backoff window size is also exponentially&#10; increased Retransmission will not start until another backoff is completed to&#10; avoid congestion.  </description>
  <author>Charlie Zhong, Yang Zhao</author>
  <version>TxCoordination.java,v 1.13 2004/04/22 19:46:17 ellen_zh Exp</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (czhong)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (reviewmoderator)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="PduRequest">Port receiving messages from the network layer</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="TXTXConfirm">Port receiving confirmation from the Transmission block</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="BkDone">Port receiving backoff complete notification from the Backoff process</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="GotAck">Port receiving the notification of the receipt of either Ack or Cts&#10;  from the RxCoordination process</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="fromPowerControl">Port receiving messages from the PowerControl block</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="getBackoff">Port sending the backoff request to the Backoff process</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="TXTXRequest">Port sending the TX request to the Transmission block</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="overhead">Port sending overhead of handling a pdu request.</port>
</doc>
