<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Philosopher" class="ptolemy.domains.csp.demo.DiningPhilosophers.Philosopher">
  <description>
A philosopher sits at a table with 4 other philosophers. Between&#10; each two philosophers there is a chopstick. A Philosopher eats when he has&#10; both chopsticks next to him. A Philosopher thinks for a while, then tries&#10; to eat. When he succeeds in obtaining both chopsticks he eats for a while,&#10; then puts both chopsticks back on the table and continues thinking.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Due to the rendezvous nature of communication in the CSP domain, a&#10; philosopher stalls if it tries to get a chopstick but cannot. When&#10; it acquires the chopstick, it eats for a while and then sends a&#10; message to the chopstick to say that it is finished using it.&#10; Note this actor has been slowed down with Thread.sleep() statements to&#10; mimic the eating nature of the philosophers in real time.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor is parameterized by three parameters: &quot;eatingRate&quot; which&#10; controls the distribution of the eating times, and &quot;thinkingRate&quot;&#10; which controls the distribution of the thinking times. Both these&#10; rates characterize a uniform distribution between 0 and the rate.&#10; &lt;p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Neil Smyth</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 0.3</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (nsmyth)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="leftIn">The port through which this philosopher&#10;  is granted access to the left chopstick.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="leftOut">The port through which this philosopher&#10;  releases access to the left chopstick.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="rightIn">The port through which this philosopher&#10;  is granted access to the right chopstick.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="rightOut">The port through which this philosopher&#10;  releases access to the right chopstick.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="eating">This parameter determines the rate at which&#10;  this philosopher will spend time eating.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="thinking">This parameter determines the rate at which&#10;  this philosopher will spend time thinking.</property>
</doc>
