<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="LinearStateSpace" class="ptolemy.domains.continuous.lib.LinearStateSpace">
  <description>
Linear state space model in the CT domain.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;The State-Space model implements a system whose behavior is defined by:&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10; dx/dt = Ax + Bu&#10; y = Cx + Du&#10; x(0) = x0&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; where x is the state vector, u is the input vector, and y is the output&#10; vector. The matrix coefficients must have the following characteristics:&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10; A must be an n-by-n matrix, where n is the number of states.&#10; B must be an n-by-m matrix, where m is the number of inputs.&#10; C must be an r-by-n matrix, where r is the number of outputs.&#10; D must be an r-by-m matrix.&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; The actor accepts &lt;i&gt;m&lt;/i&gt; inputs and generates &lt;i&gt;r&lt;/i&gt; outputs&#10; through a multi-input port and a multi-output port. The widths of the&#10; ports must match the number of rows and columns in corresponding&#10; matrices, otherwise, an exception will be thrown.&#10; &lt;P&gt;&#10; This actor works like a higher-order function. It is opaque after&#10; construction or the change of parameters. Upon preinitialization,&#10; the actor will create a subsystem using integrators, adders, and&#10; scales. After that, the actor becomes transparent, and the director&#10; takes over the control of the actors contained by this actor.&#10; &lt;P&gt;&#10; This actor is based on the&#10; ptolemy.domains.ct.lib.LinearStateSpace actor by Jie Liu.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee, Contributor: Jie Liu</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 8.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (liuj)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="input">Multi-input port.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">Multi-output port.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="stateOutput">State output multiport.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="A">The A matrix in the state-space representation. It must be a&#10;  square matrix.&#10;  The default value is [[1.0]].</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="B">The B matrix in the state-space representation. The number of&#10;  rows must equal to the number of rows of the A matrix. The number&#10;  of columns must equal to the width of the input port.&#10;  The default value is [[1.0]].</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="C">The C matrix in the state-space representation. The number of&#10;  columns must equal to the number of columns of the A matrix.&#10;  The number of rows must equal to the width of the output port.&#10;  The default value is [[1.0]].</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="D">The D matrix in the state-space representation. The number of&#10;  columns must equal to the width of the input port.&#10;  The number of rows must equal to the width of the output port.&#10;  The default value is [[0.0]].</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="initialStates">The initial condition for the state variables. This must be&#10;  a vector (double matrix with only one row) whose length equals&#10;  to the number of state variables.&#10;  The default value is [0.0].</property>
</doc>
