<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="ResourcePool" class="ptolemy.domains.csp.lib.ResourcePool">
  <description>
This actor manages a pool of resources, where each resource is&#10; represented by a token with an arbitrary value.  Resources are&#10; granted on the &lt;i&gt;grant&lt;/i&gt; output port and released on the&#10; &lt;i&gt;release&lt;/i&gt; input port. These ports are both multiports,&#10; so resources can be granted to multiple users of the resources,&#10; and released by multiple actors.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The initial pool of resources is provided by the &lt;i&gt;initialPool&lt;/i&gt;&#10; parameter, which is an array of arbitrary type.  The &lt;i&gt;grant&lt;/i&gt;&#10; output port and &lt;i&gt;release&lt;/i&gt; input port are constrained to have&#10; compatible types. Specifically, the &lt;i&gt;grant&lt;/i&gt; output port must be&#10; able to send tokens with types that match the elements of this array,&#10; and it must also be able to send tokens with types that match&#10; inputs provided at the &lt;i&gt;release&lt;/i&gt; input.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor is designed for use in the CSP domain, where it will&#10; execute in its own thread. At all times, it is ready to&#10; rendezvous with any other actor connected to its &lt;i&gt;release&lt;/i&gt;&#10; input port.  When such a rendezvous occurs, the token provided&#10; at that input is added to the resource pool. In addition,&#10; whenever the resource pool is non-empty, this actor is ready&#10; to rendezvous with any actor connected to its &lt;i&gt;grant&lt;/i&gt;&#10; output port. When such a rendezvous occurs, it sends&#10; the first token in the resource pool to that output port&#10; and removes that token from the resource pool.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 5.2</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="grant">The output port through which this actor grants resources.&#10;  This port has type equal to the element type&#10;  of the &lt;i&gt;initialPool&lt;/i&gt; parameter.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="release">The input port through which other actors release resources.&#10;  This port has type equal to the element type&#10;  of the &lt;i&gt;initialPool&lt;/i&gt; parameter.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="initialPool">The initial resource pool. This is an array with default&#10;  value {1} (an integer array with one entry with value 1).</property>
</doc>
