<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="PSDFScheduler" class="ptolemy.domains.psdf.kernel.PSDFScheduler">
  <description>
A scheduler that implements basic scheduling of PSDF graphs.  PSDF&#10; scheduling is similar to SDF scheduling, EXCEPT:&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; 1) Because parameter values may change, the solution to the&#10; balance equation is computed symbolically.  i.e. the repetitions&#10; vector is a function of the parameter values.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; 2) Because the firing vector may change, the schedule determined&#10; by this class can only be a quasi-static, or parameterized schedule.&#10; Note that parameterized schedules cannot generally be constructed for&#10; models with feedback or with unconstrained parameter values.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; This class uses a ConstVariableModelAnalysis to determine which&#10; scheduling parameters are constants and which may change during&#10; execution of the model.  Rate parameters that can change are checked&#10; to ensure that their change context is not strictly contained by the&#10; model being scheduled.  If this is the case, then the actor is not&#10; locally synchronous, and cannot be statically scheduled.  Dynamic&#10; parameters with a valid changed context are treated symbolically when&#10; computing the repetitions vector.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; After computing a schedule, this scheduler determines the external&#10; rate of each of the model's external ports.  Since the firing vector&#10; is only computed symbolically, these rates can also only be computed&#10; symbolically.  The dependence of these external rates on the rates of&#10; ports in the model is declared using a DependenceDeclaration.  Higher&#10; level directors may use this dependence information to determine the&#10; change context of those rate variables and may refuse to schedule the&#10; composite actor if those rates imply that this model is not locally&#10; synchronous.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; This scheduler uses a version of the P-APGAN scheduling algorithm&#10; described in [1].&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; [1] B. Bhattacharya and S. S. Bhattacharyya. Quasi-static scheduling of&#10; reconfigurable dataflow graphs for DSP systems. In &lt;em&gt; Proceedings of the&#10; International Workshop on Rapid System Prototyping &lt;/em&gt;,&#10; pages 84-89, Paris, France, June 2000.  </description>
  <author>Stephen Neuendorffer, Shuvra S. Bhattacharyya</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 3.1</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (neuendor)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (neuendor)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
</doc>
