<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="OrderedMerge" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.OrderedMerge">
  <description>
This actor merges two monotonically nondecreasing streams of tokens into&#10; one monotonically nondecreasing stream. On each firing, it reads data from&#10; one of the inputs.  On the first firing, it simply records that token.&#10; On the second firing, it reads data from the other input and outputs&#10; the smaller of the recorded token and the one it just read.  If they&#10; are equal, then it outputs the recorded token. It then&#10; records the larger token.  On each subsequent firing, it reads a token&#10; from the input port that did not provide the recorded token, and produces&#10; at the output the smaller of the recorded token and the one just read.&#10; Each time it produces an output token, it also produces&#10; &lt;i&gt;true&lt;/i&gt; on the &lt;i&gt;selectedA&lt;/i&gt; output&#10; if the output token came from &lt;i&gt;inputA&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;false&lt;/i&gt;&#10; if it came from &lt;i&gt;inputB&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; If both input sequences are nondecreasing, then the output sequence&#10; will be nondecreasing.&#10; Note that if the inputs are not nondecreasing, then the output is&#10; rather complex.  The key is that in each firing, it produces the smaller&#10; of the recorded token and the token it is currently reading.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 2.0.1</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (eal)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="inputA">The first input port, which accepts any scalar token.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="inputB">The second input port, which accepts any scalar token with&#10;  the same type as the first input port.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">The output port, which has the same type as the input ports.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="selectedA">Output port indicating whether the output token came from&#10;  &lt;i&gt;inputA&lt;/i&gt;.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="eliminateDuplicates">If true, eliminate duplicate tokens in the output stream.&#10;  This is a boolean that defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="inputA_tokenConsumptionRate">The token consumption rate for &lt;i&gt;inputA&lt;/i&gt;.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="inputB_tokenConsumptionRate">The token consumption rate for &lt;i&gt;inputB&lt;/i&gt;.</property>
</doc>
