<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="RecordAssembler" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.RecordAssembler">
  <description>
On each firing, read one token from each connected input port and assemble&#10; them into a RecordToken. Disconnected input ports are ignored. The labels for&#10; the RecordToken much match the names of the input ports. This is achieved&#10; using two type constraints:&#10;&#10; &lt;ul&gt;&#10; &lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;output &amp;ge; {x = typeOf(inputPortX), y = typeOf(inputPortY), ..}&#10; &lt;/tt&gt;, which requires the types of the input ports to be compatible&#10; with the corresponding types in the output record.&#10; &lt;/li&gt;&#10; &lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;each input &amp;ge; the type of the corresponding field inside the&#10; output record&lt;/tt&gt;, which together with the first constraint forces&#10; the input types to be exactly equal to the types of the corresponding&#10; fields in the output record. This constraint is intended to back-&#10; propagate type information upstream, not to assure type compatibility.&#10; Therefore, this constraint is only set up for input ports that do not&#10; already have a type declared.&lt;/li&gt;&#10; &lt;/ul&gt;&#10; Note that the output record is not required to contain a corresponding&#10; field for every input, as downstream actors might require fewer fields&#10; in the record they accept for input.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; To use this class, instantiate it, and then add input ports&#10; (instances of TypedIOPort).  This actor is polymorphic. The type constraint&#10; is that the type of each record field is no less than the type of the&#10; corresponding input port.&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;Note that if the display name of a port is set, display name is used in&#10; the type constraints instead of name. This is useful in case fields to&#10; add to the record contain a period, because periods are not allowed in&#10; port names.&lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Yuhong Xiong, Marten Lohstroh</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (yuhong)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">The output port.</port>
</doc>
