<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="ResettableTimer" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.ResettableTimer">
  <description>
Produce an output after the time specified on the input has elapsed.&#10; If the input value is 0.0, then the output will be produced at the&#10; next superdense time index (i.e., on the next firing, but at the current&#10; time). If the input is negative, this actor will cancel the previously&#10; requested output, if it has not yet been produced by the time the&#10; negative input is received.&#10; The value of the output is specified by the &lt;i&gt;value&lt;/i&gt; parameter.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; If the &lt;i&gt;preemptive&lt;/i&gt; parameter is true (the default), then if&#10; a new input arrives before the previous timer request has expired,&#10; then that timer request is canceled. If an input arrives at the same&#10; time that the previous timer request expires, an output is produced&#10; immediately. The timer request is not cancelled.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; If the &lt;i&gt;preemptive&lt;/i&gt; parameter is&#10; false, then the new input will cause the timer to start only after&#10; the currently pending timer (if any is pending) expires.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; When the &lt;i&gt;preemptive&lt;/i&gt; parameter is true,&#10; this actor resembles the VariableDelay actor in the DE domain, except that&#10; arrivals of new inputs before the delay has expired causes the&#10; previously scheduled output to be canceled. Also, the output value&#10; is given in this actor&#10; by the &lt;i&gt;value&lt;/i&gt; parameter instead of by the input.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; When the &lt;i&gt;preemptive&lt;/i&gt; parameter is false,&#10; this actor resembles the Server actor in the DE domain, except that&#10; the time delay is specified by the single input.&#10; The Server actor, by contrast, has separate inputs for service time and&#10; payload, and the service time experienced by a payload depends&#10; on the most recently arrived service time input &lt;i&gt;at the time&#10; that the payload service begins&lt;/i&gt;, not at the time the payload&#10; arrives.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; If this actor is used in a modal model and is in a mode that is&#10; not active for some time, then no outputs will be produced for&#10; the times it is inactive. If it becomes active again before the&#10; scheduled time to produce an output, then it will produce that&#10; output. If it is not preemptive, then upon&#10; becoming active again, it will behave as if it had been active&#10; during the intervening time, calculating when the outputs should&#10; have been produced, and discarding them if the calculated time&#10; falls in the inactive period.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 8.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (eal)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="preemptive">Indicator of whether new inputs cancel previous requests.&#10;  This is a boolean that defaults to true.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="value">The value produced at the output.  This can have any type,&#10;  and it defaults to a boolean token with value &lt;i&gt;true&lt;/i&gt;.</property>
</doc>
