<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Sequence" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.Sequence">
  <description>
This actor produces a sequence of values, optionally periodically repeating&#10; them. The &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; parameter contains an ArrayToken that specifies the&#10; sequence of values to produce at the output. If the &lt;i&gt;enable&lt;/i&gt; input&#10; port is connected, then it provides a boolean sequence that specifies&#10; whether to produce an output. If the &lt;i&gt;enable&lt;/i&gt; is present and&#10; true, then the actor will produce the next output. Otherwise, it&#10; produces no output and will produce the next in the sequence&#10; on the next firing (if enable is true). If the &lt;i&gt;holdLastOutput&lt;/i&gt;&#10; parameter is true, then the sequence is infinite, with the last&#10; value being repeated forever.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Compared with the Pulse actor, this actor can be enabled or disabled&#10; on each firing by providing a true or false input on the &lt;i&gt;enable&lt;/i&gt;&#10; port.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.1</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="enable">The enable input port.  If this port is connected, then its&#10;  input will determine whether an output is produced in any&#10;  given firing. The type is boolean.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">The output port. The type is greater than or equal to the&#10;  types of the two input ports.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="holdLastOutput">A flag indicating whether to interpret the &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt;&#10;  as an infinite sequence where the last value is repeated&#10;  forever. This is a boolean that defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="repeat">The flag that indicates whether the sequence needs to be&#10;  repeated. If this is false, then either the last value of the&#10;  sequence is repeatedly produced after the entire sequence&#10;  has been produced, or the actor stops producing output,&#10;  depending on the value of &lt;i&gt;holdLastOutput&lt;/i&gt;.&#10;  This is a boolean, and defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="values">The values that will be produced on the output.&#10;  This parameter is an array, with default value {1}.</property>
</doc>
