<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="TestExceptionAttribute" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.TestExceptionAttribute">
  <description>
This actor tests for exceptions that are expected to occur when&#10; running a test model. When an exception is&#10; thrown by the model, this actor is invoked. It has two&#10; working modes, training mode and non-training mode. If in training mode,&#10; this actor handles an exception by recording the exception message. If&#10; not in training mode, this actor first compares the previously stored&#10; (assumed correct) message to the exception message and then throws an&#10; exception if the two messages are not the same.&#10; Also, if a test runs to completion without throwing an exception, this actor&#10; throws an exception in its wrapup() method. An exception is expected.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (hyzheng)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (hyzheng)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="correctExceptionMessage">The correct exception message to be compared against.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="matchPrefixOfLength">If greater than zero, then check that the first &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&#10;  characters of the exception message match, where &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&#10;  is the value of this parameter. Otherwise, if this is zero&#10;  or negative, then check all the characters. This is an&#10;  integer that defaults to zero.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.SharedParameter-->
    <property name="trainingMode">If true, then collect the exception message and set the&#10;  correctExceptionMessage parameter with the content of the&#10;  exception. This parameter is a boolean, and it defaults to false.&#10;  It is a shared parameter, meaning&#10;  that changing it for any one instance in a model will change&#10;  it for all instances in the model.</property>
</doc>
