<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="URLDirectoryReader" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.URLDirectoryReader">
  <description>
This actor reads a URL and if the URL names a directory, it outputs&#10; the name of each file or subdirectory contained in the directory.&#10; If the URL names a file, then it outputs the name of that file.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;If the &lt;i&gt;repeat&lt;/i&gt; flag is true, then the sequence of file&#10; names is repeated indefinitely.&#10; If the &lt;i&gt;refresh&lt;/i&gt; flag is true, and the &lt;i&gt;repeat&lt;/i&gt; flag is&#10; true, then the directory is re-read before repeating the sequence of&#10; files and subdirectories.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;If the &lt;i&gt;endsWith&lt;/i&gt; String parameter is non-null and non-empty,&#10; then only file names or subdirectories that end with the value&#10; of the &lt;i&gt;endsWith&lt;/i&gt; parameter are output.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;One alternative implementation would be that if the URL named a file,&#10; then the actor would output the names of the files and subdirectories&#10; in the directory that contains the file.&#10; &lt;br&gt;Another alternative implementation would output the names of the&#10; files and subdirectories in an array.&#10; &lt;br&gt;An extension would be to include a filter parameter that could be&#10; a regular expression that would allow us to filter the file names.&#10; &lt;br&gt; Should this actor extend URLReader or SequenceActor?  </description>
  <author>Christopher Hylands</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 2.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (liuj)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (liuj)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="endsWith">If non-null and non-empty, then only output file names and sub&#10;  directories that end with this String value.&#10;        The default value of this parameter is the empty String &quot;&quot;.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="repeat">Repeat after outputting all elements of the directory.&#10;        The default value of this parameter is a false BooleanToken.</property>
</doc>
