<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="JAIPNGWriter" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.jai.JAIPNGWriter">
  <description>
Write a javax.media.jai.RenderedOp to a specified PNG file.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;The file is specified by the &lt;i&gt;fileName&lt;/i&gt; attribute&#10; using any form acceptable to FileParameter.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;If the &lt;i&gt;confirmOverwrite&lt;/i&gt; parameter has value &lt;i&gt;false&lt;/i&gt;,&#10; then this actor will overwrite the specified file if it exists without&#10; asking.  If &lt;i&gt;true&lt;/i&gt; (the default), then if the file exists, then&#10; this actor will ask for confirmation before overwriting.  </description>
  <author>James Yeh, Christopher Hylands Brooks</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="adam7Interlacing">If the Adam7 Interlacing option is false, pixels are stored&#10;  left to right and from top to bottom. If it is true (the&#10;  default), seven distinct passes are made over the image, each&#10;  transmitting a subset of the pixels.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="background">If the setBackground parameter is false, then this parameter&#10;  is ignored.  If it is true, this parameter sets the&#10;  background color of the image.  Note that this will only show&#10;  up in images with transparency.  If the image is a grayscale&#10;  image, only the first value of the array is used.  The value&#10;  is an integer that should range from 0 to (2^bitdepth - 1).&#10;  The bitdepth is defined by the bitDepth parameter in this&#10;  actor.  If the image is an RGB image, then the first 3 values&#10;  of the array are read.  Each of these also range from&#10;  0 to (2^bitdepth - 1).</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="bitDepth">The bit depth.  The initial default is an integer of value 8.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="gamma">The gamma.  The initial default is a double of value 0.455.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="setBackground">True if the background is to be set.  The initial value is false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="setGamma">True if the gamma parameter is to be used.&#10;  The initial value is false.</property>
</doc>
