<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="WirelessIOPort" class="ptolemy.domains.wireless.kernel.WirelessIOPort">
  <description>
This port communicates via channels without wired connections.&#10; Channels are instances of WirelessChannel. The port references&#10; channels by name, where the name is specified by the&#10; &lt;i&gt;outsideChannel&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;insideChannel&lt;/i&gt; parameter.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This port can be used on the boundary of wireless domain models.&#10; A port is outside wireless if an outside channel name is given and&#10; a wireless channel with the given name is contained by the container&#10; of the port's container (transparent hierarchy is not supported).&#10; Specially, it will use the specified wireless channel to communicate&#10; on the outside. A port is inside wireless if an inside channel&#10; name is given and a wireless channel with the given name is&#10; contained by the container of this port. It will use the specified&#10; wireless channel to communicate on the inside. If no outside channel&#10; or inside channel name is given or the named channel does not exist,&#10; then the behavior of the port reverts to that of the base class.&#10; Specifically, it will only communicate if it is wired.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; It is valid for a model using the wireless director to have both&#10; wireless communication and wired communication, i.e. it may contain&#10; actors with ports using wireless communication (by specifying a&#10; wireless channel) and actors with ports using wired communication.&#10; If a port is outside/inside wireless(a wireless channel is specified),&#10; it will ignore all the communication through the wired connections&#10; to it if there is any on the outside/inside of it.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The width of this port on either side that is using wireless&#10; communication is fixed at one. Otherwise, it depends on the&#10; number of links to the port.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; When this port is used for wireless communications, nothing is&#10; connected to it.  Consequently, methods that access the topology such&#10; as connectedPortList() and deepConnectedInPortList() return an empty&#10; list. There are no deeply connected ports.  However, sinkPortList()&#10; returns the port of the specified wireless channel. A consequence of&#10; this is that type constraints are automatically set up between ports&#10; that send on the channel and the channel port.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee and Xiaojun Liu</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="insideChannel">The name of the inside channel.  This is a string that defaults to&#10;  the empty string, indicating that communication is not wireless.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="insideTransmitProperties">The transmit properties of this port for inside transmissions.&#10;  This field may be used by the channel to determine transmission&#10;  range or other properties of the transmission. By default, this&#10;  has no value, which indicates to channels to use their default&#10;  properties, whatever those might be. When its value is set,&#10;  it is required to be a record type.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="outsideChannel">The name of the outside channel.  This is a string that defaults to&#10;  the empty string, indicating that communication is not wireless.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="outsideTransmitProperties">The transmit properties of this port for outside transmissions.&#10;  This field may be used by the channel to determine transmission&#10;  range or other properties of the transmission. By default, this&#10;  has no value, which indicates to channels to use their default&#10;  properties, whatever those might be. When its value is set,&#10;  it is required to be a record type.</property>
</doc>
