<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="HDFDirector" class="ptolemy.domains.hdf.kernel.HDFDirector">
  <description>
The Heterochronous Dataflow (HDF) domain is an extension of the&#10; Synchronous Dataflow (SDF) domain and implements the HDF model of&#10; computation [1]. In SDF, the set of port rates (called rate signatures)&#10; of an actor are constant. In HDF, however, rate signatures are allowed&#10; to change between iterations of the HDF schedule.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This director is often used with HDFFSMDirector. The HDFFSMDirector&#10; governs the execution of a modal model. The change of rate signatures can&#10; be modeled by state transitions of the modal model, in which each state&#10; refinement infers a set of rate signatures. Within each state, the HDF&#10; model behaves like an SDF model.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This director recomputes the schedules dynamically. To improve efficiency,&#10; this director uses a CachedSDFScheduler. A CachedSDFScheduler caches&#10; schedules labeled by their corresponding rate signatures, with the most&#10; recently used at the beginning of the queue. Therefore, when a state in HDF&#10; is revisited, the schedule identified by its rate signatures in the cache&#10; is used. We do not need to recompute the schedule.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The size of the cache in the CachedSDFScheduler is set by the&#10; &lt;i&gt;scheduleCacheSize&lt;/i&gt; parameter of HDFDirector. The default value of&#10; this parameter is 100. If the cache is full, the least recently used&#10; schedule (at the end of the cache) is discarded.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;OL&gt;&#10; &lt;LI&gt;&#10; A. Girault, B. Lee, and E. A. Lee,&#10; ``&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/papers/98/starcharts&quot;&gt;&#10; Hierarchical Finite State Machines with Multiple Concurrency Models&lt;/A&gt;,&#10; '' April 13, 1998.&lt;/LI&gt;&#10; &lt;/ol&gt;  </description>
  <author>Ye Zhou. Contributor: Brian K. Vogel</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 5.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (zhouye)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="scheduleCacheSize">A parameter representing the size of the schedule cache to use.&#10;  If the value is less than or equal to zero, then schedules&#10;  will never be discarded from the cache. The default value is 100.&#10;  &lt;p&gt;&#10;  Note that the number of schedules in an HDF model can be&#10;  exponential in the number of actors. Setting the cache size to a&#10;  very large value is therefore not recommended if the&#10;  model contains a large number of HDF actors.</property>
</doc>
