<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="StringSimpleReplace" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.string.StringSimpleReplace">
  <description>
On each firing, look for instances of the pattern specified by &lt;i&gt;pattern&lt;/i&gt;&#10; in &lt;i&gt;stringToEdit&lt;/i&gt; and replace them with the string given by&#10; &lt;i&gt;replacement&lt;/i&gt;.  If &lt;i&gt;replaceAll&lt;/i&gt; is true, then replace&#10; all instances that match &lt;i&gt;pattern&lt;/i&gt;.  Otherwise, replace only&#10; the first instance that matches.  If there is no match, then the&#10; output is the string provided by &lt;i&gt;stringToEdit&lt;/i&gt;, unchanged.&#10; The &lt;i&gt;pattern&lt;/i&gt; is &lt;b&gt;not&lt;/b&gt; a regular expression, to use&#10; a regular expression, see &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/string/StringReplace.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.lib.string.StringReplace&lt;/a&gt;.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The &lt;i&gt;replacement&lt;/i&gt; string, as usual with string-valued parameters&#10; in Ptolemy II, can include references to parameter values in scope.&#10; E.g., if the enclosing composite actor has a parameter named &quot;x&quot;&#10; with value 1, say, then the replacement string a${x}b will become&#10; &quot;a1b&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;Note that if the &lt;i&gt;pattern&lt;/i&gt; is the two character string&#10; &lt;code&gt;\r&lt;/code&gt;, then that pattern is handled specially and&#10; collapsed to the single character '\r'.  This is for use in removing&#10; \r's from test output.  </description>
  <author>Christopher Brooks</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 8.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>ret (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">The output port on which the edited string is produced.&#10;  This has type string.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.PortParameter-->
    <property name="stringToEdit">The string to edit by replacing substrings that match the&#10;  specified pattern with the specified replacement. This is&#10;  a string that defaults to the empty string.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.PortParameter-->
    <property name="pattern">The pattern used to pattern match and replace the stringToEdit&#10;  string. It is an empty string by default.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.PortParameter-->
    <property name="replacement">The replacement string that replaces any matched instance of the&#10;  pattern. It is an empty string by default.</property>
</doc>
