<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="ColtBinomialSelector" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.colt.ColtBinomialSelector">
  <description>
Assign trials from several populations using a conditional Binomial&#10; selection process.  For example, if a vector of &lt;code&gt;P&lt;/code&gt;&#10; populations are presented (as &lt;code&gt;P&lt;/code&gt; input channels) and&#10; &lt;code&gt;N&lt;/code&gt; trials is specified, then this algorithm will&#10; distribute the &lt;code&gt;N&lt;/code&gt; trials based on the proportions&#10; represented in the &lt;code&gt;P&lt;/code&gt; populations.  This is done by&#10; performing a progressively conditional Binomial selection in which&#10; &lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; change after each trial assignment&#10; step.  The Binomial trials (&lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt;) is decremented after each&#10; assignment step to represent the remaining trials, and the new&#10; Binomial probability (&lt;code&gt;p&lt;/code&gt;) is calculated based on the&#10; populations that remain eligible for selection.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; A new set of trial assignments is produced for each iteration and&#10; will not change until the next iteration.  The values that are&#10; generated are independent and the expected values of the assignments&#10; will have expected values that are representative of the population&#10; proportions.  </description>
  <author>Raymond A. Cardillo, Matthew J. Robbins, Contributors: Jason Smith and Brian Hudson</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 6.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="populations">The populations to select from.  This multiport is of type Long.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.PortParameter-->
    <property name="trials">The total number of trials to assign.  This PortParameter is&#10;  of type Int and has an initial default value of 1.</property>
</doc>
