<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="ConfigurationSwitch" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.ConfigurationSwitch">
  <description>
Split an input stream onto two output ports depending on a&#10; boolean selector parameter.  The value of the &lt;i&gt;selector&lt;/i&gt; parameter specifies the&#10; output port that should be written to in this and subsequent iterations.&#10; In each iteration, at most one token on each channel of the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port&#10; is read and sent to the corresponding channel of the&#10; &lt;i&gt;trueOutput&lt;/i&gt; port or the &lt;i&gt;falseOutput&lt;/i&gt; port, depending on the&#10; most value of the &lt;i&gt;selector&lt;/i&gt; parameter.&#10; If the input has width greater than an output port, then&#10; some input tokens will be discarded (those on input channels for which&#10; there is no corresponding output channel).&#10; Because tokens are&#10; immutable, the same Token is sent to the output, rather than a copy.&#10; The &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port may receive Tokens of any type.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;Note that the this actor may be used in Synchronous Dataflow (SDF)&#10; models, but only under certain circumstances. It specifies an output&#10; production rate of zero on the output port not used, so downstream&#10; actors will not be fired.  </description>
  <author>Charles Shelton</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 8.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (cshelton)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cshelton)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="input">The input port.  The type can be anything. This is a multiport,&#10;  and input tokens on all channels are routed to corresponding&#10;  channels on the output port, if there are such channels.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="trueOutput">Output for tokens on the true path.  The type is at least the&#10;  type of the input.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="falseOutput">Output for tokens on the false path.  The type is at least the&#10;  type of the input.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.PortParameter-->
    <property name="selector">PortParameter that selects one of the two input ports.  The type is&#10;  BooleanToken that defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="trueOutput_tokenProductionRate">This parameter provides token consumption rate for &lt;i&gt;trueOutput&lt;/i&gt;.&#10;  The type is int and it defaults to zero.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="falseOutput_tokenProductionRate">This parameter provides token consumption rate for &lt;i&gt;falseOutput&lt;/i&gt;.&#10;  The type is int and it defaults to one.</property>
</doc>
