<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="ExecutionTime" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.ExecutionTime">
  <description>
Read the input token, if there is one, execute an (uninteresting)&#10; computation to consume a specified amount of real time or to execute&#10; it a fixed number of times, and produce&#10; on the output the actual execution time (in milliseconds). Unlike the&#10; Sleep actor, which suspends the calling thread for the specified&#10; amount of time, this actor performs a computation during the&#10; specified amount of time, thus consuming compute resources.&#10; If &lt;i&gt;realTime&lt;/i&gt; is true, then the number of computations it&#10; performs is not fixed, but rather depends on what the thread&#10; scheduler does. If it is false, then the amount of computation&#10; done is fixed. The default is false.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 8.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="executionTime">The amount of time to consume. This is either in milliseconds,&#10;  if the realTime parameter is set to true, or in the number of&#10;  iterations of a fixed computation, if the realTime parameter&#10;  is set to false. This is a long&#10;  that defaults to 1000L.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="granularity">The granularity of the computation. This parameter specifies&#10;  the number of additions performed in each invocation of the&#10;  (uninteresting) computation. This is a long, which defaults&#10;  to 400000, which yields a computation time granularity&#10;  of approximately 1msec on a MacBook Pro.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="realTime">If true, then the executionTime parameter is&#10;  interpreted as milliseconds. If it is false (the default), then the&#10;  executionTime parameter is interpreted to specify the number&#10;  of cycles of a fixed computation.  Use false to specify&#10;  a fixed computational load, and use true to specify an&#10;  amount of real time to consume. When this is true,&#10;  if the thread executing the fire() method is preempted&#10;  during its run, then less computation is done.</property>
</doc>
