<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="PublisherNonStrictTest" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.PublisherNonStrictTest">
  <description>
This actor publishes input tokens on a named channel and compares&#10; the inputs against the value specified by the &lt;i&gt;correctValues&lt;/i&gt; parameter.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;This actor combines the &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/Publisher.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.lib.Publisher&lt;/a&gt; actor&#10; and the &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/NonStrictTest.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.lib.NonStrictTest&lt;/a&gt; actor.  Thus, it has quite&#10; a bit of duplicated code from the NonStrictTest actor.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; Note that in the superclass (Publisher), the input is a multiport,&#10; whereas in this class it is a regular non-multiport.  To use a multiport&#10; input, use &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/PublisherTest.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.lib.PublisherTest&lt;/a&gt;  </description>
  <author>Christopher Brooks, based on Test, which has Edward A. Lee and Jim Armstrong as authors</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 6.1</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="correctValues">A matrix specifying what the input should be.&#10;  This defaults to a one-by-one array containing a boolean true.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="tolerance">A double specifying how close the input has to be to the value&#10;  given by &lt;i&gt;correctValues&lt;/i&gt;.  This is a DoubleToken, with default&#10;  value 10&lt;sup&gt;-9&lt;/sup&gt;.  During training, if a correct value is&#10;  greater than 10 orders of magnitude than the tolerance, then the&#10;  tolerance is changed to a value 9 orders of magnitude less than&#10;  the correct value.  This helps avoid comparisons beyond the&#10;  precision of a Java double.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.SharedParameter-->
    <property name="trainingMode">If true, then do not check inputs, but rather collect them into&#10;  the &lt;i&gt;correctValues&lt;/i&gt; array.  This parameter is a boolean,&#10;  and it defaults to false. It is a shared parameter, meaning&#10;  that changing it for any one instance in a model will change&#10;  it for all instances in the model.</property>
</doc>
