<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Pulse" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.Pulse">
  <description>
Produce a pulse with a shape specified by the parameters.&#10; The &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; parameter contains an ArrayToken, which specifies&#10; the sequence of values to produce at the output.  The &lt;i&gt;indexes&lt;/i&gt;&#10; parameter contains an array of integers, which specifies when those values&#10; should be produced.  The array in the &lt;i&gt;indexes&lt;/i&gt; parameter&#10; must have the same length as that in the&#10; &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; parameter or an exception will be thrown by the fire() method.&#10; Also, the &lt;i&gt;indexes&lt;/i&gt; array must be increasing and non-negative,&#10; or an exception will be thrown when it is set.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Eventually, this actor will support various kinds of interpolation.&#10; For now, it outputs a zero (of the same type as the values) whenever&#10; the iteration count does not match an index in &lt;i&gt;indexes&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The default for the &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; parameter is&#10; an integer vector of form {1, 0}.&#10; The default indexes array is {0, 1}.&#10; Thus, the default output sequence will be 1, 0, 0, ...&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; However, the Pulse actor has a &lt;I&gt;repeat&lt;/i&gt; parameter. When set to&#10; true, the defined sequence is repeated indefinitely. Otherwise, the&#10; default sequence of zero values result.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The type of the output can be any token type. This type is inferred&#10; from the element type of the &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; parameter.&#10; &lt;p&gt;The Ptolemy Expression language has several constructs that are&#10; useful for creating arrays for use as values or indexes:&#10; &lt;dl&gt;&#10; &lt;dt&gt;&lt;code&gt;[0:1:100].toArray()&lt;/code&gt;&#10; &lt;dd&gt;Matlab style array construction that creates an array of 100 elements,&#10; 0 through 99.&#10; &lt;dt&gt;&lt;code&gt;repeat(100, {1}(0))&lt;/code&gt;&#10; &lt;dd&gt;Creat a sequence of one hundred 1's.&#10; &lt;/dl&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; NOTE: A reset input for this actor would be useful.  This would reset&#10; the iterations count, to cause the pulse to emerge again.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 0.2</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="indexes">The indexes at which the specified values will be produced.&#10;  This parameter is an array of integers, with default value {0, 1}.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="repeat">The flag that indicates whether the pulse sequence needs to be&#10;  repeated. This is a boolean, and defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="values">The values that will be produced at the specified indexes.&#10;  This parameter is an array, with default value {1, 0}.</property>
</doc>
