<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="IconLink" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.export.web.IconLink">
  <description>
Attribute specifying a URI to link to from an icon when a model&#10; is exported to a web page.&#10; Using the &lt;i&gt;linkTarget&lt;/i&gt; parameter, you can control how the&#10; link is displayed.&#10; In contrast, &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../../ptolemy/actor/gui/LiveLink.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.gui.LiveLink&lt;/a&gt; provides a link to a model&#10; in Vergil (instead of in an exported web page).&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; To use this, drag it onto an icon in your model. Then double&#10; click on that icon to set the URL to link to. The &lt;i&gt;linkTarget&lt;/i&gt;&#10; parameter specifies whether the link should be opened in a&#10; new browser window (the default), in the same browser window,&#10; in a lightbox, etc.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Note that this attribute can be used in combination with&#10; &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../../ptolemy/vergil/basic/export/web/LinkToOpenTableaux.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.vergil.basic.export.web.LinkToOpenTableaux&lt;/a&gt;. The latter provides a hyperlink that works&#10; within Vergil, whereas this attribute provides a hyperlink&#10; that works in an exported HTML page.  For example,&#10; LinkToOpenTableaux might be used to provide a hyperlink to another&#10; model (a pointer to its MoML file), so that double clicking&#10; on the container of the LiveLink attribute opens the other&#10; model. If that container also contains an instance of&#10; IconLink, then when the model is exported to a web page,&#10; the container's icon can become a link to the exported page&#10; for the other model.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.vergil.basic.export.web.LinkTarget-->
    <property name="linkTarget">Parameter specifying the target for the link.&#10;  The possibilities are:&#10;  &lt;ul&gt;&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;_lightbox&lt;/b&gt;: Open in a lightbox-style popup frame.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;_blank&lt;/b&gt;: Open in a new window or tab.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;_self&lt;/b&gt;: Open in the same frame as it was clicked.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;_parent&lt;/b&gt;: Open in the parent frameset.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;_top&lt;/b&gt;: Open in the full body of the window.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;framename&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;: Open in a named frame.&#10;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#10;  The default is &quot;_lightbox&quot;.</property>
</doc>
