<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Title" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.export.web.Title">
  <description>
Attribute specifying a title for a model or a component in a model.&#10; This attribute provides a visual title in the model,&#10; rendered more suitably for a title than a normal annotation.&#10; Moreover, if you export to web, this is used as the title for the&#10; containing component and for any exported web page.&#10; By default, the title is not shown on the web page except&#10; as part of the image of the model. If you wish for the title&#10; to also be shown in the HTML text before the image, then set&#10; the &lt;i&gt;showTitleInHTML&lt;/i&gt; parameter to true.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="bold">A boolean indicating whether the font should be bold.&#10;  This defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="center">A boolean parameter that controls whether the origin of the text is&#10;  center (if true) or north-west.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="fontFamily">The font family. This is a string that defaults to &quot;SansSerif&quot;.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="italic">A boolean indicating whether the font should be italic.&#10;  This defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="showTitleInHTML">If set to true, then the title given by this parameter&#10;  will be shown in the HTML prior to the image of the model&#10;  (as well as in the image of the model, if it is visible&#10;  when the export to web occurs). This is a boolean that&#10;  defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.gui.ColorAttribute-->
    <property name="textColor">The text color.  This is a string representing an array with&#10;  four elements, red, green, blue, and alpha, where alpha is&#10;  transparency. The default is &quot;{0.0, 0.0, 0.0, 1.0}&quot;, which&#10;  represents an opaque black.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="textSize">The text size.  This is an int that defaults to 14.</property>
</doc>
