<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Director" class="ptolemy.actor.Director">
  <description>
A Director governs the execution within a CompositeActor.  A composite actor&#10; that contains a director is said to be &lt;i&gt;opaque&lt;/i&gt;, and the execution model&#10; within the composite actor is determined by the contained director.   This&#10; director is called the &lt;i&gt;local director&lt;/i&gt; of a composite actor.&#10; A composite actor is also aware of the director of its container,&#10; which is referred to as its &lt;i&gt;executive director&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; A director may also be contained by a CompositeEntity that is not a&#10; CompositeActor, in which case it acts like any other entity within&#10; that composite.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; A top-level composite actor is generally associated with a &lt;i&gt;manager&lt;/i&gt;&#10; as well as a local director.  The Manager has overall responsibility for&#10; executing the application, and is often associated with a GUI.   Top-level&#10; composite actors have no executive director and getExecutiveDirector() will&#10; return null.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; A local director is responsible for invoking the actors contained by the&#10; composite.  If there is no local director, then the executive director&#10; is given the responsibility.  The getDirector() method of CompositeActor,&#10; therefore, returns the local director, if there is one, and otherwise&#10; returns the executive director.  Thus, it returns whichever director&#10; is responsible for executing the contained actors, or null if there is none.&#10; Whatever it returns is called simply the &lt;i&gt;director&lt;/i&gt; (vs. local&#10; director or executive director).&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; A director implements the action methods (preinitialize(),&#10; initialize(), prefire(), fire(), postfire(), iterate(),&#10; and wrapup()).  In this base class, default implementations&#10; are provided that may or may not be useful in specific domains.   In general,&#10; these methods will perform domain-dependent actions, and then call the&#10; respective methods in all contained actors.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The director also provides methods to optimize the iteration portion of an&#10; execution. This is done by setting the workspace to be read-only during&#10; an iteration. In this base class, the default implementation results in&#10; a read/write workspace. Derived classes (e.g. domain specific&#10; directors) should override the _writeAccessRequired() method to report&#10; that write access is not required. If none of the directors in a simulation&#10; require write access, then it is safe to set the workspace to be read-only,&#10; which will result in faster execution.&#10; &lt;p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Mudit Goel, Edward A. Lee, Lukito Muliadi, Steve Neuendorffer, John Reekie</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 0.2</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (neuendor)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="startTime">The local time of model when this director is initialized.&#10;  By default, this is blank, which&#10;  indicates that the start time is the current time of the enclosing&#10;  director when initialize() is invoked, or 0.0 if there is no&#10;  enclosing director. This can be set to a double value to explicitly&#10;  specify a start time.&#10;  Note that if &lt;i&gt;startTime&lt;/i&gt; is given a value&#10;  that is different from the start time of the enclosing&#10;  director, then local time may be ahead of or behind&#10;  environment time during execution.&#10;  Also note that some directors do not advance time (including&#10;  PN and Rendezvous, for example), in which case, local time remains&#10;  at the start time value throughout the execution.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="stopTime">The stop time of the model. By default, this is blank, which&#10;  means that no stop time is specified. If a stop time is specified,&#10;  it must be a double, and when local time meets or exceeds the&#10;  stop time, then &lt;a href=&quot;../../ptolemy/actor/Director.html#postfire&quot;&gt;postfire()&lt;/a&gt; returns false.</property>
</doc>
