<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="GRDirector" class="ptolemy.domains.gr.kernel.GRDirector">
  <description>
GR is a domain for displaying three-dimensional graphics in Ptolemy&#10; II.  GR is an untimed domain in where actors are connected in an&#10; acyclic directed graph.  Actors are fired according to a simple&#10; topological sort of the graph.  Nodes in the graph that have no&#10; descendants are assumed to be consumers of data produced by the rest&#10; of the model.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;The basic idea behind the GR domain is to arrange geometry and&#10; transform actors in a directed acyclic graph to represent the location&#10; and orientation of objects in a scene. This topology of connected GR&#10; actors form what is commonly called a scene graph in computer graphics&#10; literature.  The GR director converts the GR scene graph into a Java3D&#10; representation for rendering on the computer screen.  </description>
  <author>C. Fong, Steve Neuendorffer, Contributor: Christopher Hylands</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>yellow (chf)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>yellow (vogel)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="iterations">A parameter representing the number of times that postfire()&#10;  may be called before it returns false.  If the value is less&#10;  than or equal to zero, the execution will never return false&#10;  in postfire(), and thus the execution continues indefinitely.&#10;  This parameter must contain an IntToken.&#10;  The default value is an IntToken with the value zero.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="iterationTimeLowerBound">A parameter that indicates the time lower bound of each&#10;  iteration.  This parameter is useful for guaranteeing that&#10;  each frame of an animation takes at least a certain amount of&#10;  time before proceeding to the next frame. This parameter is&#10;  measured in milliseconds.&#10;  This parameter must contain an IntToken.&#10;  The default value is an IntToken with value the 33, which&#10;  corresponds roughly to 30 frames per second.</property>
</doc>
