<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Script" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.export.web.Script">
  <description>
A parameter for associating a script (such as Javascript) with an object in&#10; a model.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee, Elizabeth Latronico</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="evaluateScript">Parameter indicating whether the script text's expression should be&#10;  evaluated or not.  Ptolemy interprets the dollar sign to indicate that&#10;  the value of a parameter should be inserted; for example, $pi and&#10;  a variable pi=3.14 would evaluate to 3.14.  However, many scripting&#10;  languages such as jQuery use a dollar sign as part of the script itself&#10;  (to refer to jQuery variables).  In this case, we want to insert the&#10;  exact plain text into the web page, not the evaluated text.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.vergil.basic.export.web.AreaEventType-->
    <property name="eventType">Event type to respond to by executing the command given by&#10;  the value of this Script parameter.&#10;  The script will be run when the icon corresponding to the&#10;  container of this parameter gets one of the following events:&#10;  &lt;ul&gt;&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;onblur&lt;/b&gt;: Command to be run when an element loses focus.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;onclick&lt;/b&gt;: Command to be run on a mouse click.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;ondblclick&lt;/b&gt;: Command to be run on a mouse double-click.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;onfocus&lt;/b&gt;: Command to be run when an element gets focus.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;onmousedown&lt;/b&gt;: Command to be run when mouse button is pressed.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;onmousemove&lt;/b&gt;: Command to be run when mouse pointer moves.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;onmouseout&lt;/b&gt;: Command to be run when mouse pointer moves out of an element.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;onmouseover&lt;/b&gt;: Command to be run when mouse pointer moves over an element.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;onmouseup&lt;/b&gt;: Command to be run when mouse button is released.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;onkeydown&lt;/b&gt;: Command to be run when a key is pressed.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;onkeypress&lt;/b&gt;: Command to be run when a key is pressed and released.&#10;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;onkeyup&lt;/b&gt;: Command to be run when a key is released.&#10;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#10;  These are the events supported by the HTML area tag.&#10;  The default is &quot;onmouseover&quot;.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="script">Script to insert in the head section of the&#10;  web page. This will normally define a JavaScript function that&#10;  will be invoked when the UI event specified by &lt;i&gt;eventType&lt;/i&gt;&#10;  occurs. By default, this is blank. For example, if the value&#10;  of this parameter is the string&#10;    &lt;pre&gt;&#10;    function writeText(text) {&#10;    document.getElementById(&quot;xyz&quot;).innerHTML = text;&#10;    };&#10;    &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; and the value of this parameter is &quot;writeText('hello world')&quot;,&#10; then the HTML element with ID xyz will be populated with the&#10; string 'hello world' when the UI action &lt;i&gt;eventType&lt;/i&gt; occurs.</property>
</doc>
