<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="BasicSwitch" class="ptolemy.domains.de.lib.aspect.BasicSwitch">
  <description>
A &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../../ptolemy/domains/de/lib/aspect/BasicSwitch.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.domains.de.lib.aspect.BasicSwitch&lt;/a&gt; actor that, when its&#10;  &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../../ptolemy/domains/de/lib/aspect/BasicSwitch.html#sendToken&quot;&gt;sendToken(Receiver, Receiver, Token)&lt;/a&gt; method is called, delays&#10;  the delivery of the specified token to the specified receiver&#10;  according to the delays and contention on input buffers, output buffers,&#10;  and switch fabric delays.&#10;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;This communication aspect implements a simple switch which has a parametrizable&#10;  number of ports. Note that these ports are not visually represented&#10;  as Ptolemy actor ports. The first token received by this actor is delayed for&#10;  &lt;i&gt;inputBufferDelay&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;switchFabricDelay&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;outputBufferDelay&lt;/i&gt;&#10;  time units. Tokens received on the same switch input are buffered in a FIFO queue.&#10;  Similarly, tokens for the same output are buffered in FIFO queues. The switch&#10;  fabric in this switch acts as a FIFO queue as well. Tokens on different input&#10;  and output ports are processed in parallel, tokens in the switch fabric are&#10;  processed one after the other.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;To use this actor, drag it into a model. Input ports get decorated with&#10;  &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../../ptolemy/domains/de/lib/aspect/BasicSwitch/BasicSwitchAttributes.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.domains.de.lib.aspect.BasicSwitch.BasicSwitchAttributes&lt;/a&gt; which describe the path a token takes through&#10;  the switch: the switch input port number and the switch output port&#10;  number.&lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Patricia Derler</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (derler)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (derler)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="numberOfPorts">Number of ports on the switch. This parameter must contain an&#10;  IntToken.  The value defaults to 4.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="inputBufferDelay">Time it takes for a token to be put into the input queue.&#10;  This parameter must contain a DoubleToken. The value defaults&#10;  to 0.1.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="outputBufferDelay">Time it takes for a token to be put into the output queue.&#10;  This parameter must contain a DoubleToken. The value defaults&#10;  to 0.1.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="switchFabricDelay">Time it takes for a token to be processed by the switch fabric.&#10;  This parameter must contain a DoubleToken. The value defaults&#10;  to 0.1.</property>
</doc>
