<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="FIR" class="ptolemy.domains.sdf.lib.FIR">
  <description>
This actor implements a type polymorphic finite-impulse response&#10; filter with multirate capability. Since this filter operates on&#10; Tokens, it is polymorphic in the type of data it operates on.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Note that the current implementation of this actor only reads its&#10; parameters during initialization, so the filter cannot be&#10; changed during execution.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; When the &lt;i&gt;decimation&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;interpolation&lt;/i&gt;)&#10; parameters are different from unity, the filter behaves exactly&#10; as it were followed (preceded) by a DownSample (UpSample) actor.&#10; However, the implementation is much more efficient than&#10; it would be using UpSample or DownSample actors;&#10; a polyphase structure is used internally, avoiding unnecessary use&#10; of memory and unnecessary multiplication by zero.&#10; Arbitrary sample-rate conversions by rational factors can&#10; be accomplished this way.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; To design a filter for a multirate system, simply assume the&#10; sample rate is the product of the interpolation parameter and&#10; the input sample rate, or equivalently, the product of the decimation&#10; parameter and the output sample rate.&#10; In particular, considerable care must be taken to avoid aliasing.&#10; Specifically, if the input sample rate is &lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt;,&#10; then the filter stopband should begin before &lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt;/2.&#10; If the interpolation ratio is &lt;i&gt;i&lt;/i&gt;, then &lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt;/2 is a fraction&#10; 1/2&lt;i&gt;i&lt;/i&gt; of the sample rate at which you must design your filter.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The &lt;i&gt;decimationPhase&lt;/i&gt; parameter is somewhat subtle.&#10; It is exactly equivalent the phase parameter of the DownSample actor.&#10; Its interpretation is as follows; when decimating,&#10; samples are conceptually discarded (although a polyphase structure&#10; does not actually compute the discarded samples).&#10; If you are decimating by a factor of three, then you will select&#10; one of every three outputs, with three possible phases.&#10; When decimationPhase is zero (the default),&#10; the latest (most recent) samples are the ones selected.&#10; The decimationPhase must be strictly less than&#10; the decimation ratio.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;Note: in this description &quot;sample rate&quot; refers to the physical sampling&#10; rate of an A/D converter in the system.  In other words, the number of&#10; data samples per second.  This is not usually specified anywhere in an&#10; SDF system, and most definitely does NOT correspond to the SDF rate parameters&#10; of this actor.  This actor automatically sets the rates of the input&#10; and output ports to the decimation and interpolation ratios, respectively.&lt;/i&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; For more information about polyphase filters, see F. J. Harris,&#10; &quot;Multirate FIR Filters for Interpolating and Desampling&quot;, in&#10; &lt;i&gt;Handbook of Digital Signal Processing&lt;/i&gt;, Academic Press, 1987.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee, Bart Kienhuis, Steve Neuendorffer</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 0.2</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (neuendor)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (neuendor)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="decimation">The decimation ratio of the filter. This must contain an&#10;  IntToken, and by default it has value one.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="decimationPhase">The decimation phase of the filter. This must contain an&#10;  IntToken, and by default it has value zero.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="interpolation">The interpolation ratio of the filter. This must contain an&#10;  IntToken, and by default it has value one.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="taps">The taps of the filter. This has a type of ArrayToken.&#10;  By default, it contains an array with a single integer one,&#10;  meaning that the output of the filter is the same as the input.</property>
</doc>
