<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="MatrixJoin" class="ptolemy.domains.sdf.lib.MatrixJoin">
  <description>
This actor joins matrices into a single matrix by tiling.&#10; It reads N*M input matrices from the input port, where N is&#10; the value of the &lt;i&gt;rows&lt;/i&gt; parameter, and M is&#10; the value of the &lt;i&gt;columns&lt;/i&gt; parameter. The matrices&#10; read are arranged left-to-right,&#10; top-to-bottom, in a raster scan pattern.&#10; For example, if &lt;i&gt;rows&lt;/i&gt; = &lt;i&gt;columns&lt;/i&gt; = 2, then on&#10; each firing, four matrices, A, B, C, D, will be read from&#10; the input channel.  Assuming A is the first one read, then&#10; the output matrix will be a matrix arranged as follows:&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10;   A B&#10;   C D&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; The size of the output depends on the matrices in the top row&#10; and left column. That is, in the above examples, the number of&#10; columns in the output will equal the sum of the number of columns&#10; in A and B.  The number of rows will equal the sum of the number&#10; of rows in A and C.  The matrices are tiled in raster-scan order,&#10; first A, then B, then C, and then D.  Gaps are zero filled,&#10; and overlaps are overwritten, where later matrices in the raster-scan&#10; order overwrite earlier matrices.  For example, if B has more rows&#10; than A, then the bottom rows of B will be overwritten by rows of D.&#10; &lt;p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Edward Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 6.1</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (neuendor)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="columns">The number of matrices to arrange left to right on the output.&#10;  This is an integer that defaults to 1.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="rows">The number of matrices to arrange top to bottom on the output.&#10;  This is an integer that defaults to 1.</property>
</doc>
