<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Chop" class="ptolemy.backtrack.automatic.ptolemy.domains.sdf.lib.Chop">
  <description>
This actor reads a sequence of input tokens of any type, and writes a&#10; sequence of tokens constructed from the input sequence (possibly&#10; supplemented with zeros).  The number of input tokens consumed&#10; is given by &lt;i&gt;numberToRead&lt;/i&gt;, and the number of output tokens&#10; produced is given by &lt;i&gt;numberToWrite&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; The &lt;i&gt;offset&lt;/i&gt; parameter (default 0) specifies where in the output&#10; block the first (oldest) input that is read should go.&#10; If &lt;i&gt;offset&lt;/i&gt; is positive and &lt;i&gt;usePastInputs&lt;/i&gt; is true,&#10; then the first few outputs will come from values read in previous iterations.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; A simple use of this actor is to pad a block of inputs with zeros.&#10; Set &lt;i&gt;offset&lt;/i&gt; to zero and use &lt;i&gt;numberToWrite &amp;gt; numberToRead&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; &lt;a name=&quot;padding&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Another simple use is to obtain overlapping windows from&#10; an input stream.&#10; Set &lt;i&gt;usePastInputs&lt;/i&gt; to true, use &lt;i&gt;numberToWrite &amp;gt; numberToRead&lt;/i&gt;,&#10; and set &lt;i&gt;offset&lt;/i&gt; equal to &lt;i&gt;numberToWrite - numberToRead&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; &lt;a name=&quot;overlapping windows&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#10; &lt;a name=&quot;windowing&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The general operation is illustrated with the following examples.&#10; If &lt;i&gt;offset&lt;/i&gt; is positive,&#10; there two possible scenarios, illustrated by the following examples:&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10; iiiiii                  numberToRead = 6&#10; \    \                 offset = 2&#10; ppiiiiii00              numberToWrite = 10&#10; iiiiii                  numberToRead = 6&#10; \ \  \                 offset = 2&#10; ppiii                   numberToWrite = 5&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The symbol &quot;i&quot; refers to any input token. The leftmost symbol&#10; refers to the oldest input token of the ones consumed in a given&#10; firing. The symbol &quot;p&quot; refers to a token that is either zero&#10; (if &lt;i&gt;usePastInputs&lt;/i&gt; is false) or is equal to a previously&#10; consumed input token (if &lt;i&gt;usePastInputs&lt;/i&gt; is true).&#10; The symbol &quot;0&quot; refers to a zero-valued token.&#10; In the first of the above examples, the entire input block is&#10; copied to the output, and then filled out with zeros.&#10; In the second example, only a portion of the input block fits.&#10; The remaining input tokens are discarded, although they might&#10; be used in subsequent firings if &lt;i&gt;usePastInputs&lt;/i&gt; is true.&lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; When the &lt;i&gt;offset&lt;/i&gt; is negative, this indicates that the&#10; first &lt;i&gt;offset&lt;/i&gt; input tokens that are read should be&#10; discarded.  The corresponding scenarios are shown below:&lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10; iiiiii                  numberToRead = 6&#10; / /  /                   offset = -2&#10; iiii000000              numberToWrite = 10&#10; iiiiii                  numberToRead = 6&#10; / / //                   offset = -2&#10; iii                     numberToWrite = 3&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; In the first of these examples, the first two input tokens are&#10; discarded.  In the second example, the first two and the last input&#10; token are discarded.&lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The zero-valued tokens are constructed using the zero() method of&#10; the first input token that is read in the firing.  This returns&#10; a zero-valued token with the same type as the input.&lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (neuendor)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="numberToRead">The number of input tokens to read.&#10; This is an integer, with default 128.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="numberToWrite">The number of tokens to write to the output.&#10; This is an integer, with default 64.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="offset">Start of output block relative to start of input block.&#10; This is an integer, with default 0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="usePastInputs">If offset is greater than 0, specify whether to use previously&#10; read inputs (otherwise use zeros).&#10; This is a boolean, with default true.</property>
</doc>
