<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="LocalClock" class="ptolemy.actor.LocalClock">
  <description>
A clock that keeps track of model time at a level of the model hierarchy&#10;  and relates it to the time of the enclosing model, if there is one. The time&#10;  of the enclosing model is referred to as the environment time. This&#10;  clock has a notion of local time and committed time. The committed time&#10;  is &quot;simultaneous&quot; with the environment time.&#10;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;The local time is&#10;  not allowed to move backwards past the committed time, but ahead&#10;  of that time, it can move around at will. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;&#10;  There is no way of explicitly committing time, but&#10;  several methods have the side effect of committing the current&#10;  local time. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;../../ptolemy/actor/LocalClock.html#setClockDrift&quot;&gt;setClockDrift(double)&lt;/a&gt; will commit&#10;  the current local time and change the clock drift.  So will&#10;  &lt;a href=&quot;../../ptolemy/actor/LocalClock.html#start&quot;&gt;start()&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;../../ptolemy/actor/LocalClock.html#stop&quot;&gt;stop()&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;&#10;  This class implements the AbstractSettableAttribute interface because&#10;  we want the localClock to be shown as a parameter in the editor&#10;  dialogue of a director. A better implementation would be to derive&#10;  LocalClock from Attribute and make changes to vergil such that&#10;  Attributes are displayed in the dialogue, however, for the moment,&#10;  the required changes are too complex.&#10;  The value of the clock is exposed as an attribute that, by default,&#10;  is non editable. The clock drift is a contained attribute that can&#10;  be modified. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;  &lt;p&gt; This class also specifies a &lt;i&gt;globalTimeResolution&lt;/i&gt;&#10;  parameter. This is a double with default 1E-10, which is&#10;  10&lt;sup&gt;-10&lt;/sup&gt;.  All time values are rounded to the nearest&#10;  multiple of this value. If the value is changed during a run, an&#10;  exception is thrown.  This is a shared parameter, which means that&#10;  all instances of Director in the model will have the same value&#10;  for this parameter. Changing one of them changes all of them. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;FIXME: Setting of clock drift must be controlled because it commits&#10;  time. &lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Ilge Akkaya, Patricia Derler, Edward A. Lee, Christos Stergiou, Michael Zimmer</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>red (eal)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.SharedParameter-->
    <property name="globalTimeResolution">The time precision used by this director. All time values are&#10;  rounded to the nearest multiple of this number. This is a double&#10;  that defaults to &quot;1E-10&quot; which is 10&lt;sup&gt;-10&lt;/sup&gt;.&#10;  This is a shared parameter, meaning that changing one instance&#10;  in a model results in all instances being changed.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="clockDrift">The drift of the local clock with respect to the environment&#10;  clock. If this is a top level director the clock drift has no&#10;  consequence. The value is a double that is initialized to&#10;  1.0 which means that the local clock drift matches the one&#10;  of the environment.</property>
</doc>
