<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="SysMLADirector" class="ptolemy.domains.sysml.kernel.SysMLADirector">
  <description>
&lt;p&gt;&#10; Version A of a SysML director. This version is inspired by a&#10; subset of the semantics of IBM Rational's Rhapsody SysML tool.&#10; In this MoC, each actor executes in its own thread (corresponding&#10; to an &quot;active object&quot; in SysML). Inputs provided to an input&#10; port (by the thread of another actor) are put into a single queue&#10; belonging to the destination actor. The thread for the&#10; destination actor retrieves the first input in the queue&#10; and uses it to set the value of exactly one input port.&#10; All other input ports are marked absent. The actor then&#10; fires, possibly producing one or more outputs which are&#10; directed to their destination actors.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; When multiple actors send tokens to an actor,&#10; whether to the same port or to distinct ports,&#10; this MoC is nondeterministic. The order in which the&#10; tokens are processed will depend on the happenstances&#10; of scheduling, since the tokens are put into a single queue&#10; in the order in which they arrive.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; In this MoC, we assume that an actor iterates within its&#10; thread only if either it has called fireAt() to request a&#10; future firing (or a re-firing at the current time), or&#10; it has at least one event in its input queue. Thus, the&#10; actor's thread will block until one of those conditions&#10; is satisfied.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; When all threads are blocked, then if at least one has&#10; called fireAt() to request a future firing, then this director&#10; will advance model time to the smallest time of such a request,&#10; and then again begin executing actors until they all block.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; When all actors are blocked, and none has called fireAt(),&#10; the model terminates.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (eal)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="activeObjects">If true, then every actor executes in its own thread.&#10;  This is a boolean that defaults to false.</property>
</doc>
