<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="DatabaseSelect" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.database.DatabaseSelect">
  <description>
Select the columns from rows that match the specified pattern via the specified&#10; database manager. The output is an array of records, one for each row that&#10; matches the pattern. In each record, there is field for each column,&#10; where the name of the field is the name of the column and the value&#10; is the value from the matching row. If no rows match the specified&#10; pattern, then the output is an empty array of the appropriate type.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 8.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.PortParameter-->
    <property name="columns">A record indicating what to query for.&#10;  The names of the fields are the names of the columns to&#10;  retrieve from the database, and the value of the field is&#10;  the type. This is a record that defaults to&#10;  {LNAME=string, DESKNO=string}, indicating that two columns,&#10;  LNAME (for last name) and DESKNO (for desk number) should&#10;  be retrieved from the database.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="databaseManager">Name of the DatabaseManager to use.&#10;  This defaults to &quot;DatabaseManager&quot;.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="distinct">Indicator of whether to return only distinct records.&#10;  This is a boolean that defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="orderBy">Optional ordering of the results.&#10;  For example, to order first by DESKNO (ascending)&#10;  and then by LNAME (descending), you would change&#10;  the value of this parameter to&#10;  &quot;DESKNO asc, LNAME desc&quot;.&#10;  This parameter is a string that defaults to empty,&#10;  meaning that the ordering of the results is arbitrary.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.PortParameter-->
    <property name="pattern">A pattern specifying which rows to select from the database.&#10;  Any pattern understood in the 'where' clause of an SQL&#10;  statement is acceptable. This is a string that defaults to&#10;  &quot;trim(room)='545Q' and trim(bldg)='Cory'&quot;, indicating that the retrieved&#10;  records should have &quot;Cory&quot; in the bldg column and &quot;545Q&quot;&#10;  in the room column.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="table">Table to use within the database.&#10;  This is a string that defaults to &quot;v_spaces&quot;.</property>
</doc>
