<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="QSSDirector" class="ptolemy.domains.qss.kernel.QSSDirector">
  <description>
A director that extends the discrete-event model of computation&#10; to include a Quantized-State System (QSS) solver to perform integration.&#10; This solver performs using a discrete-event style, quantizing the magnitude&#10; of signals rather than the time, as done by a conventional ODE solver.&#10; The &lt;i&gt;absoluteQuantum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;relativeQuantum&lt;/i&gt; parameters determine&#10; the quantization granularity.  For information about QSS, see&#10; &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/domains/qss/kernel/QSSIntegrator.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.domains.qss.kernel.QSSIntegrator&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../org/ptolemy/qss/solver/QSSBase.xml&quot;&gt;org.ptolemy.qss.solver.QSSBase&lt;/a&gt;.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Note that the expression function smoothToken(double, {double})&#10; is available in the expression language. This function creates&#10; a &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/data/SmoothToken.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.data.SmoothToken&lt;/a&gt; with value equal to the first argument and any number&#10; of derivatives given in the second argument. Actors in this domain&#10; can use such tokens, when they are provided, to perform more accurate&#10; calculations.  </description>
  <author>Thierry S. Nouidui and Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy 11.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="absoluteQuantum">The minimum quantum for QSS integrations under the control&#10;  of this director. This is a double that defaults to 1E-4.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="QSSSolver">The class name of the QSS solver used for integration.  This&#10;  is a string that defaults to &quot;QSS1&quot;.  Solvers are all required&#10;  to be in package &quot;org.ptolemy.qss&quot;. Note that if the solver is&#10;  changed during the execution of the model, the change will not&#10;  take effect until the model re-initialized.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="relativeQuantum">The relative quantum to use for QSS integrations under the control&#10;  of this director. If the value here is greater than zero,&#10;  then the quantum will be the larger of the&#10;  &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/domains/qss/kernel/QSSDirector.xml#absoluteQuantum&quot;&gt;absoluteQuantum&lt;/a&gt; and |x| * relativeQuantum,&#10;  where x is the current value of the state being quantized.&#10;  This is a double that defaults to be 0.0, which causes the&#10;  absoluteQuantum to be used.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="quantumScaleFactor">The quantum scale factor to use for QSS integrations under the control&#10;  of this director. This value is used to scale the value of the absolute and&#10;  relative quantum to achieve a finer quantization. This is a double which&#10;  value must be greater than 0.0 and less or equal to 1.0.</property>
</doc>
