<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="SymmetricEncryption" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.security.SymmetricEncryption">
  <description>
Encrypt an unsigned byte array using a symmetric algorithm.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;In cryptography, a symmetric algorithm is an algorithm that uses&#10; the same key for encryption and decryption.  An asymmetric algorithm uses&#10; two different keys: a public key and a private key.  Sun's documentation&#10; says that asymmetric algorithms are usually much slower than&#10; symmetric algorithms.  The initial default set of algorithms that&#10; comes with the Sun JDK does not include an asymmetric encryption algorithm,&#10; though other algorithms may be installed by the system administrator.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;This actor reads an unsigned byte array at the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port,&#10; encrypts the data using the data from the &lt;i&gt;key&lt;/i&gt; port and then&#10; writes the unsigned byte array results to the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; port.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;i&gt;key&lt;/i&gt; should be the same for both the&#10; SymmetricDecryption actor and this actor.  The &lt;i&gt;key&lt;/i&gt; should not&#10; be visible to users as the security of the encrypted message relies on&#10; the secrecy of this key.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;i&gt;algorithm&lt;/i&gt; parameter determines which algorithm is used.&#10; The algorithm specified must be symmetric. The mode and padding can also&#10; be specified in the &lt;i&gt;mode&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;padding&lt;/i&gt; parameters.  In&#10; case a provider specific instance of an algorithm is needed the&#10; provider may also be specified in the &lt;i&gt;provider&lt;/i&gt; parameter.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;Note that for simplicity, this actor does not support the&#10; notion of algorithm parameters, so the algorithm must not require&#10; that algorithm parameters be transmitted separately from the key.&#10; If the user selects an algorithm that uses algorithm parameters, then&#10; an exception will likely be thrown.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;This actor relies on the Java Cryptography Architecture (JCA) and Java&#10; Cryptography Extension (JCE).  See the&#10; &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/security/CryptographyActor.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.lib.security.CryptographyActor&lt;/a&gt; documentation for&#10; resources about the JCE.  </description>
  <author>Christopher Hylands Brooks, Contributor: Rakesh Reddy</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="key">The key to be used by this actor to encrypt the data.&#10;  The type is an KeyToken containing a java.security.Key.&#10;  Usually the output of the &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/security/SecretKey.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.lib.security.SecretKey&lt;/a&gt;&#10;  actor is connected to this port</port>
</doc>
