<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="SymmetricDecryption" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.security.SymmetricDecryption">
  <description>
Decrypt an unsigned byte array using a symmetric algorithm.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/security/SymmetricEncryption.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.lib.security.SymmetricEncryption&lt;/a&gt; for a&#10; description of symmetric vs. asymmetric algorithms.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;This actor reads an unsigned byte array at the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port,&#10; decrypts the data using the data from the &lt;i&gt;key&lt;/i&gt; port and then&#10; writes the unsigned byte array results to the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; port.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;i&gt;key&lt;/i&gt; should be the same for both the SymmetricEncryption&#10; actor and this actor.&#10;&#10; The &lt;i&gt;algorithm&lt;/i&gt; parameter determines which algorithm is used.&#10; The algorithm specified must be symmetric. The mode and padding can also&#10; be specified in the &lt;i&gt;mode&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;padding&lt;/i&gt; parameters.  In&#10; case a provider specific instance of an algorithm is needed the&#10; provider may also be specified in the &lt;i&gt;provider&lt;/i&gt; parameter.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;Note that for simplicity, this actor does not support the&#10; notion of algorithm parameters, so the algorithm must not require&#10; that algorithm parameters be transmitted separately from the key.&#10; If the user selects an algorithm that uses algorithm parameters, then&#10; an exception will likely be thrown.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;This actor relies on the Java Cryptography Architecture (JCA) and Java&#10; Cryptography Extension (JCE).  See the&#10; &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/security/CryptographyActor.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.lib.security.CryptographyActor&lt;/a&gt; documentation for&#10; resources about JCA and JCE.  </description>
  <author>Christopher Hylands Brooks, Contributor: Rakesh Reddy</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="key">The key port.  This port contains the key that is used to&#10;  decrypt data from the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port.  The type is KeyToken&#10;  that contains a java.security.key</port>
</doc>
