<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="CanBus" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.aspect.CanBus">
  <description>
This actor is an &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/actor/CommunicationAspect.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.CommunicationAspect&lt;/a&gt; that simulates a CAN bus network&#10;  When its &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/aspect/CanBus.html#sendToken&quot;&gt;sendToken(Receiver, Receiver, Token)&lt;/a&gt; method is called,&#10;  the delivery of the specified token to the specified receiver is delayed according to the CAN protocol.&#10;  &lt;p&gt;&#10;  The CAN bus is a serial communication protocol that supports real-time systems with high reliability.&#10;  Its main features are: priority-based bus access and non destructive content-based arbitration.&#10;  If two or more nodes attempt to transmit a message on the idle bus, the access conflicts are resolved&#10;  by performing a bitwise arbitration (non destructive) according to a priority (called here &lt;i&gt;CanPriority&lt;/i&gt;).&#10;  Our &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/actor/CommunicationAspect.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.CommunicationAspect&lt;/a&gt; simulates such content-based arbitration.&#10;  A node attempting to transmit a message when the bus is busy must try again when the bus will be free (in fact, there is a&#10;  queue with messages that did not win the bus during arbitration or arrived when the bus is busy).&#10;  &lt;/p&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;&#10;  In order to perform such an arbitration, it is needed to set a parameter called &lt;i&gt;CanPriority&lt;/i&gt; to each receiving switch port.&#10;  &lt;i&gt;CanPriority&lt;/i&gt; is a positive integer. The higher is CanPriority the lower is the priority.&#10;  (note that in the reality the arbitration is done bit to bit. The higher is the &lt;i&gt;identifier&lt;/i&gt; the higher is the priority)&#10;  It is just needed to set this parameter, using the Parameter dialogs offered by the Decorator mechanism, to the port(s) we want to connect to the bus.&#10;  The &lt;i&gt;CanPriority&lt;/i&gt; parameter is already added and is visible on Parameter dialogs when the CanBus QM is deployed in a model (enhancing visibility).&#10;  &lt;/p&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;&#10;  Messages sent on the Bus are stored and delivered on due time.&#10;  Since the CAN protocol cover the second layer of the OSI model, messages sent on the bus are encapsulated&#10;  in frames according to the CAN protocol.&#10;  We consider that messages sent by actors correspond to exactly one frame.&#10;  Also, two formats of frames are provided by the CAN standard: the base frame and the extended frame.&#10;  We can choose the standard according to which the simulation will be performed.&#10;  &lt;/p&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;&#10;  Of course, the bit rate of the bus is also a parameter that can be modified.&#10;  Typical bit rates for the CAN bus range from 125 Kbits/second to 1 Mbits/second.&#10;  &lt;/p&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;&#10;  Future work: implementing an application layer of the OSI model based on CAN, taking errors into account&#10;  by delaying the deliveries of messages, finest management of time by dividing the time continuum in periods of 1/bitRate,&#10;  bit stuffing...&#10;  &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;  For more information please refer to: &lt;i&gt;CAN bus simulator using a communication aspect&lt;/i&gt;.  </description>
  <author>D. Marciano, G. Lasnier, P. Derler</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (glasnier)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (glasnier)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="bitRate">The bit rate of the bus. This is a double with default value to 125 (Kbit/second).&#10;  It is required to be positive.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="canFormatOfFrame">The format of frame. This is a string with default value to &quot;Standard frame&quot;.&#10;  It is required to be either &quot;Standard frame&quot; or &quot;Extended frame&quot;.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="canFramePolicy">The selected policy for the frame queue behavior. This is a string with&#10; the default value &quot;Send All Frames&quot;.</property>
</doc>
