<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="FixedPriorityScheduler" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.aspect.FixedPriorityScheduler">
  <description>
This is a fixed priority scheduler resource manager on a single processor or core.&#10;This attribute decorates actors in the model at the same and lower levels of the&#10;hierarchy, including those inside opaque composite actors. It decorates them&#10;with the following parameters:&#10;&lt;ul&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt; &lt;i&gt;enable&lt;/i&gt;: If true, then the decorated actor will use this resource.&#10;     This is a boolean that defaults to false.&#10;&lt;li&gt; &lt;i&gt;executionTime&lt;/i&gt;: Specifies the execution time of the&#10;     decorated actor. This means the time that the decorated actor occupies&#10;     the processor or core when it fires.&#10;     This is a double that defaults to 0.0.&#10;&lt;li&gt; &lt;i&gt;priority&lt;/i&gt;: An integer where a lower number indicates a higher priority.&#10;     E.g., priority 1 means higher priority than priority 2.&#10;     Priority 0 means higher priority than any positive number.&#10;     Priority -1 means higher priority than any non-negative number.&#10;&lt;/ul&gt;&#10;&#10;For usage and supported directors &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/actor/ActorExecutionAspect.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.ActorExecutionAspect&lt;/a&gt;.&#10;&#10;When using this ExecutionAspect in the Ptides domain, the platform&#10;time in Ptides will be used to schedule execution times. When&#10; the Ptides director requests that an actor fire, if this resource is&#10;free, it will immediately schedule it. Otherwise, it will queue it to be&#10;executed when the resource becomes free. When the resource becomes free,&#10;the actor with the highest priority (the lower priority number) will&#10;be chosen from the queue to be executed. If two actors have the same&#10;highest priority, then they will be executed in FIFO order.  </description>
  <author>Patricia DerlerEdward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (derler)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="preemptive">Parameter to configure whether a preemptive or non-preemptive&#10;  scheduling strategy should be used. The default value is the&#10;  boolean value true.</property>
</doc>
