<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="HMMGaussianEstimator" class="org.ptolemy.machineLearning.hmm.HMMGaussianEstimator">
  <description>
&lt;p&gt;This actor implements a parameter estimator for Hidden Markov Models with Gaussian&#10;Emissions. The base class ParameterEstimator performs the parameter estimation and&#10;the HMMGaussianEstimator class contains density-specific methods for Gaussian emission&#10;calculations and produces the relevant estimates at its output ports.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;&#10;The output ports for a Gaussian HMM model are the &lt;i&gt;mean&lt;/i&gt; and the &lt;i&gt;standardDeviation&lt;/i&gt;&#10;vectors of the possible hidden states in addition to the HMM parameters independent&#10;from the emission density: &lt;i&gt;transitionMatrix&lt;/i&gt; .&#10;T&#10;he &lt;i&gt;mean&lt;/i&gt;  is a double array output containing the mean estimates and&#10;&lt;i&gt;sigma&lt;/i&gt; is a double array output containing standard deviation estimates of&#10;each mixture component. If the &lt;i&gt;modelType&lt;/i&gt; is HMM, then an additional output,&#10;&lt;i&gt;transitionMatrix&lt;/i&gt; is provided, which is an estimate of the transition matrix&#10;governing the Markovian process representing the hidden state evolution.&#10;If the &lt;i&gt;modelType&lt;/i&gt; is MM, this port outputs a double array with the prior&#10;probability estimates of the mixture components.&#10;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;&#10;The user-defined parameters are initial guesses for the model parameters, given by&#10;&lt;i&gt;m0&lt;/i&gt;, the mean vector guess, &lt;i&gt;s0&lt;/i&gt;, the standard deviation vector guess,&#10;&lt;i&gt;prior&lt;/i&gt;, the prior state distribution guess, &lt;i&gt;A0&lt;/i&gt;, the transition&#10;matrix guess ( only for HMM). &lt;i&gt;iterations&lt;/i&gt; is the number of EM iterations&#10;allowed until convergence.&#10;If, during iteration, the conditional log-likelihood of the observed&#10;sequence given the parameter estimates converges to a value within &lt;i&gt;likelihoodThreshold&lt;/i&gt;,&#10;the parameter estimation stops iterating and delivers the parameter estimates.  </description>
  <author>Ilge Akkaya</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (ilgea)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating></Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="mean">Mean parameter array for the Gaussian distribution.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="standardDeviation">Standard deviation parameter array for the Gaussian distribution.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="meanVectorGuess">The initial guess mean parameter array for the Gaussian distribution.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="standardDeviationGuess">The initial guess standard deviation parameter array for the Gaussian distribution.</property>
</doc>
