<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="DatagramWriter" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.net.DatagramWriter">
  <description>
This actor sends its input as a Datagram over the network using the&#10; UDP protocol.  Before being sent, the data is optionally encoded as a&#10; text string representing the value being sent.  When this option is&#10; selected, any Ptolemy data type may be represented.&#10; See the &lt;i&gt;encoding&lt;/i&gt; parameter.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;NOTE: This actor has problems, the tests do not reliably pass.&#10; For details, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://chess.eecs.berkeley.edu/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=54&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://chess.eecs.berkeley.edu/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=54&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;The address and socket number towards which the datagram is sent&#10; are given by the optional inputs &lt;i&gt;remoteAddress&lt;/i&gt; and&#10; &lt;i&gt;remoteSocketNumber&lt;/i&gt;.  However, unless/until token(s) arrive at&#10; these inputs, default values, given by &lt;i&gt;defaultRemoteAddress&lt;/i&gt; and&#10; &lt;i&gt;defaultRemoteSocketNumber&lt;/i&gt; are used.  Note that some IP&#10; addresses are special broadcast addresses.  An address such as&#10; &quot;128.32.239.255&quot; broadcasts to any IP addresses on the &quot;128.23.239.X&quot;&#10; subnet.  This only works on your own subnet.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;Each instance of this actor needs to allocate a local socket from&#10; which to transmit datagrams.  Initially, the local socket number is&#10; set to 4003, just to pick a number.  The socket is not allocated&#10; until the model is run.  </description>
  <author>Winthrop Williams, Joern Janneck, Xiaojun Liu, Edward A. Lee&#10; (Based on TiltSensor actor written by&#10; Chamberlain Fong, Xiaojun Liu, Edward Lee)</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 2.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (winthrop)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (winthrop)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="triggerOutput">The triggerOutput port.  The type of this port is GENERAL,&#10;  forcing input ports connected here to also be of type GENERAL,&#10;  (as trigger inputs typically are).  This port always transmits&#10;  a Token with nothing in it.  This gives the designer a way to&#10;  control the order in which other actors fire with respect to&#10;  the firing of this actor in the SDF domain.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="data">Data to be sent.  Data can be encoded different ways,&#10;  depending on the setting of &lt;i&gt;encoding&lt;/i&gt;.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="remoteAddress">The remote address towards which to launch the packet.&#10;  This is a multiport.  This permits it to be left unconnected in DE.&#10;  If multiple addresses are delivered simultaneously to this port,&#10;  the one arriving via the highest numbered channel is used.&#10;  Type is string.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="remoteSocketNumber">The remote socket number towards which to launch the packet.&#10;  This is a multiport.  This permits it to be left unconnected in DE.&#10;  If multiple addresses are delivered simultaneously to this port,&#10;  the one arriving via the highest numbered channel is used.&#10;  Type is integer.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="localSocketNumber">The local socket number for this actor's socket.  Integer in&#10;  the range 0..65535.  Default is 4003.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="defaultRemoteAddress">The default remote address to which to send datagrams.&#10;  This is a string.  It will get looked up to find the IP address.&#10;  (Legal forms of this string include &quot;128.32.239.10&quot; and &quot;localhost&quot;.)</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="defaultRemoteSocketNumber">The default remote UDP socket to which to launch the packet.&#10;  This is an integer in 0..65535.  NOTE: TCP sockets&#10;  get their own distinct, non-interfering, set of 2^16 numbers!</property>
</doc>
