<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="ErasureChannel" class="ptolemy.domains.wireless.lib.ErasureChannel">
  <description>
Model of a wireless channel with a specified loss probability. If the&#10; loss probability is greater than zero then on each&#10; call to the transmit() method, for each receiver in range,&#10; with the specified probability, the transmission to that&#10; receiver will not occur.  Whether a transmission occurs to a particular&#10; receiver is independent of whether it occurs to any other receiver.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; For convenience, a variable named &quot;distance&quot; is available and&#10; equal to the distance between the transmitter and the receiver&#10; when the &lt;i&gt;lossProbability&lt;/i&gt; is evaluated.  Thus, the&#10; loss probability can be given as an expression that depends&#10; on this distance.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The distance between the transmitter and receiver is determined&#10; by the protected method _distanceBetween(), which is also used&#10; to set the value of the &lt;i&gt;distance&lt;/i&gt; variable that can be&#10; used in the expression for loss probability.&#10; In this base class, that method uses&#10; the _location attribute of the transmit and receive actors,&#10; which corresponds to the position of the icon in the Vergil&#10; visual editor.  Subclasses may override this protected method&#10; to provide some other notion of distance.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="lossProbability">The probability that a call to transmit() will fail to deliver&#10;  the token to a receiver that is in range.&#10;  This is a double that defaults to 0.0, which means that&#10;  no loss occurs.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="seed">The seed that controls the random number generation.&#10;  A seed of zero is interpreted to mean that no seed is specified,&#10;  which means that each execution of the model could result in&#10;  distinct data. For the value 0, the seed is set to&#10;  System.currentTimeMillis() + hashCode(), which means that&#10;  with extremely high probability, two distinct actors will have&#10;  distinct seeds.  However, current time may not have enough&#10;  resolution to ensure that two subsequent executions of the&#10;  same model have distinct seeds.&#10;  This parameter contains a LongToken, initially with value 0.</property>
</doc>
