<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="ParameterSet" class="ptolemy.actor.parameters.ParameterSet">
  <description>
An attribute that reads multiple values from a file and sets&#10; corresponding parameters in the container.&#10; The values are in the form:&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;attributeName&lt;/i&gt; = &lt;i&gt;value&lt;/i&gt;&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; where &lt;code&gt;&lt;i&gt;variableName&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/code&gt; is the name of the attribute&#10; in a format suitable for &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/kernel/util/NamedObj.html#setName&quot;&gt;setName(String)&lt;/a&gt;&#10; (i.e., does not contain periods) and  &lt;code&gt;&lt;i&gt;value&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/code&gt; is&#10; the expression in the Ptolemy expression language.&#10; Comments are lines that begin with the &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; character.&#10; Each line in the file is interpreted as a separate assignment.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;The attributes that are created will have the same&#10; visibility as parameters of the container of the attribute.&#10; They are shadowed, however, by parameters of the container.&#10; That is, if the container has a parameter with the same name&#10; as one in the parameter set, the one in the container provides&#10; the value to any observer.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;If the file is modified during execution of a model, by default&#10; this will not be noticed until the next run. If you set the&#10; &lt;i&gt;checkForFileUpdates&lt;/i&gt; parameter to &lt;i&gt;true&lt;/i&gt;, then&#10; on each prefiring of the enclosing opaque composite actor,&#10; this parameter will check for updates of the file. Otherwise,&#10; it will only check between runs of the model or when the file&#10; name or URL gets changed.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;Note that the order the parameters are created is arbitrary,&#10; this is because we read the file in using java.util.Properties.load(),&#10; which uses a HashMap to store the properties.  We use a Properties.load()&#10; because it provides a nice parser for the files and can read and write&#10; values in both text and XML.  </description>
  <author>Christopher Brooks, contributor: Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 5.2</since>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="checkForFileUpdates">If this parameter is set to true, then the specified file or&#10;  URL will be checked for updates on every prefiring of the&#10;  enclosing opaque composite actor. Otherwise, it will check&#10;  for updates only between runs. This is a boolean that&#10;  defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.FileParameter-->
    <property name="fileOrURL">A parameter naming the file or URL to be read that contains&#10;  attribute names and values.  The file should be in a format&#10;  suitable for java.util.Properties.load(), see the class&#10;  comment of this class for details.&#10;  This initial default value is the empty string &quot;&quot;,&#10;  which means that no file will be read and no parameter&#10;  values will be defined.</property>
</doc>
