<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Display" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.gui.Display">
  <description>
&lt;p&gt;&#10; Display the values of the tokens arriving on the input channels in a&#10; text area on the screen.  Each input token is written on a&#10; separate line.  The input type can be of any type.&#10; If the input happens to be a StringToken,&#10; then the surrounding quotation marks are stripped before printing&#10; the value of the token.  Thus, string-valued tokens can be used to&#10; generate arbitrary textual output, at one token per line.&#10; Tokens are read from the input only in&#10; the postfire() method, to allow them to settle in domains where they&#10; converge to a fixed point.&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#10;  This actor accepts any type of data on its input port, therefore it&#10; doesn't declare a type, but lets the type resolution algorithm find&#10; the least fixed point. If backward type inference is enabled, and&#10; no input type has been declared, the input is constrained to be&#10; equal to &lt;code&gt;BaseType.GENERAL&lt;/code&gt;. This will result in upstream&#10; ports resolving to the most general type rather than the most specific.&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor has a &lt;i&gt;suppressBlankLines&lt;/i&gt; parameter, whose default value&#10; is false. If this parameter is configured to be true, this actor does not&#10; put a blank line in the display.&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#10; Note that because of complexities in Swing, if you resize the display&#10; window, then, unlike the plotters, the new size will not be persistent.&#10; That is, if you save the model and then re-open it, the new size is&#10; forgotten.  To control the size, you should set the &lt;i&gt;rowsDisplayed&lt;/i&gt;&#10; and &lt;i&gt;columnsDisplayed&lt;/i&gt; parameters.&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#10; Note that this actor internally uses JTextArea, a Java Swing object&#10; that is known to consume large amounts of memory. It is not advisable&#10; to use this actor to log large output streams.&lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Yuhong Xiong, Edward A. Lee Contributors: Ishwinder Singh</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (yuhong)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (vogel)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="input">The input port, which is a multiport.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="columnsDisplayed">The horizontal size of the display, in columns. This contains&#10;  an integer, and defaults to 40.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="rowsDisplayed">The vertical size of the display, in rows. This contains an&#10;  integer, and defaults to 10.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="suppressBlankLines">The flag indicating whether this display actor suppress&#10;  blank lines. The default value is false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="title">The title to put on top. Note that the value of the title&#10;  overrides the value of the name of the actor or the display&#10;  name of the actor.</property>
</doc>
