<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="SketchedSource" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.gui.SketchedSource">
  <description>
This actor is a plotter that also produces as its output a&#10; signal that has been sketched by the user on the screen.&#10; The &lt;i&gt;length&lt;/i&gt; parameter specifies the&#10; number of samples in the sketched signal.  The &lt;i&gt;periodic&lt;/i&gt;&#10; parameter, if true, specifies that the signal should be repeated.&#10; If this parameter is false, then the sketched signal is produced&#10; exactly once, at the beginning of the execution of the model.  If&#10; &lt;i&gt;periodic&lt;/i&gt; is true and the sketch is modified during&#10; execution of the model, then the modification appears in the next&#10; cycle after the modification has been completed.  In&#10; other words, the change does not appear mid-cycle.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor is also a plotter, and will plot the input signals&#10; on the same plot as the sketched signal.  It can be used in a&#10; feedback loop where the output affects the input. The first batch&#10; of outputs is produced in the initialize() method, so it can&#10; be put in a feedback loop in a dataflow model.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (vogel)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">The output port.  The type of this port is double.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="initialTrace">The default signal to generate, prior to any user sketch.&#10;  By default, this contains an array of zeros with the length&#10;  given by the &lt;i&gt;length&lt;/i&gt; parameter.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="length">The length of the output signal that will be generated.&#10;  This parameter must contain an IntToken.  By default, it has&#10;  value 100.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="periodic">An indicator of whether the signal should be periodically&#10;  repeated.  This parameter must contain a boolean token.&#10;  By default, it has value true.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="runOnModification">If &lt;i&gt;true&lt;/i&gt;, then when the user edits the plot, if the&#10;  manager is currently idle, then run the model.&#10;  This is a boolean that defaults to &lt;i&gt;false&lt;/i&gt;.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="yBottom">The bottom of the Y range. This is a double, with default value -1.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="yTop">The top of the Y range. This is a double, with default value 1.0.</property>
</doc>
