<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="SchedulingRelation" class="ptolemy.domains.ptera.kernel.SchedulingRelation">
  <description>
A scheduling relation is an edge from one Ptera event to another. If it is not&#10; a cancelling edge, then processing the event at the starting point of the edge&#10; causes the one at the end point to be scheduled after a certain amount of&#10; model-time delay, if the guard of the scheduling relation is satisfied. If it&#10; is a cancelling edge, then processing the first event causes the second one to&#10; be cancelled if it is already scheduled in the containing Ptera controller's&#10; event queue.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; A scheduling relation may carry argument values to be supplied to the event to&#10; be scheduled, who has parameters defined on it. The number and types of the&#10; evaluated arguments must match those of the parameters declared by the event.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; If the guard of a scheduling relation is omitted, it is defaulted to true,&#10; which means the scheduling relation is unconditional.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; A scheduling relation can be assigned a priority, which is an integer number.&#10; The default priority is 0. Priorities are used to order the scheduling&#10; relations from the same event. Scheduling relations with higher priorities&#10; (smaller priority numbers) are scheduled before those with lower priorities&#10; from the same event, if they are scheduled at exactly the same time in the&#10; future.  </description>
  <author>Thomas Huining Feng</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 8.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (tfeng)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (tfeng)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="canceling">A Boolean-valued parameter that defines whether this scheduling relation&#10;        is cancelling.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.Priority-->
    <property name="priority">The priority of this scheduling relation.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="triggers">A comma-separated list of port names and variable names to be&#10;  monitored.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute-->
    <property name="arguments">The attribute for arguments. Its value must be evaluated to an&#10;        ArrayToken or RecordToken, though this evaluation is performed only when&#10;        this scheduling relation is to be considered by the starting event but&#10;        not when this attribute is set by the designer.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute-->
    <property name="delay">The attribute for the model-time delay. Its value must be evaluated to a&#10;        ScalarToken, though this evaluation is performed only when this&#10;        scheduling relation is to be considered by the starting event but not&#10;        when this attribute is set by the designer.</property>
</doc>
