<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="GRShadedShape" class="ptolemy.domains.gr.lib.GRShadedShape">
  <description>
An abstract base class for GR Actors that have material and color&#10; properties.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The parameter &lt;i&gt;diffuseColor&lt;/i&gt; determines&#10; the color of the object in the usual sense that it determines the&#10; color of light reflected off the object. The default is gray.&#10; The parameter &lt;i&gt;emissiveColor&lt;/i&gt; specifies a color that is&#10; emitted by the object, and hence does not depend on illumination.&#10; It is black by default, which means that the object does not emit&#10; any light and will be invisible without illumination. The&#10; parameter &lt;i&gt;specularColor&lt;/i&gt; determines the color of highlights&#10; that are reflected by the object if the object is set to be shiny.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The parameter &lt;i&gt;shininess&lt;/i&gt; determines the shininess of the object.&#10; It ranges from 1.0 (the default) to 128.0, meaning not shiny to very&#10; shiny. A shiny object reflects the &lt;i&gt;specularColor&lt;/i&gt;, unless&#10; it is black, in which case shininess has no effect.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The &lt;i&gt;texture&lt;/i&gt; parameter can be used to specify an image file.&#10; The specified image will be mapped onto the shape.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The parameter &lt;i&gt;transparency&lt;/i&gt; determines the transparency of the&#10; object. It ranges from 0.0 (the default) to 1.0, meaning opaque to&#10; fully transparent (which makes the object invisible).&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The &lt;i&gt;wireFrame&lt;/i&gt; parameter can be used to view only the lines&#10; that outline the polygons of the object and not the surface.&#10; The &lt;i&gt;flat&lt;/i&gt; parameter can be set to make rendered polygons&#10; flat rather than rounded at the corners.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The &lt;i&gt;allowRuntimeChanges&lt;/i&gt; parameter, if true, specifies&#10; that changes to parameter values during the execution of the model&#10; take effect immediately. By default, this parameter is false,&#10; which means that changes to parameter values take effect only&#10; on the next run of the model. A value of false yields better&#10; performance, but less interactivity.  Changing this to true will&#10; only have an effect on the next run of the model.  </description>
  <author>C. Fong, Steve Neuendorffer, Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Green (liuxj)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="sceneGraphOut">The output port for connecting to other GR Actors in&#10;  the scene graph. The type is SceneGraphToken.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="allowRuntimeChanges">If true, then changes to parameter values can be made during&#10;  execution of the model. This is a boolean that defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.gui.ColorAttribute-->
    <property name="diffuseColor">The diffuse color, which is the color of the object reflecting&#10;  illumination. Note that the alpha value (the fourth&#10;  element of the array), which would normally specify transparency,&#10;  is ignored. The default color is grey.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.gui.ColorAttribute-->
    <property name="emissiveColor">The emissive color, which is a color that does not depend on&#10;  ambient illumination. Note that the alpha value (the fourth&#10;  element of the array), which would normally specify transparency,&#10;  is ignored. The default color is black, which means that there&#10;  is no emissive color (illumination is required).</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.DoubleRangeParameter-->
    <property name="shininess">The shininess of the 3D shape.&#10;  This parameter should contain a DoubleToken in the range 1.0&#10;  to 128.0, where 1.0 represents not shiny and 128.0 represents&#10;  very shiny.  This is a double with default 1.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.gui.ColorAttribute-->
    <property name="specularColor">The specular color, which is a color of a highlight reflecting&#10;  ambient illumination. Note that the alpha value (the fourth&#10;  element of the array), which would normally specify transparency,&#10;  is ignored. The default color is white, which means that the&#10;  illumination is reflected white.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.FileParameter-->
    <property name="texture">Texture URL, which if non-empty, specifies an image file&#10;  or URL. The image from the file is mapped onto the shape&#10;  as a texture.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.DoubleRangeParameter-->
    <property name="transparency">The transparency, where 0.0 means opaque (the default) and 1.0&#10;  means fully transparent. The type is double.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="wireFrame">If true, render the shape using a wire frame. This is a boolean&#10;  that defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="flat">If true, render the facets flat rather than rounded.&#10;  This is a boolean that defaults to false.</property>
</doc>
