<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Rotate2D" class="ptolemy.domains.gr.lib.Rotate2D">
  <description>
Rotate a two-dimensional figure based on the angle, and anchor point&#10; provided by the user.  The angle, step, and anchor points can either&#10; be preset in the parameter edit window, or updated dynamically through&#10; the actor's ports.  The angle can be specified in radians or degrees&#10; by selecting the angle type in the parameter edit window.  Angles&#10; increase clockwise beginning at the positive X-axis in a Cartesian&#10; plane.  If the &lt;i&gt;accumulate&lt;/i&gt; parameter defined in the base class&#10; is set to true, any changes to the angle of rotation will be relative&#10; to the figure's current orientation.  Otherwise, the angle specified&#10; will be relative to the positive X-axis.  </description>
  <author>Ismael M. Sarmiento, Steve Neuendorffer</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (ismael)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (chf)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="theta">The angle the figure is to be rotated by, measured clockwise from&#10;  the positive X-axis on a Cartesian plane.  The default double value&#10;  is 0.0.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="anchorX">The X coordinate of the point the figure is to be rotated about.&#10;  The default double value is 0.0.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="anchorY">The Y coordinate of the point the figure is to be rotated about.&#10;  The default double value is 0.0.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="initialTheta">The initial angle of rotation.  The default double value is 0.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="initialAnchorX">The initial x-coordinate of the anchor point.&#10;  The default double value is 0.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="initialAnchorY">The initial y-coordinate of the anchor point.&#10;  The default double value is 0.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute-->
    <property name="angleType">How the angle is specified.  Can be &lt;B&gt;degrees&lt;/B&gt; or&#10;  &lt;B&gt;radians&lt;/B&gt; (default).</property>
</doc>
