<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="DifferentialSystem" class="ptolemy.domains.continuous.lib.DifferentialSystem">
  <description>
A differential system in the Continuous domain.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;The differential system  model implements a system whose behavior&#10; is defined by:&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10; dx/dt = f(x, u, t)&#10; y = g(x, u, t)&#10; x(0) = x0&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; where x is the state vector, u is the input vector, and y is the output&#10; vector, t is the time. To use this actor, proceed through the following&#10; steps:&#10; &lt;ul&gt;&#10; &lt;li&gt; For each input in &lt;i&gt;u&lt;/i&gt;, create an input port.&#10; Each input may have any name, since you will refer to it by&#10; name rather than by the symbol &lt;i&gt;u&lt;/i&gt;. This actor will&#10; automatically create a parameter with the same name as the&#10; input port. That parameter will have its value set during&#10; execution to match the value of the input.&#10; Note that at this time, multiport inputs are not supported.&#10;&#10; &lt;li&gt; Fill in the &lt;i&gt;stateVariableNames&lt;/i&gt; parameter, which is&#10; an array of strings, with the names of the state variables in &lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; These names can be anything you like, since you will refer them to&#10; by name rather than by the symbol &lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;.&#10;&#10; &lt;li&gt; For each state variable name in &lt;i&gt;stateVariableNames&lt;/i&gt;,&#10; create a parameter with a value equal to the initial value of that&#10; particular state variable.&#10;&#10; &lt;li&gt; Specify an update function (part of &lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt; above) for each&#10; state variable by creating a parameter named &lt;i&gt;name&lt;/i&gt;_dot, where&#10; &lt;i&gt;name&lt;/i&gt; is the name of the state variable. The value of this&#10; parameter should be an expression giving the rate of change of&#10; this state variable as a function of any of the state variables,&#10; any input, any other actor parameter, and (possibly), the variable&#10; &lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt;, representing current time.&#10;&#10; &lt;li&gt; For each output in &lt;i&gt;y&lt;/i&gt;, create an output port.&#10; The output may have any name. This actor will automatically&#10; create a parameter with the same name as the output port.&#10;&#10; &lt;li&gt; For each parameter matching an output port, set its&#10; value to be an expression giving the output&#10; value as a function of the state variables, the inputs, any other&#10; actor parameter, and (possibly), the variable&#10; &lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt;, representing current time.&#10;&#10; &lt;/ul&gt;&#10; &lt;P&gt;&#10; This actor is a higher-order component. Upon preinitialization,&#10; the actor will create a subsystem using integrators and expressions.&#10; These are not persistent (they are not exported in the MoML file),&#10; and will instead by created each time the actor is preinitialized.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor is based on the ptolemy.domain.ct.lib.DifferentialSystem&#10; actor by Jie Liu.  </description>
  <author>Jie Liu and Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 7.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (liuj)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="stateVariableNames">The names of the state variables, in an array of strings.&#10;  The default is an ArrayToken of an empty String.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="t">The value of current time. This parameter is not visible in&#10;  the expression screen except in expert mode. Its value initially&#10;  is just 0.0, a double, but upon each firing, it is given a&#10;  value equal to the current time as reported by the director.</property>
</doc>
