<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="PeriodicSampler" class="ptolemy.domains.continuous.lib.PeriodicSampler">
  <description>
This actor generates discrete events by periodically sampling the input signal.&#10; The sampling rate is given by parameter &lt;i&gt;samplePeriod&lt;/i&gt;, which has default value&#10; 0.1.  Specifically, if the actor is initialized at time &lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt; and the sample&#10; period is &lt;i&gt;T&lt;/i&gt;, then the output will have the value of the input&#10; at times &lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;nT&lt;/i&gt;, for all natural numbers &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; By default, this sampler will send to the output the initial value of&#10; the input (the input value at microstep 0), but will send it one&#10; microstep later (at microstep 1).&#10; This ensures that the output at microstep 0 is always absent, thus&#10; ensuring continuity from the left. That is, the input is absent prior&#10; to the sample time, so continuity requires that it be absent at&#10; microstep 0 at the sample time.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; To get this sampler to record values other than the initial value,&#10; set the &lt;i&gt;microstep&lt;/i&gt; parameter to a value greater than 0.&#10; Setting it to 1, for example, will record the input value after&#10; a discontinuity rather than before the discontinuity. Note&#10; that &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/Sampler.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.lib.Sampler&lt;/a&gt; normally records its inputs at microstep 1&#10; (because it is triggered by a discrete signal, which has events&#10; at microstep 1), and therefore if you want this PeriodicSampler&#10; to behave the same as Sampler, you should set &lt;i&gt;microstep&lt;/i&gt;&#10; to 1.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor has multiport inputs and outputs. Signals in&#10; each input channel are sampled and produced to corresponding output&#10; channel.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Note that this actor does not tolerate changing input or output&#10; connections during execution.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 8.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="microstep">The microstep at which to read the input. This is an&#10;  whose default value is 0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="samplePeriod">The parameter for the sampling period. This is a double&#10;  whose default value is 0.1.</property>
</doc>
