<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="PteraModalModel" class="ptolemy.domains.ptera.kernel.PteraModalModel">
  <description>
This is a typed composite actor to be a Ptera modal model. A Ptera modal model&#10; has a Ptera (Ptolemy Event Relation Actor) model inside. The Ptera model has a&#10; number of events, and scheduling relations may exist between events, meaning&#10; that the processing of the starting event causes the ending event to occur&#10; after a certain amount of model time. A scheduling relation may also be guarded&#10; by a Boolean expression.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The controller of a Ptera modal model is a Ptera controller (instance of &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/domains/ptera/kernel/PteraController.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.domains.ptera.kernel.PteraController&lt;/a&gt;). The Ptera controller contains an &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/domains/ptera/kernel/PteraDirector.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.domains.ptera.kernel.PteraDirector&lt;/a&gt;,&#10; which has an event queue to store scheduled events in time-stamp order. The&#10; Ptera modal model itself also has a Ptera director. The Ptera director in the&#10; controller maintains its own event queue, and schedules itself to be fired by&#10; putting the controller in the event queue of the Ptera modal model's director.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; An event can have one or more refinements. A refinement can be an actor model,&#10; an FSM model, or a Ptera model. If a refinement is a Ptera model, then its&#10; controller reports its earliest event to the controller of this modal model,&#10; which fires it when the model time reaches the reported time in the future. If&#10; the Ptera refinement itself contains an event that has a refinement in Ptera,&#10; that controller reports to the controller one level above, which in turn&#10; reports to the modal model.  </description>
  <author>Thomas Huining Feng</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 8.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (tfeng)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (tfeng)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
</doc>
