<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="AtomicWirelessChannel" class="ptolemy.domains.wireless.kernel.AtomicWirelessChannel">
  <description>
The base class for communication channels in the wireless domain.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;To use this class, place it in a wireless model that contains&#10; a wireless director and wireless actors (actors whose ports are&#10; instances of WirelessIOPort).  Then set the &lt;i&gt;outsideChannel&lt;/i&gt;&#10; parameter of those ports to match the name of this channel.  The&#10; model can also itself contain ports that are instances of&#10; WirelessIOPort, in which case their &lt;i&gt;insideChannel&lt;/i&gt; parameter&#10; should contain the name of this channel if they should use this&#10; channel.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; In this base class, transmission on a channel reaches all ports&#10; at the same level of the hierarchy that are instances of&#10; WirelessIOPort and that specify that they use this channel. These&#10; ports include those contained by entities that have the container&#10; as this channel and that have their &lt;i&gt;outsideChannel&lt;/i&gt;&#10; parameter set to the name of this channel.  They also include&#10; those ports whose containers are the same as the container of&#10; this channel and whose &lt;i&gt;insideChannel&lt;/i&gt; parameter matches&#10; this channel name.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Derived classes will typically limit the range of the transmission,&#10; using for example location information from the ports. They&#10; may also introduce random losses or corruption of data.  To do this,&#10; derived classes can override the _isInRange() protected method,&#10; or the transmit() public method.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Other classes may register a property transformer that allows them&#10; to modify meta data prior to transmission of the data token on the channel.  </description>
  <author>Xiaojun Liu, Edward A. Lee, Yang Zhao, Heather Taylor, Elaine Cheong</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="defaultProperties">The default properties for transmission. In this base class,&#10;  the type is constrained to be a record and the default value&#10;  is set to an empty record.  Derived classes&#10;  will define this to be a record.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.NameParameter-->
    <property name="name">When set to a non-empty value, this NameParameter will cause&#10;  the name of this channel to be set to this value.</property>
</doc>
