<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="WirelessToWired" class="ptolemy.domains.wireless.lib.WirelessToWired">
  <description>
On each firing, this actor reads at most one token from the input&#10; port and output the payload on the &lt;i&gt;payload&lt;/i&gt; port and the properties&#10; on the &lt;i&gt;properties&lt;/i&gt; port.  If there are no properties, then&#10; output a token only on the &lt;i&gt;payload&lt;/i&gt; port.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; NOTE: The type of the properties port is inferred from the&#10; &lt;i&gt;defaultProperties&lt;/i&gt; field of the channel at preinitialize()&#10; time. If the channel is changed during execution, or this&#10; field is changed, then the type of the port will not be updated,&#10; and a run-time type error could occur.&#10; Thus, this actor assumes that these types do not change.&#10; If the channel has no default properties (as in the base class&#10; AtomicWirelessChannel), then the type of the properties port will&#10; be undefined. If it is left disconnected, then this is fine,&#10; but if it is connected, then its type will need to be declared&#10; explicitly.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="payload">Output port that transmits the payload received on the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt;&#10;  port. This has the same type as the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.domains.wireless.kernel.WirelessIOPort-->
    <port name="input">Input port that receives a wireless input.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="properties">Output port that transmits the properties received on the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt;&#10;  port. The type of this port is a record type.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="inputChannelName">Name of the input channel. This is a string that defaults to&#10;  &quot;AtomicWirelessChannel&quot;.</property>
</doc>
