<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Waveform" class="ptolemy.domains.continuous.lib.Waveform">
  <description>
This actor produces a periodic continuous-time signal defined by a&#10; periodic sequence of samples and an interpolation method.&#10; The &lt;i&gt;interpolation&lt;/i&gt; parameter specifies the interpolation method,&#10; which is either &quot;linear&quot;,   which indicates linear interpolation, or &quot;hermite&quot;,&#10; which indicates  third order interpolation based on the Hermite curves in chapter&#10; 11 of &quot;Computer Graphic, Principles and Practice&quot;, by Foley, van Dam, Feiner&#10; and Hughes, 2nd ed. in C, 1996. Interpolation is calculated assuming that&#10; the waveform is periodic.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; At the beginning of each time interval of length given by &lt;i&gt;period&lt;/i&gt;,&#10; starting from the time at which initialize() is invoked,&#10; this actor initiates a continuous output that passes through the values given by&#10; &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; at the time offsets into the period given by &lt;i&gt;offsets&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; These parameters contain arrays, which are required to have the same length.&#10; The &lt;i&gt;offsets&lt;/i&gt; array contains doubles, which&#10; must be nondecreasing and nonnegative,&#10; or an exception will be thrown when it is set.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; You can provide a finite &lt;i&gt;stopTime&lt;/i&gt;. Upon reaching that stop time,&#10; postfire() returns false, which requests that the director&#10; not fire this actor again. The output will be absent after that time.&#10; The clock can also be started and stopped repeatedly&#10; during an execution. A token at the &lt;i&gt;start&lt;/i&gt; input will start the clock&#10; at the beginning of a period. A token&#10; at the &lt;i&gt;stop&lt;/i&gt; input will stop the clock, if it is still running.&#10; If both &lt;i&gt;start&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;stop&lt;/i&gt; are received simultaneously, then&#10; the clock will be stopped. When the clock is stopped, the output is absent.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; parameter by default&#10; contains the array {1.0, -1.0}.  The default&#10; &lt;i&gt;offsets&lt;/i&gt; array is {0.0, 1.0}.&#10; The default period is 2.0. This results in a triangle&#10; wave (for linear interpolation) and a smooth sinusoid-like&#10; waveform (for hermite interpolation).&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The type of the output is double.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; If two offsets are equal, or if one is equal to the period,&#10; then two events will be produced at the same time, but with&#10; different microsteps. This will cause strange effects with&#10; hermite interpolation, and hence is not recommended. But&#10; it can sometimes be useful with linear interpolation to get&#10; discontinuous outputs.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; If the &lt;i&gt;period&lt;/i&gt; is changed at any time, either by&#10; provided by an input or by changing the parameter, then the&#10; new period will take effect immediately if the new period&#10; is provided at the same time (including the&#10; microstep) that the current cycle starts,&#10; or after the current cycle completes otherwise.  </description>
  <author>Sarah Packman, Yuhong Xiong, Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (yuhong)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (yuhong)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="interpolation">The interpolation method, which must be &quot;linear&quot; or &quot;hermite&quot;.</property>
</doc>
