<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Register" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.vhdl.Register">
  <description>
A register is a stateful actor with a trigger port that accepts&#10; read requests.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; In the fire() method, if there is an event on the &lt;i&gt;trigger&lt;/i&gt;&#10; input port, this actor will produce an output event. The value&#10; of the output event will be the previously recorded event&#10; from the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port, or the value of the &lt;i&gt;initialValue&lt;/i&gt;&#10; parameter if there has been no previous input event. If, however,&#10; &lt;i&gt;initialValue&lt;/i&gt; contains no value, then no output will be&#10; produced. In the postfire() method, if there is an input event on&#10; the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port, then its value is recorded to be used&#10; in future firings as the value of the output.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The inputs can be of any token type, but the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; port&#10; is constrained to be of a type at least that of the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt;&#10; port and the &lt;i&gt;initialValue&lt;/i&gt; parameter.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This class extends Sampler. Unlike its base class, this actor&#10; can be used to break dependencies in a feedback loop in that&#10; the input tokens are consumed from the input ports after the outputs&#10; are generated. Another difference is that the Register actor can be&#10; fired when either the trigger port or the input port has a token, while&#10; the Sampler can only be fired when the trigger port receives a token.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Both the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port and the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; port are multiports.&#10; Generally, their widths should match. Otherwise, if the width of the&#10; &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; is greater than the width of the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt;, the extra&#10; input tokens will not appear on any output, although they will be&#10; consumed from the input port. If the width of the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; is&#10; greater than that of the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt;, then the last few channels of&#10; the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; will never emit tokens.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Note: If the width of the input changes during execution, then the&#10; most recent inputs are forgotten, as if the execution of the model&#10; were starting over.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee, Haiyang Zheng</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.1</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (eal)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="input">Input for tokens to be added.  This is a multiport of fix point&#10;  type</port>
</doc>
