<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="AFDXSwitch" class="ptolemy.domains.de.lib.aspect.AFDXSwitch">
  <description>
A &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../../ptolemy/actor/CommunicationAspect.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.CommunicationAspect&lt;/a&gt; actor that, when its&#10;  &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../../ptolemy/domains/de/lib/aspect/AFDXSwitch.html#sendToken&quot;&gt;sendToken(Receiver, Receiver, Token)&lt;/a&gt; method is called, delays&#10;  the delivery of the specified token to the specified receiver&#10;  according to a service rule. This communication aspect is used on&#10;  input ports by setting a parameter with an ObjectToken that refers&#10;  to this CommunicationAspect at the port. Note that the name of this&#10;  parameter is irrelevant.&#10;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;This communication aspect implements an AFDX switch. It has a parameter&#10;  specifying the number of ports. On each port, an actor is connected.&#10;  Note that these ports are not represented as ptolemy actor ports.&#10;  This actor can send tokens to the switch and receive tokens from the&#10;  switch. The mapping of ports to actors is done via parameters of this&#10;  communication aspect.&#10;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;Internally, this switch has a buffer for every input, a buffer&#10;  for the switch fabric and a buffer for every output. The delays&#10;  introduced by the buffers are configured via parameters. Tokens are&#10;  processed simultaneously on the buffers.&#10;&#10;  &lt;p&gt; This switch implements the specific switch for the AFDX network.&#10;  This implementation is based on the basic switch implementation.  </description>
  <author>Gilles Lasnier, Based on BasiSwitch.java by Patricia Derler</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (glasnier)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (glasnier)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="numberOfPorts">Number of ports on the switch. This parameter must contain an&#10;  IntToken.  The value defaults to 2.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="inputBufferDelay">Time it takes for a token to be put into the input queue.&#10;  This parameter must contain a DoubleToken. The value defaults&#10;  to 0.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="outputBufferDelay">Time it takes for a token to be put into the output queue.&#10;  This parameter must contain a DoubleToken. The value defaults&#10;  to 0.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="technologicalDelay">Technological latency according to the AFDX specification.&#10;  This parameter must contain a DoubleToken. The value defaults&#10;  to 0.000140 (140 us).</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="bitRate">The bit rate of the bus. The value defaults to 100 Mbits/s.</property>
</doc>
