<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="JSAccessor" class="org.terraswarm.accessor.JSAccessor">
  <description>
An component accessor that consists of an interface and a script.&#10;&#10;   &lt;p&gt;The &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;#VisionOfSwarmLets&quot;&gt;Vision of Swarmlets&lt;/a&gt;&quot; paper&#10;   defines three types of accessors: Interface, Component and Composite.&#10;   The paper states: &quot;A component accessor has an interface and a&#10;   script...  The script defines one or more functions that are invoked&#10;   by the swarmlet host.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;   &lt;p&gt;This is a specialized JavaScript actor that hides the script&#10;   from casual users by putting it in &quot;expert&quot; mode.&#10;   It also sets the actor to &quot;restricted&quot; mode, which restricts&#10;   the functionality of the methods methods and variables&#10;   provided in the JavaScript context.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;   &lt;p&gt;FIXME: This should support versioning of accessors.&#10;   It should check the accessorSource for updates and replace&#10;   itself if there is a newer version and the user agrees to&#10;   the replacement. This will be tricky because any parameters&#10;   and connections previously set should be preserved.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;   &lt;p&gt;This actor extends &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/jjs/JavaScript.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.lib.jjs.JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&#10;   and thus requires Nashorn, which is present in Java-1.8 and&#10;   later.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;   &lt;p&gt;This actor will run &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;node&lt;/code&gt;, which&#10;   require network access.  To skip running things that require network&#10;   access, set the &lt;code&gt;PT_NO_NET&lt;/code&gt; environment variable to a&#10;   non-empty string.  For example, under bash:&lt;/p&gt;&#10;   &lt;pre&gt;&#10;   export PT_NO_NET=true&#10;   &lt;/pre&gt;&#10;   &lt;p&gt;Note that if &lt;code&gt;PT_NO_NET&lt;/code&gt; is set to any value, then&#10;   the actor will attempt to avoid using the network.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;   &lt;p&gt;To always run ptdoc, set the &lt;code&gt;PT_RUN_PTDOC&lt;/code&gt;&#10;   environment variable.  Otherwise, if PT_NO_NET is not set, then the&#10;   ptdocs are only regenerated when the git pull modifies a&#10;   file.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;   &lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;&#10;&#10;   &lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;VisionOfSwarmLets&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Latronico, Edward A. Lee, Marten Lohstroh, Chris Shaver, Armin Wasicek, Matt Weber.&lt;/a&gt;&#10;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.terraswarm.org/pubs/332.html&quot;&gt;A Vision of Swarmlets&lt;/a&gt;,&#10;   &lt;i&gt;IEEE Internet Computing, Special Issue on Building Internet of Things Software&lt;/i&gt;,&#10;   19(2):20-29, March 2015.&lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee, Contributor: Christopher Brooks</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 11.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.SharedParameter-->
    <property name="checkoutOrUpdateAccessorsRepository">If true, then check out the accessors git&#10;  repository when the accessor is reloaded and run ant to build&#10;  the PtDoc files.  This repository is not currently publically&#10;  readable.  This parameter is a boolean, and the initial&#10;  default value is true.  This parameter is a shared parameter,&#10;  meaning that changing it for any one instance in a model will&#10;  change it for all instances in the model.</property>
</doc>
