<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="NamedObj" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.NamedObj">
  <description>
This is a base class for almost all Ptolemy II objects.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This class supports a naming scheme, change requests, a persistent&#10; file format (MoML), a mutual exclusion mechanism for models (the&#10; workspace), an error handler, and a hierarchical class mechanism&#10; with inheritance.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; An instance of this class can also be parameterized by attaching&#10; instances of the Attribute class.&#10; Instances of Attribute can be attached by calling their setContainer()&#10; method and passing this object as an argument. Those instances will&#10; then be reported by the &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/kernel/util/NamedObj.html#getAttribute&quot;&gt;getAttribute(String)&lt;/a&gt;,&#10; &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/kernel/util/NamedObj.html#getAttribute&quot;&gt;getAttribute(String, Class)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/kernel/util/NamedObj.html#attributeList&quot;&gt;attributeList()&lt;/a&gt;&#10; and &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/kernel/util/NamedObj.html#attributeList&quot;&gt;attributeList(Class)&lt;/a&gt; methods.&#10; Classes derived from NamedObj may constrain attributes to be a&#10; subclass of Attribute.  To do that, they should override the protected&#10; _addAttribute(Attribute) method to throw an exception if&#10; the object provided is not of the right class.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; An instance of this class has a name.&#10; A name is an arbitrary string with no periods.  If no&#10; name is provided, the name is taken to be an empty string (not a null&#10; reference). An instance also has a full name, which is a concatenation&#10; of the container's full name and the simple name, separated by a&#10; period. If there is no container, then the full name begins with a&#10; period. The full name is used for error reporting throughout Ptolemy&#10; II.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Instances of this class are associated with a workspace, specified as&#10; a constructor argument.  The reference to the workspace is immutable.&#10; It cannot be changed during the lifetime of this object.  It is used for&#10; synchronization of methods that depend on or modify the state of&#10; objects within it. If no workspace is specified, then the default&#10; workspace is used.  Note that the workspace should not be confused&#10; with the container.  The workspace never serves as a container.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; In this base class, the container is null by default, and no&#10; method is provided to change it. Derived classes that support&#10; hierarchy provide one or more methods that set the container.&#10; By convention, if the container is set,&#10; then the instance should be removed from the workspace directory, if&#10; it is present.  The workspace directory is expected to list only&#10; top-level objects in a hierarchy.  The NamedObj can still use the&#10; workspace for synchronization.  Any object contained by another uses&#10; the workspace of its container as its own workspace by default.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This class supports &lt;i&gt;change requests&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;mutations&lt;/i&gt;,&#10; which are changes to a model that are performed in a disciplined&#10; fashion.  In particular, a mutation can be requested via the&#10; &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/kernel/util/NamedObj.html#requestChange&quot;&gt;requestChange(ChangeRequest)&lt;/a&gt; method. By default, when&#10; a change is requested, the change is executed immediately.&#10; However, by calling &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/kernel/util/NamedObj.html#setDeferringChangeRequests&quot;&gt;setDeferringChangeRequests(boolean)&lt;/a&gt;,&#10; you can ensure that change requests are queued to be executed&#10; only when it is safe to execute them.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This class supports the notion of a &lt;i&gt;model error&lt;/i&gt;, which is&#10; an exception that is handled by a registered model error handler, or&#10; passed up the container hierarchy if there is no registered model&#10; error handler.  This mechanism complements the exception mechanism in&#10; Java. Instead of unraveling the calling stack to handle exceptions,&#10; this mechanism passes control up the Ptolemy II hierarchy.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Derived classes should override the _description() method to&#10; append new fields if there is new information that should be included&#10; in the description.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; A NamedObj can contain instances of &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/kernel/util/DecoratorAttributes.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.kernel.util.DecoratorAttributes&lt;/a&gt;. These are attributes that are&#10; added by another NamedObj that implements the &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/kernel/util/Decorator.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.kernel.util.Decorator&lt;/a&gt; interface.&#10; These attributes are stored separately and can be retrieved by using&#10; &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/kernel/util/NamedObj.html#getDecoratorAttributes&quot;&gt;getDecoratorAttributes(Decorator)&lt;/a&gt; or&#10; &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/kernel/util/NamedObj.html#getDecoratorAttribute&quot;&gt;getDecoratorAttribute(Decorator, String)&lt;/a&gt;.  </description>
  <author>Mudit Goel, Edward A. Lee, Neil Smyth, Contributor: Bert Rodiers</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 0.2</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Green (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
</doc>
