<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Accumulator" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.Accumulator">
  <description>
Output the initial value plus the sum of all the inputs since&#10; the last time a true token was received at the reset port.&#10; One output is produced each time the actor is fired. The&#10; inputs and outputs can be any token type that supports addition.&#10; The output type is constrained to be greater than or&#10; equal to the input type and the type of the &lt;i&gt;init&lt;/i&gt; parameter.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; If the input and &lt;i&gt;init&lt;/i&gt; data type are scalars, then you can&#10; also set the &lt;i&gt;lowerBound&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;upperBound&lt;/i&gt; parameters to&#10; limit the range of the accumulated value.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 2.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (neuendor)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="reset">If this port receives a True token on any channel, then the&#10;  accumulator state will be reset to the initial value.&#10;  This is a multiport and has type boolean.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="lowerBound">The lower bound. If this is set, then its type must be the&#10;  same as that of the &lt;i&gt;init&lt;/i&gt; parameter, and the output&#10;  will be constrained to never drop below the lower bound.&#10;  By default, this is not set, so there is no lower bound.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="init">The value produced by the actor on its first iteration.&#10;  The default value of this parameter is the integer 0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="upperBound">The upper bound. If this is set, then its type must be the&#10;  same as that of the &lt;i&gt;init&lt;/i&gt; parameter, and the output&#10;  will be constrained to never rise above the upper bound.&#10;  By default, this is not set, so there is no upper bound.</property>
</doc>
