<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="ArrayLevelCrossing" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.ArrayLevelCrossing">
  <description>
&lt;p&gt;Search an array from the specified starting index and report the&#10; index of the first item in the array that is below or above the&#10; specified threshold.  If there is no such item, then -1 is&#10; returned.  The threshold can be absolute or relative to the value&#10; at the starting index.  If it is relative, it can be given on a&#10; linear scale or in decibels.  If the threshold is relative and we&#10; are looking for values above the threshold, then values that are&#10; above the value at the starting index by more than the threshold&#10; are reported.  If the threshold is relative and we are looking for&#10; values below the threshold, then values that are below the value at&#10; the starting index by more than the threshold are reported.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; This actor is a generalization of Matlab code developed by John&#10; Signorotti of Southwest Research Institute. The original function&#10; was called UFDipSearch.&lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee, Steve Neuendorffer</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="array">The array to search for a threshold crossing.&#10;  This has type {double}.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">The output port producing the index of the first bin to break&#10;  the threshold.  This has type int.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="above">An indicator of whether to look for values above or below the&#10;  specified threshold.  This is a boolean that defaults to false,&#10;  which specifies to find values below the threshold.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="forwards">The direction to search from the start. If true, search forwards.&#10;  Otherwise, search backwards.  This is a boolean that defaults to true.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="scale">An indicator of whether &lt;i&gt;threshold&lt;/i&gt; should be interpreted&#10;  as absolute or relative, and if relative, then on a linear&#10;  scale, in amplitude decibels, or power decibels. If decibels&#10;  are used, then the corresponding linear threshold is&#10;  10^(&lt;i&gt;threshold&lt;/i&gt;/&lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;), where &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt; is 20 (for&#10;  amplitude decibels) or 10 (for power decibels).&#10;  This parameter is a string with possible values &quot;absolute&quot;,&#10;  &quot;relative linear&quot;, &quot;relative amplitude decibels&quot; or &quot;relative&#10;  power decibels&quot;. The default value is &quot;absolute&quot;.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.PortParameter-->
    <property name="start">The index from which to start looking for a threshold crossing.&#10;  This is an integer that defaults to 0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.PortParameter-->
    <property name="threshold">The threshold to look for. This is a double that can be&#10;  interpreted on an absolute or relative scale, and if relative,&#10;  on a linear or decibel scale, depending on the &lt;i&gt;scale&lt;/i&gt;&#10;  parameter. It defaults to 0.0.</property>
</doc>
