<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="ConfigurationSelect" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.ConfigurationSelect">
  <description>
Conditionally merge the streams at two input ports&#10; depending on the value of the boolean parameter.&#10; The token in the &lt;i&gt;selector&lt;/i&gt; parameter specifies the&#10; input port that should be read from in the next firing.&#10; If the &lt;i&gt;selector&lt;/i&gt; parameter&#10; token is false, then the &lt;i&gt;falseInput&lt;/i&gt; port is used,&#10; otherwise the &lt;i&gt;trueInput&lt;/i&gt; port is used. In the next&#10; firing, tokens are consumed from the specified&#10; port and sent to the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; port.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The actor is able to fire if the &lt;i&gt;selector&lt;/i&gt; parameter&#10; is either has a true or false token and there is a token on every&#10; channel of the specified input port.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; If the input port that is read has width greater than an output port, then&#10; some input tokens will be discarded (those on input channels for which&#10; there is no corresponding output channel).&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Because tokens are immutable, the same Token is sent&#10; to the output, rather than a copy.  The &lt;i&gt;trueInput&lt;/i&gt; and&#10; &lt;i&gt;falseInput&lt;/i&gt; port may receive Tokens of any type.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor is designed to be used with the DDF or PN director,&#10; but it can also be used with SR, DE, and possibly other domains.&#10; It should not be used with&#10; SDF because the number of tokens it consumes is not fixed.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor is similar to the BooleanSelect actor, except that&#10; it uses a parameter rather than a control port to determine which input&#10; to use.  </description>
  <author>Charles Shelton and Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 8.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (cshelton)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cshelton)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="trueInput">Input for tokens on the true path.  The type can be anything.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="falseInput">Input for tokens on the false path.  The type can be anything.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">The output port.  The type is at least the type of&#10;  &lt;i&gt;trueInput&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;falseInput&lt;/i&gt;</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="selector">Parameter that selects one of the two input ports.  The type is&#10;  BooleanToken that defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="trueInput_tokenConsumptionRate">This parameter provides token consumption rate for &lt;i&gt;trueInput&lt;/i&gt;.&#10;  The type is int and it defaults to zero.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="falseInput_tokenConsumptionRate">This parameter provides token consumption rate for &lt;i&gt;falseInput&lt;/i&gt;.&#10;  The type is int and it defaults to one.</property>
</doc>
