<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Lattice" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.Lattice">
  <description>
An FIR filter with a lattice structure.  The coefficients of such a&#10; filter are called &quot;reflection coefficients.&quot;  Lattice filters are&#10; typically used as linear predictors because it is easy to ensure that&#10; they are minimum phase, and hence that their inverse is stable.&#10; A lattice filter is (strictly) minimum phase if its reflection&#10; coefficients are all less than unity in magnitude.  To get the&#10; reflection coefficients for a linear predictor for a particular&#10; random process, you can use the LevinsonDurbin actor.&#10; The inputs and outputs are of type double.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The default reflection coefficients correspond to the optimal linear&#10; predictor for an AR process generated by filtering white noise with&#10; the following filter:&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10;                            1&#10; H(z) =  --------------------------------------&#10;         1 - 2z&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; + 1.91z&lt;sup&gt;-2&lt;/sup&gt; - 0.91z&lt;sup&gt;-3&lt;/sup&gt; + 0.205z&lt;sup&gt;-4&lt;/sup&gt;&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Since this filter is minimum phase, the transfer function of the lattice&#10; filter is &lt;i&gt;H &lt;/i&gt;&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;(&lt;i&gt;z&lt;/i&gt;).&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Note that the definition of reflection coefficients is not quite universal&#10; in the literature. The reflection coefficients in reference [2]&#10; are the negative of the ones used by this actor, which&#10; correspond to the definition in most other texts,&#10; and to the definition of partial-correlation (PARCOR)&#10; coefficients in the statistics literature.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The signs of the coefficients used in this actor are appropriate for values&#10; given by the LevinsonDurbin actor.&#10; The structure of the filter is as follows:&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10;      y[0]              y[1]               y[n-1]           y[n]&#10; X(n) -------o--&amp;gt;-(+)--&amp;gt;----o--&amp;gt;-(+)--&amp;gt;-- ... -&amp;gt;---o--&amp;gt;-(+)------&amp;gt;  Y(n)&#10;      |       \   /          \   /                  \   /&#10;      |      +K1 /          +K2 /                  +Kn /&#10;      |         X              X                      X&#10;      V      -K1 \          -K2 \                  -Kn \&#10;      |       /   \          /   \                  /   \&#10;      \-[z]--o--&amp;gt;-(+)-[z]---o--&amp;gt;-(+)-[z]- ... -&amp;gt;---o--&amp;gt;-(+)&#10;           w[0]         w[1]               w[n-1]           w[n]&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;[1]&#10; J. Makhoul, &quot;Linear Prediction: A Tutorial Review&quot;,&#10; &lt;i&gt;Proc. IEEE&lt;/i&gt;, Vol. 63, pp. 561-580, Apr. 1975.&#10; &lt;p&gt;[2]&#10; S. M. Kay, &lt;i&gt;Modern Spectral Estimation: Theory &amp;amp; Application&lt;/i&gt;,&#10; Prentice-Hall, Englewood Cliffs, NJ, 1988.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee, Christopher Hylands, Steve Neuendorffer</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="reflectionCoefficients">The reflection coefficients.  This is an array of doubles with&#10;  default value {0.804534, -0.820577, 0.521934, -0.205}. These&#10;  are the reflection coefficients for the linear predictor of a&#10;  particular random process.</property>
</doc>
