<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="RandomSource" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.RandomSource">
  <description>
A base class for sources of random numbers.&#10; It uses the class java.util.Random.&#10; This base class manages the seed. Specifically,&#10; the seed is a shared parameter, so setting the seed&#10; in any one instance of a RandomSource results in setting&#10; the seed in all instances. If the seed is set to value 0L,&#10; the default, then this is interpreted as not specifying a seed,&#10; and the random number generators are set to use a seed that&#10; depends on the current time in milliseconds. If the seed&#10; is set to any value other than 0L, then a seed is computed&#10; for the random number generator by adding that specified seed&#10; to the hashcode for the full name of the actor. This ensures&#10; that with high probability, multiple instances of RandomSource&#10; (and derived classes) will have distinct seeds, but that the&#10; executions are deterministically repeatable.&#10;&lt;p&gt;&#10; If the &lt;i&gt;resetOnEachRun&lt;/i&gt; parameter is true (it is&#10; false by default), then each run resets the random number&#10; generator. If the seed is non-zero, then this makes&#10; each run identical.  This is useful for constructing&#10; tests. If the seed is zero, then a new seed is generated&#10; on each run using the same technique described above&#10; (combining current time and the hash code).  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee, Steve Neuendorffer, Elaine Cheong</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 0.3</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Green (bilung)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.SharedParameter-->
    <property name="resetOnEachRun">If true, this parameter specifies that the random number&#10;  generator should be reset on each run of the model (in&#10;  the initialize() method). It is a boolean that defaults&#10;  to false. This is a shared parameter, meaning that changing&#10;  it somewhere in the model causes it to be changed everywhere&#10;  in the model.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.SharedParameter-->
    <property name="seed">The seed that controls the random number generation.&#10;  This is a shared parameter, meaning that all instances of&#10;  RandomSource or derived classes in the same model share the&#10;  same value.&#10;  A seed of zero is interpreted to mean that no seed is specified,&#10;  which means that each execution of the model could result in&#10;  distinct data. For the value 0, the seed is set to&#10;  System.currentTimeMillis() + hashCode(), which means that&#10;  with extremely high probability, two distinct actors will have&#10;  distinct seeds.  However, current time may not have enough&#10;  resolution to ensure that two subsequent executions of the&#10;  same model have distinct seeds. For a value other than zero,&#10;  the seed is set to that value plus the hashCode() of the&#10;  full name of the actor. This means that with high probability,&#10;  two distinct actors will have distinct, but repeatable seeds.&#10;&#10;  This parameter contains a LongToken, initially with value 0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="privateSeed">This private seed overrides the shared seed parameter to specify a&#10;  particular seed rather than using System.currentTimeMillis() or&#10;  hashCode() to compute the seed value.&#10;&#10;  By default, this parameter is empty, which means that the shared seed&#10;  parameter is used.&#10;&#10;  WARNING: It is up to the user to make sure that different seed&#10;  values are used in different random number generators.</property>
</doc>
