<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Reader" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.Reader">
  <description>
This actor reads tokens from an URL, and output them. Each entry in&#10; the file corresponds to one iteration. If there are multiple fires in&#10; the iteration, the same token will be repeated.  This actor has a&#10; multiport, where each port corresponds to one column in the data file.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; The file format at the URL is assumed as the following.  A newline&#10; character separates the rows, and a tab or a space character separates&#10; the columns.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; The &lt;i&gt;sourceURL&lt;/i&gt; parameter should be set to the name of the&#10; file, specified as a fully qualified URL.  If the &lt;i&gt;sourceURL&lt;/i&gt;&#10; parameter is an empty string, then the System.in is used for input.&#10;&#10; It is possible to load a file from the local file system by using the&#10; prefix &quot;file://&quot; instead of &quot;http://&quot;. Relative file paths are&#10; allowed. To specify a file relative to the current directory, use&#10; &quot;../&quot; or &quot;./&quot;. For example, if the current directory contains a file&#10; called &quot;test.txt&quot;, then &lt;i&gt;sourceURL&lt;/i&gt; should be set to&#10; &quot;file:./test.txt&quot;. If the parent directory contains a file called&#10; &quot;test.txt&quot;, then &lt;i&gt;sourceURL&lt;/i&gt; should be set to&#10; &quot;file:../test.txt&quot;. To reference the file test.txt, located at&#10; &quot;/tmp/test.txt&quot;, &lt;i&gt;sourceURL&lt;/i&gt; should be set to&#10; &quot;file:///tmp/test.txt&quot; The default value is &quot;file:///tmp/test.txt&quot;.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;FIXME: The type of the output ports is set to Double for now.&#10; It should read a line in the prefire() and refer the type&#10; from there.&#10; &lt;p&gt;FIXME: Reader should read in expressions and serialized tokens  </description>
  <author>Jie Liu</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (liuj)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (liuj)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="sourceURL">The URL of the file to read from. This parameter contains&#10;  a StringToken.  By default, it contains an empty string, which&#10;  is interpreted to mean that input should be directed to the&#10;  standard input.&#10;  FIXME: Should this bring up a dialog box to type (or select) a URL?</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="refresh">Refresh between each readings. Default is false.</property>
</doc>
