<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Source" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.Source">
  <description>
Base for simple data sources.  This provides an output&#10; port and a trigger input port, both exposed as public variables.&#10; The trigger port is a multiport with undeclared type, meaning that&#10; you can supply it with any data type.  The trigger port can also be&#10; left unconnected.  The purpose of the trigger input is to&#10; (optionally) supply events that cause the actor to fire.  If the&#10; port is connected to something, then this actor will check it&#10; for a token and return false from prefire() if there is no token.&#10; each channel of the trigger input, if any, and then discards the&#10; token.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Some derived classes may attach additional significance to an input&#10; on the trigger port. For example, they might fix the type and attach&#10; some significance to the value.  Note that it is not recommend to&#10; use getWidth() on the port to determine whether the port is connected,&#10; since the width may be greater than zero even if there&#10; is no actual source of data.  This can occur, for example, if a trigger port&#10; is connected to the inside of a port of an opaque composite actor, and&#10; there is nothing connected to the outside of that port. It is not&#10; recommended to make the behavior of an actor dependent on a global&#10; property such as whether there is ultimately a source of data.&lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Any type of data on is accepted on the trigger port, therefore no&#10; type is declared. Instead, the type resolution algorithm finds&#10; the least fixed point. If backward type inference is enabled, and&#10; no type has been declared for the trigger, it is constrained to be&#10; equal to &lt;code&gt;BaseType.GENERAL&lt;/code&gt;. This will result in upstream&#10; ports resolving to the most general type rather than the most specific.&#10; &lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 0.3</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Green (bilung)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">The output port.  The type of this port is unspecified.&#10;  Derived classes may set it.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="trigger">The trigger port.  The type of this port is undeclared, meaning&#10;  that it will resolve to any data type.</port>
</doc>
