<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="FixSequence" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.vhdl.FixSequence">
  <description>
This actor produces a sequence of values, optionally periodically repeating&#10; them. The &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; parameter contains an ArrayToken that specifies the&#10; sequence of values to produce at the output. If the &lt;i&gt;enable&lt;/i&gt; input&#10; port is connected, then it provides a boolean sequence that specifies&#10; whether to produce an output. If the &lt;i&gt;enable&lt;/i&gt; is present and&#10; true, then the actor will produce the next output. Otherwise, it&#10; produces no output.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; Compared with the &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/Pulse.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.lib.Pulse&lt;/a&gt; actor, this&#10; actor can be enabled or disabled on each firing by providing a true&#10; or false input on the &lt;i&gt;enable&lt;/i&gt; port.  </description>
  <author>Terry Esther Filiba, based on Pulse by Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 4.1</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="enable">The enable input port.  If this port is connected, then its&#10;  input will determine whether an output is produced in any&#10;  given firing. The type is boolean.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="trigger">The trigger port.  The type of this port is undeclared, meaning&#10;  that it will resolve to any data type.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="repeat">The flag that indicates whether the sequence needs to be&#10;  repeated. If this is false, then the last value of the&#10;  sequence is repeatedly produced after the entire sequence&#10;  has been produced. This is a boolean, and defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="values">The values that will be produced on the output.&#10;  This parameter is an array, with default value {1}.</property>
</doc>
