<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="RaisedCosine" class="ptolemy.domains.sdf.lib.RaisedCosine">
  <description>
This actor implements an FIR filter with&#10; a raised cosine or square-root raised cosine frequency response.&#10; The excess bandwidth is given&#10; by &lt;i&gt;excessBW&lt;/i&gt; and the symbol interval (in number of samples)&#10; by &lt;i&gt;interpolation&lt;/i&gt; (which by default is 16).&#10; The length of the filter (the number of taps) is given by &lt;i&gt;length&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; For the ordinary raised cosine response,&#10; the impulse response of the filter would ideally be&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10;        sin(pi n/T)   cos(alpha pi n/T)&#10; h(n) = ----------- * -----------------&#10;          pi n/T      1-(2 alpha n/T)&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; where &lt;i&gt;alpha&lt;/i&gt; is &lt;i&gt;excessBW&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T&lt;/i&gt; is the&#10; &lt;i&gt;interpolation&lt;/i&gt; factor.&#10; However, this pulse is centered at zero, and we can only implement causal&#10; filters in the SDF domain in Ptolemy.  Hence, the impulse response is&#10; actually&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10; g(n) = h(n - M)&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; where &lt;i&gt;M&lt;/i&gt; = &lt;i&gt;length/&lt;/i&gt;2 if &lt;i&gt;length&lt;/i&gt; is even, and &lt;i&gt;M&#10; &lt;/i&gt;= (&lt;i&gt;length+&lt;/i&gt;1)&lt;i&gt;/&lt;/i&gt;2 if &lt;i&gt;length&lt;/i&gt; is odd.&#10; The impulse response is simply truncated outside this range, so&#10; the impulse response will generally not be symmetric if &lt;i&gt;length&lt;/i&gt; is even&#10; because it will have one more sample to the left than to the right of center.&#10; Unless this extra sample is zero, the filter will not have linear phase&#10; if &lt;i&gt;length&lt;/i&gt; is even.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; For the ordinary raised cosine response, the&#10; distance (in number of samples) from the center&#10; to the first zero crossing is given by &lt;i&gt;symbolInterval&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; For the square-root raised cosine response, a cascade of two identical&#10; square-root raised cosine filters would be equivalent to a single&#10; ordinary raised cosine filter.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The impulse response of the square-root raised cosine pulse is given by&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10;         4 alpha(cos((1+alpha)pi n/T)+Tsin((1-alpha)pi n/T)/(4n alpha/T))&#10; h(n) = -----------------------------------------------------------------&#10;                      pi sqrt(T)(1-(4 alpha n/T)&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;)&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; This impulse response convolved with itself will, in principle, be equal&#10; to a raised cosine pulse.  However, because of the abrupt rectangular&#10; windowing of the pulse, with low excess bandwidth, this ideal is not&#10; closely approximated except for very long filters.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The output sample rate is &lt;i&gt;interpolation&lt;/i&gt; times the input.&#10; This is set by default to 16 because in digital communication systems&#10; this pulse is used for the line coding of symbols, and upsampling is necessary.&#10; Typically, the value of &lt;i&gt;interpolation&lt;/i&gt; is the same as that of&#10; &lt;i&gt;symbolInterval&lt;/i&gt;, at least when the filter is being used&#10; as a transmit pulse shaper.&#10; &lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;[1]&#10; E. A. Lee and D. G. Messerschmitt,&#10; &lt;i&gt;Digital Communication,&lt;/i&gt; Kluwer Academic Publishers, Boston, 1988.&#10; &lt;p&gt;[2]&#10; I. Korn, &lt;i&gt;Digital Communications&lt;/i&gt;, Van Nostrand Reinhold, New York, 1985.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 0.2</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (neuendor)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (neuendor)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="excessBW">The excess bandwidth.  This contains a&#10;  DoubleToken, and by default it has value 1.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="length">The length of the pulse.  This contains an&#10;  IntToken, and by default it has value 64.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="root">If true, use the square root of the raised cosine instead of the&#10;  raised cosine.  This contains a&#10;  BooleanToken, and by default it has value false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="symbolInterval">The symbol interval, which is the number of samples to the first&#10;  zero crossing on each side of the main lobe.  Its value is an&#10;  IntToken, and by default it has value 16.</property>
</doc>
