<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Effigy" class="ptolemy.actor.gui.Effigy">
  <description>
An effigy represents model metadata, and is contained by the&#10; model directory or by another effigy. The effigy, for example,&#10; keeps track of where the model originated (from a URI or file)&#10; and whether the model has been modified since the URI or file was&#10; read. In design automation, such information is often called&#10; &quot;metadata.&quot; When we began to design this class, we called it&#10; ModelModel, because it was a model of a Ptolemy II model.&#10; However, this name seemed awkward, so we changed it to Effigy.&#10; We also considered the name Proxy for the class. We rejected that&#10; name because of the common use of the word &quot;proxy&quot; in distributed&#10; object-oriented models.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The Effigy class extends CompositeEntity, so an instance of Effigy&#10; can contain entities.  By convention, an effigy contains all&#10; open instances of Tableau associated with the model. It also&#10; contains a string attribute named &quot;identifier&quot; with a value that&#10; uniquely identifies the model. A typical choice (which depends on&#10; the configuration) is the canonical URI for a MoML file that&#10; describes the model.  In the case of an effigy contained by another,&#10; a typical choice is the URI of the parent effigy, a pound sign &quot;#&quot;,&#10; and a name.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; An effigy may contain other effigies.  The master effigy&#10; in such a containment hierarchy is typically associated with a&#10; URI or file.&#10; Contained effigies are associated with the same file, and represent&#10; structured data within the top-level representation in the file.&#10; The masterEffigy() method returns that master effigy.&#10; The topEffigy() method in this base class returns the same&#10; master effigy. However, in derived classes, a master effigy&#10; may be contained by another effigy, so the top effigy is not&#10; the same as the master effigy. The top effigy is directly contained&#10; by the ModelDirectory in the Configuration.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; NOTE: It might seem more natural for the identifier to match the name&#10; of the effigy rather than recording the identifier in a string attribute.&#10; But in Ptolemy II, an entity name cannot have periods in it, and a URI&#10; typically does have periods in it.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; To determine the Effigy of a NamedObj, use&#10; &lt;a href=&quot;../../../ptolemy/actor/gui/Configuration.html#findEffigy&quot;&gt;findEffigy(NamedObj)&lt;/a&gt;.  </description>
  <author>Steve Neuendorffer and Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (celaine)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute-->
    <property name="identifier">The identifier for the effigy.  The default value is &quot;Unnamed&quot;.</property>
</doc>
