<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="SoundPlayer" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.javasound.SoundPlayer">
  <description>
This actor plays audio samples provided on the input port.&#10; The audio samples that are supplied to&#10; this actor should be doubles in the range -1.0 to 1.0, provided&#10; as a DoubleMatrix, where the first index of the matrix represents&#10; the channel and the second index is the sample number. That is,&#10; each row is a sequence of samples for the channel corresponding&#10; to the row number. Any input&#10; value that is outside of the valid range will be hard-clipped&#10; to fall within the range [-1.0, 1.0] before it is written&#10; to the audio output port of the computer.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;The parameters are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;ul&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;sampleRate&lt;/i&gt; should be set to desired sample rate, in Hz.&#10; The default value is 8000. Allowable values are 8000, 11025, 22050,&#10; 44100, and 48000 Hz.&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;bytesPerSample&lt;/i&gt; gives the resolution of audio samples.&#10; This is an integer that defaults to 2, meaning 16-bit samples.&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;channels&lt;/i&gt; should be set to desired number of audio&#10; channels. Allowable values are 1 (for mono) and 2 (for stereo).  The&#10; default value is 1. Some sound cards support more than two audio&#10; channels, but this is not supported in Java. FIXME: If this&#10; differs from the input dimensions?&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;transferSize&lt;/i&gt; The number of samples that will be&#10; transferred to the audio driver together.  This is an integer with&#10; default 128.&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;sampleRate&lt;/i&gt; The requested buffer size in the audio&#10; hardware. This affects how far ahead of real time the model can&#10; get. There is no harm in making this large because this actor will&#10; overwrite previously queued values if necessary. This is an integer&#10; that defaults to 8000, representing a buffer with 8000 samples per&#10; channel. At an 8 kHz sample rate, this corresponds to one second of&#10; sound.&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;/ul&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; All of these parameters are shared by all audio actors that use&#10; the audio hardware, so changing them in one of those actors will&#10; cause it to change in all.&lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 6.1</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (eal)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="input">The input port.  This port must receive double matrix tokens (in the&#10;  range of -1.0 to 1.0).</port>
</doc>
