<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="SmoothSignal" class="ptolemy.domains.qss.lib.SmoothSignal">
  <description>
Given inputs that are either doubles or &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/data/SmoothToken.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.data.SmoothToken&lt;/a&gt;s, construct&#10; a SmoothToken output. If all the inputs are doubles, then channel 0&#10; specifies the value of the output, channel 1 specifies the first&#10; derivative, channel 2 specifies the second derivative, etc.&#10; If any channel is missing an input, then the most recently received&#10; input on that channel is used.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; If any of the inputs is a SmoothToken, then in addition to&#10; their values specifying the value and derivatives of the output,&#10; their derivatives will be used as the derivatives of the output.&#10; For example, if channel zero has a smoothToken(1.0, {1.0, 2.0})&#10; and channel one has a smoothToken(2.0, {3.0}), then the output&#10; will be a smoothToken(1.0, {2.0, 3.0}).&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#10; The inputs need not arrive all at once. Each time an input arrives,&#10; the value of the input is interpreted as an &lt;i&gt;update&lt;/i&gt; to the&#10; output value or one of the derivatives. Any previously arrived&#10; input tokens that are instances of SmoothToken are extrapolated&#10; before being used to update the output.  So for example, if this&#10; actor receives only an event on channel 0 at time 0 with value&#10; smoothToken(1.0, {1.0}), then it will produce an output with&#10; value smoothToken(1.0, {1.0}) at time 0. If then at time 1 it&#10; receives only an event on channel 1 with value smoothToken(-1.0, {1.0}),&#10; then it will first extrapolate the event it previously received&#10; on channel 0, to value smoothToken(2.0, {1.0}), and then combine&#10; it with the update on channel 1 to yield&#10; smoothToken(2.0, {-1.0, 1.0}). The new token updates the first&#10; derivative to -1.0, overwriting the previously specified first&#10; derivative of 1.0. The new token also provides a second derivative 1.0.&#10; Any derivatives provided by higher numbered channels will overwrite&#10; derivatives provided by lower numbered channels.&#10; &lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 11.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (eal)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
</doc>
