<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="DDEDirector" class="ptolemy.domains.dde.kernel.DDEDirector">
  <description>
A DDEDirector governs the execution of actors operating according to the DDE&#10; model of computation (MoC). The DDE MoC incorporates a distributed notion of&#10; time into a dataflow style communication semantic. Blocking reads occur if&#10; attempts to consume data are made when the corresponding receiver is empty&#10; and blocking writes occur if attempts to produce data are made when the&#10; corresponding receiver is full.&#10; &lt;P&gt;&#10; In conjunction with the blocking read/write facilities, the DDE domain uses a&#10; distributed, local notion of time. In a network of actors governed by a&#10; DDEDirector each actor has a local notion of time. Several features of the&#10; DDEDirector are intended to facilitate these local notions of time.&#10; &lt;P&gt;&#10; All DDE models have a completion time. The completion time is a preset time&#10; after which all execution ceases. The completion time for a DDEDirector is&#10; specified via the &lt;I&gt;stopTime&lt;/I&gt; parameter. The value of the stopTime&#10; parameter is passed to the receivers of all actors that the DDEDirector&#10; governs via newReceiver() during initialize(). After initialize() has been&#10; called, the value of stopTime can not be changed.&#10; &lt;P&gt;&#10; The default value of the stopTime parameter is&#10; PrioritizedTimedQueue.ETERNITY. Given this value, a DDE model will continue&#10; executing without regard for a completion time.&#10; &lt;P&gt;&#10; Deadlock due to feedback loops is dealt with via NullTokens. When an actor in&#10; a DDE model receives a NullToken, it may advance its local time value even&#10; though no computation results directly from consumption of the NullToken. For&#10; models with feedback topologies, the FeedBackDelay actor should be used in&#10; the feedback loop.&#10; &lt;P&gt;&#10; The DDE model of computation assumes that valid time stamps have non-negative&#10; values. Three special purpose negative time values are reserved with the&#10; following meanings. The value of PrioritizedTimedQueue.INACTIVE is reserved&#10; to indicate the termination of a receiver. The value of&#10; PrioritizedTimedQueue.ETERNITY is reserved to indicate that a receiver has&#10; not begun to participate in a model's execution. The value of&#10; PrioritizedTimedQueue.IGNORE is reserved to indicate that the current token&#10; at the head of a DDEReceiver should be ignored in favor of the tokens&#10; contained in the other receivers of the actor in question. More details of&#10; IGNORE can be found in FeedBackDelay.&#10; &lt;P&gt;&#10; NOTE: The current implementation of this director does not include an&#10; infrastructure for mutations. Hence, ChangeRequest and other facilities for&#10; changing the topology of a model are not included in this director.  </description>
  <author>John S. Davis II, Mudit Goel</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 0.3</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (davisj)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
</doc>
