<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="CADirector" class="ptolemy.domains.ca.kernel.CADirector">
  <description>
A Cellular Automata director.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The CADirector is to be used in conjunction with the CA2DConvolution Actor. To use&#10; this director, it is highly recommended to start with one of the examples.&#10; The director contains a matrix. At each iteration, every entry in the matrix&#10; is updated according to the CA2DConvolution actor. This functionality can be useful when&#10; simulating cellular automata or other grid-based phenomena.&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This director assumes the following parameters are added to the canvas:&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;xLocation&lt;/i&gt;: the xLocation in the grid (the 2D matrix) that is&#10; currently being updated.&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;yLocation&lt;/i&gt;: the yLocation in the grid (the 2D matrix) that is&#10; currently being updated.&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;currentValue&lt;/i&gt;: the currentValue in the grid at location (xLocation,&#10; yLocation).&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;newValue&lt;/i&gt;: the updated value in the grid at location (xLocation,&#10; yLocation).&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;neighbor1&lt;/i&gt;: the value of the top-left neighbor of grid location&#10; (xLocation, yLocation).&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;neighbor2&lt;/i&gt;: the value of the top neighbor of grid location&#10; (xLocation, yLocation).&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;neighbor3&lt;/i&gt;: the value of the top-right neighbor of grid location&#10; (xLocation, yLocation).&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;neighbor4&lt;/i&gt;: the value of the left neighbor of grid location&#10; (xLocation, yLocation).&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;neighbor5&lt;/i&gt;: the value of the right neighbor of grid location&#10; (xLocation, yLocation).&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;neighbor6&lt;/i&gt;: the value of the bottom-left neighbor of grid location&#10; (xLocation, yLocation).&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;neighbor7&lt;/i&gt;: the value of the bottom neighbor of grid location&#10; (xLocation, yLocation).&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;i&gt;neighbor8&lt;/i&gt;: the value of the bottom-right neighbor of grid location&#10; (xLocation, yLocation).&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The director sets the variables for each entry in the matrix every iteration.&#10; The number of high-level &lt;i&gt;iterations&lt;/i&gt; (that scan the entire matrix once)&#10; can be set as a parameter in the director. Other parameters include:&#10; &lt;i&gt;delay&lt;/i&gt;, the time delay between iterations; &lt;i&gt;randomize matrix&lt;/i&gt;,&#10; which determines if the matrix will be populated randomly; &lt;i&gt;matrix size&lt;/i&gt;,&#10; the dimension of the square matrix; and &lt;i&gt;initial values&lt;/i&gt;, the initial&#10; values of the matrix with all values not explicitly defined set to 0.0.&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; See also the documentation on the &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/domains/ca/lib/CA2DConvolution.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.domains.ca.lib.CA2DConvolution&lt;/a&gt; actor&#10; and the &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/domains/ca/lib/gui/CAViewer.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.domains.ca.lib.gui.CAViewer&lt;/a&gt; actor.&#10; &lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Zach Ezzell, Contributor: Christopher Brooks</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="delay">The delay time between iterations in seconds.  The initial default&#10;  value is a double with value 0.5, indicating a delay of half a second&#10;  between iterations.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="initialMatrix">The initial matrix parameter.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="iterations">The iterations parameter.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="random">True if the matrix will be populated with random data.  The default&#10;  value is false, indicating that all values in the matrix will be&#10;  initially set to 0.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="size">An integer representing the size of the square matrix.  The initial&#10; value is 10, indicating a 10 x 10 matrix.</property>
</doc>
