<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="FeedBackDelay" class="ptolemy.domains.dde.kernel.FeedBackDelay">
  <description>
FeedBackDelay actors are used to add delay to feedback topologies.&#10; If a FeedBackDelay actor consumes a token (real or Null), it has the&#10; option of producing an equivalent token on the output with an&#10; incremented time stamp value. Alternatively, the FeedBackDelay actor&#10; will simply produce the token without altering the time stamp.&#10; &lt;P&gt;&#10; Two parameters - &lt;I&gt;nullDelay&lt;/I&gt; and &lt;I&gt;realDelay&lt;/I&gt; - are&#10; available for determining whether an FeedBackDelay actor&#10; increments the time stamp of produced output tokens. The default&#10; value of nullDelay (realDelay) is true (false). If the nullDelay&#10; (realDelay) parameter is set to true, then the time stamps of&#10; NullTokens (real tokens) will be incremented as they pass through&#10; this actor.&#10; &lt;P&gt;&#10; The delay value that is applied (given that one of the above&#10; parameters is true) is determined by the setDelay() and getDelay()&#10; methods. More elaborate delay values can be made available by&#10; overriding the getDelay() method in derived classes.&#10; &lt;P&gt;&#10; FeedBackDelay actors are effective for preventing Zeno conditions&#10; involving cycles of null tokens. If a DDE model has a feedback&#10; topology, a FeedBackDelay actor should be added into the feedback loop.&#10; &lt;P&gt;&#10; The delay value of a FeedBackDelay actor must be wisely chosen. The&#10; delay value should be smaller than any other successive time stamp&#10; increment found in a given DDE model. This means that if a particular&#10; model might have any two time stamps with time difference delta, then&#10; the delay value should be smaller than delta.  </description>
  <author>John S. Davis II</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 0.4</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (davisj)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (yuhong)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="input">The input port.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">The output port.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="delay">The delay for this actor.  The initial default value is a double&#10;  with value 1.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="nullDelay">The boolean parameter that indicates whether a delay value&#10;  will be added to the time stamp of null tokens that are&#10;  produced by this actor. This parameter defaults to true.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="realDelay">The boolean parameter that indicates whether a delay value&#10;  will be added to the time stamp of real tokens that are&#10;  produced by this actor. This parameter defaults to false.</property>
</doc>
