<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="PtidesPort" class="ptolemy.domains.ptides.lib.PtidesPort">
  <description>
A specialized port for Ptides platform I/O implementing&#10;  functionality for sensors, actuators and network receiver and&#10;  transmitter ports.&#10;&#10;  When creating a port in vergil, a sensor or actuator port is&#10;  created. To create a network port, the parameter &lt;i&gt;&#10;  isNetworkPort&lt;/i&gt; is changed. Upon changing the type of the port,&#10;  the icon is changed as well.&#10;&#10;  PtidesPorts are configured by parameters where some parameters&#10;  are the same for all types of ports and others are specific&#10;  to the type. Every PtidesPort can be configured with a&#10;  deviceDelay and a deviceDelayBound. The deviceDelay is the amount&#10;  of platform time passing between the port receiving the event and&#10;  the platform time the event is put on the event queue (for input&#10;  ports) or the time the event is released to the environment (for&#10;  output ports).  The deviceDelayBound is the maximum of this value&#10;  and it is used in the safe-to-process analysis.&#10;&#10;  Actuators additionally have a parameter actuateAtEventTimestamp&#10;  which is used to specify whether the actuator can output events&#10;  before the event timestamp or only at the event timestamp.&#10;&#10;  A network transmitter has a parameter platformDelayBound&#10;  which is configured to represent the maximum difference between&#10;  platform time and the event timestamp if platform time is&#10;  ahead of the event timestamp. This is used for the safe-to-process&#10;  analysis.&#10;&#10;  A network receiver has a parameter sourcePlatformDelayBound&#10;  which can be used to match the parameter platformDelayBound&#10;  on the sending platform. Again, this parameter is used for&#10;  the safe-to-process analysis.&#10;&#10;  Network receivers have an additional parameter networkDelayBound&#10;  which describes the maximum physical time input events spent on&#10;  the network after being sent by the another PtidesPlatform.  </description>
  <author>Patricia Derler</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (derler)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating></Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="actuateAtEventTimestamp">Actuate at event timestamp parameter that defaults to the boolean value TRUE.&#10;  If this parameter is set to FALSE, an actuator can produce outputs as soon&#10;  as they are available.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="deviceDelay">Device delay parameter that defaults to the double value 0.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="deviceDelayBound">Device delay bound parameter that defaults to the double value 0.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="isNetworkPort">Flag that is true if the port is a network receiver or transmitter.&#10;  The flag defaults to false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="networkDelayBound">An assumed upper bound on the network delay, used if this is a network&#10;  receiver port (&lt;i&gt;isNetworkPort&lt;/i&gt; is true and the port is an input).&#10;  If the actual network delay exceeds this assumed value, then an exception&#10;  may result if actual received time of the input is too late to ensure that&#10;  DE semantics is respected.&#10;  This is a double that defaults to 0.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="platformDelayBound">An assumed upper bound on the difference between platform time and&#10;  the event timestamp sent to a network transmitter port&#10;  (&lt;i&gt;isNetworkPort&lt;/i&gt; is true and the port is an output),&#10;  where platform time is smaller than the event timestamp.&#10;  If the platform time plus the platformDelayBound&#10;  is smaller than the event timestamp, an exception is thrown.&#10;  This parameter is used in cases where the execution time is larger than&#10;  the logical time delays on the platform to indicate that the designer&#10;  knows that the execution time is bigger than the time delay on the&#10;  platform.&#10;  This is a double that defaults to 0.0. In that case, an exception&#10;  is thrown when platform time is smaller than the event timestamp.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="sourcePlatformDelayBound">An assumed upper bound on the difference between platform time and&#10;  the event timestamp received at a network receiver port&#10;  (&lt;i&gt;isNetworkPort&lt;/i&gt; is true and the port is an output),&#10;  where platform time is smaller than the event timestamp.&#10;  &lt;p&gt;This is used to indicate that the designer knows that the execution&#10;  time on the sending platform is bigger than the time delay on the&#10;  sending platform.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;Together with the networkDelayBound and the&#10;  clockSychronizationErrorBound parameters, this parameter is&#10;  used to determine whether an event is arriving at a network&#10;  receiver too late.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;The value specified for the platformDelayBound on a network transmitter&#10;  and the value specified for the sourcePlatformDelayBound on a network&#10;  receiver should ideally match, however, this is not enforced.&#10;  This is a double that defaults to 0.0.&lt;/p&gt;</property>
</doc>
