<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="ParticleFilterRange" class="org.ptolemy.machineLearning.particleFilter.ParticleFilterRange">
  <description>
A Particle Filter Implementation for Range-only measurement models.&#10;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;The particle filter runs on a state space model given by&#10;&lt;pre&gt;&#10;X_{t+1} = f(X_t, U_t, t)&#10;Y_{t} = g(X_t, U_t, t)&#10;X(0) = X0&#10;&lt;/pre&gt;&#10;where X is the state vector, U is the input vector, Y is the observation&#10;vector, and t is the model time. To use this actor :&#10;&lt;ul&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt; For each input in &lt;i&gt;U&lt;/i&gt;, create an input port with an arbitrary name.&#10;This actor will automatically create a parameter with the same name as the&#10;input port. That parameter will have its value set during execution to match&#10;the value of the input.&#10;&#10;&lt;li&gt; Fill in the &lt;i&gt;stateVariableNames&lt;/i&gt; parameter, which is&#10;an array of strings, with the names of the state variables in &lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt;.&#10;These names can be arbitrary, since you will refer them to&#10;by name rather than by the symbol &lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt;.&#10;&#10;&lt;li&gt; For each state variable name in &lt;i&gt;stateVariableNames&lt;/i&gt;,&#10;create a parameter with a value equal to the initial value of that&#10;particular state variable.&#10;&#10;&lt;li&gt; Specify an update function (part of &lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt; above) for each&#10;state variable by creating a parameter named &lt;i&gt;name&lt;/i&gt;_update, where&#10;&lt;i&gt;name&lt;/i&gt; is the name of the state variable. The value of this&#10;parameter should be an expression giving the rate of change of&#10;this state variable as a function of any of the state variables,&#10;any input, any other actor parameter, and (possibly), the variable&#10;&lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt;, representing current time.&#10;&#10;&lt;li&gt; For each output in &lt;i&gt;y&lt;/i&gt;, create an output port.&#10;The output may have any name. This actor will automatically&#10;create a parameter with the same name as the output port.&#10;&#10;&lt;li&gt; For each parameter matching an output port, set its&#10;value to be an expression giving the output&#10;value as a function of the state variables, the inputs, any other&#10;actor parameter, and (possibly), the variable&#10;&lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt;, representing current time.&#10;&#10;&lt;/ul&gt;&#10;&#10;&#10;The preinitialize() method of this actor is based on the ptolemy.domain.ct.lib.DifferentialSystem&#10;actor by Jie Liu.  </description>
  <author>Ilge Akkaya</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (ilgea)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (ilgea)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="z_m">Incoming measurements.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="z">Observation expression.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="x_update">x component update equation.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="y_update">y component update equation.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.parameters.PortParameter-->
    <property name="observerPosition">Position of the observer.</property>
</doc>
