<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="EditorIcon" class="ptolemy.vergil.icon.EditorIcon">
  <description>
An icon is the visual representation of an entity or attribute.&#10; The visual representation is a Diva Figure. This class is an attribute&#10; that serves as a factory for such figures. This base class creates the&#10; figure by composing the figures of any contained attributes that have&#10; icons.  If there are no such contained attributes, then it creates a&#10; default figure that is a white rectangle. This class also provides&#10; a facility for generating a Swing icon (i.e. an instance of&#10; javax.swing.Icon) from that figure (the createIcon() method).&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The icon consists of a background figure, created by the&#10; createBackgroundFigure() method, and a decorated version, created&#10; by the createFigure() method.  The decorated version has, in this&#10; base class, a label showing the name of the entity, unless the entity&#10; contains a parameter called &quot;_hideName&quot; with value true.&#10; The swing icon created by createIcon() does not include the&#10; decorations, but rather is only the background figure.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The decorated version can also optionally show parameter values&#10; below the icon.  If the preference named &quot;_showParameters&quot;&#10; has value &quot;All&quot;, then all parameters are shown. If it has&#10; value &quot;Overridden parameters only&quot;, then it will show&#10; only overridden parameters. In either case, only&#10; parameters that are visible and settable (see the Settable&#10; interface) will be shown, regardless of whether they are overridden.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; When the preference &quot;_showParameters&quot; has value&#10; &quot;Overridden parameters only&quot;, then some parameter values&#10; may be suppressed even if they are overridden. In particular,&#10; if an attribute contains a parameter named &quot;_hide&quot; with value&#10; true, then that parameter is not shown even if requested.&#10; If the container of the attribute contains a parameter named&#10; &quot;_hideAllParameters&quot; with value true, then none of its&#10; parameters are shown.&#10; This is useful, for example, if the icon itself shows&#10; the parameter, as with decorative visual elements.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Derived classes may simply populate this attribute with other&#10; visible attributes (attributes that contain icons), or they can&#10; override the createBackgroundFigure() method.  This will affect&#10; both the Diva Figure and the Swing Icon representations.&#10; Derived classes can also create the figure or the icon in a&#10; different way entirely (for example, starting with a Swing&#10; icon and creating the figure using a SwingWrapper) by overriding&#10; both createBackgroundFigure() and createIcon(). However, the&#10; icon editor provided by EditIconFrame and EditIconTableau&#10; will only show (and allow editing) of those icon components&#10; created by populating this attribute with other visible&#10; attributes.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This attribute contains another attribute that is an&#10; instance of EditIconTableau. This has the effect that&#10; an instance of Configuration, when it attempts to open&#10; an instance of this class, will use EditIconTableau,&#10; which in turn uses EditIconFrame to provide an icon&#10; editor.  </description>
  <author>Steve Neuendorffer, John Reekie, Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 2.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (neuendor)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (johnr)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
</doc>
