<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="AudioCapture" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.javasound.AudioCapture">
  <description>
This actor sequentially outputs audio samples that are captured&#10; from the audio input port of the computer. The audio input port&#10; typically corresponds to either the microphone input, line-in,&#10; or cd audio from the cdrom or dvd drive. It is not possible to&#10; select the desired input port under Java. This must be done from&#10; the operating system. This actor should be fired often enough to&#10; prevent overflow of the internal audio capture buffer.&#10; Overflow should be avoided, since it will result in loss of&#10; data. Each captured audio sample is converted to a double that&#10; may range from -1.0 to 1.0. Thus, the output type of this actor&#10; is DoubleToken.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The following parameters should be set accordingly. In all cases,&#10; an exception is thrown if an illegal parameter value is used.&#10; Note that these parameters may be changed while audio playback&#10; is active. If this actor is used in conjunction with an&#10; AudioPlayer actor, changing a parameter will cause the corresponding&#10; parameter value of the AudioPlayer to automatically be set to the&#10; same value. This behavior is required because the AudioCapture and&#10; AudioPlayer actors both share access to the audio hardware, which&#10; is associated with a single sample rate, bit resolution, and&#10; number of channels.&#10; &lt;ul&gt;&#10; &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;sampleRate&lt;/i&gt; should be set to the desired sample rate, in Hz.&#10; The default value is 8000. Allowable values are 8000, 11025,&#10; 22050, 44100, and 48000 Hz. Note that Java does not support&#10; 96000 Hz operation, even if the audio hardware supports it.&#10; &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;bitsPerSample&lt;/i&gt; should be set to the desired bit&#10; resolution. The default value is 16. Allowable values are 8 and 16.&#10; Note that Java does not support 20 or 24 bit audio, even if the&#10; audio hardware supports it.&#10; &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;channels&lt;/i&gt; should be set to desired number of audio&#10; channels. The default value is 1 (for mono audio). Allowable&#10; values are 1 and 2 (for stereo). Note that more than two&#10; channels of audio is not currently supported in Java, even if&#10; the audio hardware supports it.&#10; &lt;/ul&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; It should be noted that at most one AudioCapture and one AudioPlayer&#10; actor may be used simultaneously. Otherwise, an exception will&#10; occur. This restriction may be lifted in a future version of&#10; this actor.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; There are security issues involved with accessing files and audio&#10; resources in applets. Applets are not&#10; allowed to capture audio from the audio input port (e.g., the&#10; microphone) by default since this could present a security risk.&#10; Therefore, the actor will not run in an applet by default. The&#10; .java.policy file may be modified to grant applets more&#10; privileges.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Note: Requires Java 2 v1.3.0 or later.  </description>
  <author>Brian K. Vogel, Christopher Hylands, Steve Neuendorffer</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (vogel)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (chf)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="trigger">The trigger port.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">The output port.  This will always produce double data,&#10; between -1.0 and 1.0.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="output_tokenProductionRate">The output rate.</property>
</doc>
