<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="AudioReader" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.javasound.AudioReader">
  <description>
This actor outputs samples from a sound file as doubles in&#10; the range [-1.0, 1.0]. If the file has multiple channels of&#10; output data, then the separate channels are sent on successive&#10; output channels.  If the output has more channels than there&#10; are channels in the audio file, then nothing will be send&#10; on the output channels where there is no corresponding&#10; output data.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The &lt;i&gt;fileOrURL&lt;/i&gt; parameter should be set to the name of the file&#10; or a URL, in any form accepted by FileParameter. The default initial value is&#10; &lt;code&gt;$CLASSPATH/ptolemy/actor/lib/javasound/voice.wav&lt;/code&gt;,&#10; which refers to a file that is found relative to the classpath.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Supported file formats are  WAV, AU, and AIFF. The sound&#10; file format is determined from the file extension.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; When the end of the file is reached, postfire() return false, which&#10; in some domains will cause the model to stop executing (e.g. SDF),&#10; and in some will prevent further firings of this actor (e.g. DE).&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; There are security issues involved with accessing files and audio&#10; resources in applets. Applets are only allowed access to files&#10; specified by a URL and located on the machine from which the&#10; applet is loaded. The .java.policy file may be modified to grant&#10; applets more privileges.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Note: Requires Java 2 v1.3.0 or later.  </description>
  <author>Brian K. Vogel, Christopher Hylands, Edward A. Lee, Steve Neuendorffer</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (chf)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.FileParameter-->
    <property name="fileOrURL">The file name or URL from which to read.  This is a string with&#10;  any form accepted by FileParameter.</property>
</doc>
