<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="AudioPlayer" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.javasound.AudioPlayer">
  <description>
This actor reads audio samples and plays them.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;Specifically, the input stream that this actor reads is&#10; interpreted as consisting of audio samples. This actor writes this&#10; stream of audio samples to the audio output port of the computer,&#10; which typically consists of the computer speaker or the headphones&#10; output. The audio samples that are supplied to this actor should be&#10; doubles in the range [-1.0, 1.0]. Thus, the input port of this actor&#10; is of type DoubleToken. Any input tokens that are outside of the&#10; valid range will be hard-clipped to fall within the range [-1.0, 1.0]&#10; before they are written to the audio output port of the computer.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;This actor should be fired often enough to prevent underflow of&#10; the internal audio playback buffer. Underflow should be avoided,&#10; since it will result in audio discontinuities (heard as clicks)&#10; in the output. No exception will be thrown if underflow occurs.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;The following parameters should be set accordingly. In all cases,&#10; an exception is thrown if an illegal parameter value is used.  Note&#10; that these parameters may be changed while audio capture is&#10; active. If this actor is used in conjunction with an AudioCapture&#10; actor, changing a parameter of this actor will cause the&#10; corresponding parameter value of the AudioCapture actor to&#10; automatically be set to the same value. This behavior is required&#10; because the AudioCapture and AudioPlayer actors both share access to&#10; the audio hardware, which is associated with a single sample rate,&#10; bit resolution, and number of channels.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;ul&gt;&#10; &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;sampleRate&lt;/i&gt; should be set to desired sample rate, in Hz.&#10; The default value is 8000. Allowable values are 8000, 11025,&#10; 22050, 44100, and 48000 Hz. Some sound cards support 96000 Hz&#10; operation, but this is not supported in Java.&lt;/li&gt;&#10; &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;bitsPerSample&lt;/i&gt; should be set to desired bit&#10; resolution. The default value is 16. Allowable values are 8 and 16.&#10; Some sound cards support 20 and 24 bit audio, but this is not&#10; supported in Java.&lt;/li&gt;&#10; &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;channels&lt;/i&gt; should be set to desired number of audio&#10; channels. Allowable values are 1 (for mono) and 2 (for stereo).&#10; The default value is 1. Some sound cards support more than two&#10; audio channels, but this is not supported in Java.&lt;/li&gt;&#10; &lt;/ul&gt;&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; If more than one AudioPlayer actor is used in model, the sounds&#10; produced by these actors will be interleaved. This may make sense,&#10; for example, if the actor is used in a ModalModel.&lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Brian K. Vogel, Steve Neuendorffer</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (neuendor)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (chf)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="input">The input port.  This port must receive double tokens (in the&#10; range of -1.0 to 1.0);</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="input_tokenConsumptionRate">The input rate.</property>
</doc>
