<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Inhibit" class="ptolemy.domains.de.lib.Inhibit">
  <description>
Output a received input token, unless the &lt;i&gt;inhibit&lt;/i&gt; port receives a&#10; token at the same time.  If no token has been received on the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt;&#10; port when a token is received on the &lt;i&gt;inhibit&lt;/i&gt; port, then no output is&#10; produced.  The inputs can be of any token type, and the output&#10; is constrained to be of a type at least that of the input.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Both the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port and the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; port are multiports.&#10; Generally, their widths should match. Otherwise, if the width of the&#10; &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; is greater than&#10; the width of the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt;, the extra input tokens will&#10; not appear on any output, although they will be consumed from&#10; the input port. If the width of the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; is greater&#10; than that of the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt;, then the last few&#10; channels of the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; will never emit tokens.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor is similar to the Sampler actor in that it modifies a&#10; stream of events based on the presence or absence of events from another&#10; input.  This actor reacts to the absence of the other event, whereas&#10; Sampler reacts to the presence of it.  </description>
  <author>Steve Neuendorffer and Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 2.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (neuendor)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (neuendor)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="inhibit">The inhibit port, which has type Token. If this port&#10;  does not receive a token, then the most recent token from the&#10;  &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port will be emitted on the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; port.</port>
</doc>
