<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="MostRecent" class="ptolemy.domains.de.lib.MostRecent">
  <description>
Output the most recent input token when the &lt;i&gt;trigger&lt;/i&gt; port&#10; receives a token.  If no token has been received on the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt;&#10; port when a token is received on the &lt;i&gt;trigger&lt;/i&gt; port, then the&#10; value of the &lt;i&gt;initialValue&lt;/i&gt; parameter is produced.  If, however,&#10; the &lt;i&gt;initialValue&lt;/i&gt; parameter contains no value, then no output is&#10; produced.  The inputs can be of any token type, but the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt;&#10; port is constrained to be of a type at least that of the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt;&#10; port and the &lt;i&gt;initialValue&lt;/i&gt; parameter (if it has a value).&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; Both the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port and the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; port are multiports.&#10; Generally, their widths should match. Otherwise, if the width of the&#10; &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; is greater than the width of the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt;, the extra&#10; input tokens will not appear on any output, although they will be&#10; consumed from the input port. If the width of the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; is&#10; greater than that of the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt;, then the last few channels of&#10; the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; will never emit tokens.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; The &lt;i&gt;trigger&lt;/i&gt; port is a multiport. Whenever a trigger is received&#10; on any channel the actor fires and produces an output. Multiple triggers&#10; with the same timestamp are considered as one trigger.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; Note: If the width of the input changes during execution, then the&#10; most recent inputs are forgotten, as if the execution of the model&#10; were starting over.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; This actor is similar to the Inhibit actor in that it modifies a&#10; stream of events based on the presence or absence of events from&#10; another input.  This actor reacts to the presence of the other event,&#10; whereas Inhibit reacts to the absence of it.&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt; This actor is different from the Register actor in that the input&#10; tokens are consumed from the input ports before the outputs are generated.&#10; Note that this actor is also different from the&#10; &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/Sampler.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.lib.Sampler&lt;/a&gt; actor, which produces the &lt;i&gt;current&lt;/i&gt; input on the&#10; output when a &lt;i&gt;trigger&lt;/i&gt; input is present, rather than the most&#10; recently received input signal.  </description>
  <author>Jie Liu, Edward A. Lee, Steve Neuendorffer, Elaine Cheong</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="trigger">The trigger port, which has undeclared type. If this port&#10;  receives a token, then the most recent token from the&#10;  &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port will be emitted on the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; port.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="initialValue">The value that is output when no input has yet been received.&#10;  If this is changed during execution, then the output will match&#10;  the new value until another input is received.&#10;  The type should be the same as the input port.</property>
</doc>
