<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="TableIcon" class="ptolemy.vergil.icon.TableIcon">
  <description>
An icon that displays the value of a variable of the container in a&#10; table. The attribute is assumed to be an instance of Variable, and its name&#10; is given by the parameter &lt;i&gt;variableName&lt;/i&gt;. Its value must be an&#10; array of records.  A subset of the fields in the records given by&#10; the &lt;i&gt;fields&lt;/i&gt; parameter is displayed in the icon.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 8.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (johnr)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.gui.ColorAttribute-->
    <property name="boxColor">Color of the box. This defaults to white.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="colorKey">A column name to use as a color key. If this string is&#10;  non-empty, then it specifies a column name that is used&#10;  to determine a color for each row. The value in that&#10;  row and column determines the color via a hash function,&#10;  so that if two rows are identical in that column, then&#10;  they are also identical in color.  This is a string that&#10;  defaults to empty, indicating that all rows should&#10;  be displayed in black.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="fields">The fields to display in the table.&#10;  This is an array of strings specifying the field&#10;  names to display. It defaults to ALL, which indicates&#10;  that all fields should be displayed.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="maxRows">The maximum number of rows to display. This is an integer, with&#10;  default value UNBOUNDED.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="variableName">The name of the variable in the container&#10;  whose value should be displayed in the icon. The variable&#10;  value must be an array of records. This is a string that&#10;  defaults to the empty string.</property>
</doc>
