<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Processor" class="ptolemy.domains.csp.demo.BusContention.Processor">
  <description>
A CSP actor that contends for a shared resource. A Processor actor&#10; is granted access to the shared resource via a Controller actor.&#10; The processor must connect to a Controller via its requestInput&#10; and requestOutput ports. The shared resource that the Processor&#10; attempts to gain access to is a Memory actor. The memory actor&#10; is connected to via the Processor's memoryInput and memoryOutput&#10; ports.&#10;&#10; The Processor actor has four informal states. In state one it&#10; determines at what time it will next attempt to access the&#10; shared resource. It will then place a request at the determined&#10; time. In state two, it will wait to see if it has been granted&#10; the request. The Processor enters state three if it is granted&#10; the request. It remains in state three for 300 milliseconds,&#10; accesses the shared resource and then returns to state two. If&#10; the Processor is denied its request, then it enters four and&#10; remains in that state for 300 milliseconds after which it returns&#10; to state four.&#10;&#10; In addition to the resource contention features of Processor,&#10; it can also notify an ExecEventListener as this actor jumps between&#10; its three states. Such notification is enabled by adding an&#10; ExecEventListener to this actor's listener list via the addListeners()&#10; method. Listeners can be removed via the removeListeners() method.&#10; ExecEventListeners are currently implemented to serve as conduits&#10; between Ptolemy II and the Diva graphical user interface.  </description>
  <author>John S. Davis II</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 0.3</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (davisj)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="requestInput">The resource request input port. Resources are granted through&#10;  this port. The type of this port is BaseType.BOOLEAN.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="requestOutput">The resource request output port. Resource requests are made&#10;  through this port with a token that includes the requestor's&#10;  priority level. The type of this port is BaseType.INT.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="memoryInput">The input port through which this actor receives data from&#10;  the shared resource. The type of this port is BaseType.GENERAL.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="memoryOutput">The output port through which this actor sends data to the&#10;  shared resource. The type of this port is BaseType.STRING.</port>
</doc>
