<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="PteraDirector" class="ptolemy.domains.ptera.kernel.PteraDirector">
  <description>
A Ptera director implements the Event Relationship Graph semantics, and can be&#10; used by Ptera controllers (instances of &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/domains/ptera/kernel/PteraController.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.domains.ptera.kernel.PteraController&lt;/a&gt;) in Ptera modal&#10; models (instances of &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../ptolemy/domains/ptera/kernel/PteraModalModel.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.domains.ptera.kernel.PteraModalModel&lt;/a&gt;). This director has an event queue&#10; where events can be scheduled and are ordered by their time stamps. Events are&#10; processed according to their time-stamp order. Actions of the events are&#10; executed when the events are processed.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Between events there may be scheduling relations. If an event schedules another&#10; to occur after a certain amount of model time, then the other event is placed&#10; in the event queue when the first event is processed. Scheduling relations may&#10; be guarded by boolean expressions.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Each Ptera controller transparently creates a Ptera director inside. For a&#10; Ptera controller that serves as refinement of an event in another Ptera&#10; controller, the Ptera director in it invokes the fireAt() method of the Ptera&#10; director in the containing Ptera controller. When multiple events are scheduled&#10; in one firing of the inner Ptera director, only one invocation of fireAt() is&#10; made in postfire() with the most imminent event as the parameter.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This director can be used in DE as a contained model of computation. It can&#10; also be used to control timed or untimed models of computation, such as DE,&#10; dataflow, and FSM.  </description>
  <author>Thomas Huining Feng</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 8.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (tfeng)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (tfeng)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="LIFO">A Boolean parameter that decides whether simultaneous events should be&#10;  placed in the event queue in the last-in-first-out (LIFO) fashion or&#10;  not.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute-->
    <property name="controllerName">Attribute specifying the name of the Ptera controller in the&#10;  container of this director. This director must have a Ptera&#10;  controller that has the same container as this director,&#10;  otherwise an IllegalActionException will be thrown when action&#10;  methods of this director are called.</property>
</doc>
