<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="InterfaceAutomatonTransition" class="ptolemy.domains.modal.kernel.ia.InterfaceAutomatonTransition">
  <description>
A Transition for Interface Automaton. In the Interface Automata paper&#10; written by Luca de Alfaro and Henzinger, transitions are called actions.&#10; However, the name action conflicts with the Action class in this package,&#10; so this class uses the name transition.  There are three types of transitions:&#10; input, output, and internal. Each transition has a label. The labels for&#10; input, output, and internal transitions end with &quot;?&quot;, &quot;!&quot;, and &quot;;&quot;,&#10; respectively. The type of transition is determined by the ending character&#10; of the label this way. Each input transition corresponds to an input port of&#10; the InterfaceAutomaton that contains it, and its label, excluding the&#10; ending &quot;?&quot;, must be the same as the input port name; Similarly, each output&#10; transition corresponds to an output port, and its label, excluding the&#10; ending &quot;!&quot;, must be the same as the output port name;  Each internal&#10; transitions corresponds to a parameter of the InterfaceAutomaton that&#10; contains it, and its label, excluding the ending &quot;;&quot;, must be the same as&#10; the parameter name.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The guard of each transition is set automatically. Users should not set&#10; the guard. For an input transition, the guard is set to &amp;lt;inputPort&amp;gt;&#10; _isPresent,&#10; where &amp;lt;inputPort&amp;gt; is the port corresponding to this transition; For output&#10; and internal transitions, the guard is set to true. Each of the output&#10; and internal transitions contain an Action. The expression of the Action&#10; is also set automatically. For output transition, the action is set to&#10; &amp;lt;outputPort&amp;gt;=true, where &amp;lt;outputPort&amp;gt; is the output port&#10; corresponding to this transition; for internal transition, the action is set&#10; to &amp;lt;parameter&amp;gt;=true, where &amp;lt;parameter&amp;gt; is the parameter&#10; corresponding to this transition.  </description>
  <author>Yuhong Xiong, Xiaojun Liu and Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 8.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (yuhong)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (yuhong)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute-->
    <property name="label">The label of this transition. Must ends with &quot;?&quot; or &quot;!&quot; or &quot;;&quot;</property>
</doc>
