<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="BooleanSwitch" class="ptolemy.backtrack.automatic.ptolemy.actor.lib.BooleanSwitch">
  <description>
Split an input stream onto two output ports depending on a&#10; boolean control input.  In an&#10; iteration, if an input token is available at the &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt; input,&#10; that token is read, and its value is noted.  Its value specifies the&#10; output port that should be written to in this and subsequent iterations,&#10; until another &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt; input is provided. If no &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt;&#10; input is provided, then the inputs are routed to the &lt;i&gt;falseOutput&lt;/i&gt; port.&#10; In each iteration, at most one token on each channel of the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port&#10; is read and sent to the corresponding channel of the&#10; &lt;i&gt;trueOutput&lt;/i&gt; port or the &lt;i&gt;falseOutput&lt;/i&gt; port, depending on the&#10; most recently received &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt; input.&#10; If the input has width greater than an output port, then&#10; some input tokens will be discarded (those on input channels for which&#10; there is no corresponding output channel).&#10; Because tokens are&#10; immutable, the same Token is sent to the output, rather than a copy.&#10; The &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port may receive Tokens of any type.&#10; &lt;p&gt;Note that the this actor may be used in Synchronous Dataflow (SDF)&#10; models, but only under certain circumstances. Specifically, downstream&#10; actors will be fired whether a token is sent to them or not.&#10; This will only work if the downstream actors specifically check to&#10; see whether input tokens are available.  </description>
  <author>Steve Neuendorffer</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 2.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (neuendor)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (neuendor)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="control">Input that selects one of the other input ports.  The type is&#10; boolean.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="input">The input port.  The type can be anything. This is a multiport,&#10; and input tokens on all channels are routed to corresponding&#10; channels on the output port, if there are such channels.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="trueOutput">Output for tokens on the true path.  The type is at least the&#10; type of the input.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="falseOutput">Output for tokens on the false path.  The type is at least the&#10; type of the input.</port>
</doc>
