<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="BooleanSelect" class="ptolemy.backtrack.automatic.ptolemy.actor.lib.BooleanSelect">
  <description>
Conditionally merge the streams at two input ports&#10; depending on the value of the boolean control input.&#10; In the first firing, this actor consumes a token from the&#10; &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt; input port.&#10; The token at the &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt; input specifies the&#10; input port that should be read from in the next firing.&#10; If the &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt;&#10; token is false, then the &lt;i&gt;falseInput&lt;/i&gt; port is used,&#10; otherwise the &lt;i&gt;trueInput&lt;/i&gt; port is used. In the next&#10; firing, tokens are consumed from the specified&#10; port and sent to the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; port.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The actor is able to fire if either it needs a new control&#10; token and there is a token on the &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt; port, or&#10; it has read a control token and there is a token on every&#10; channel of the specified input port.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; If the input port that is read has width greater than an output port, then&#10; some input tokens will be discarded (those on input channels for which&#10; there is no corresponding output channel).&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Because tokens are immutable, the same Token is sent&#10; to the output, rather than a copy.  The &lt;i&gt;trueInput&lt;/i&gt; and&#10; &lt;i&gt;falseInput&lt;/i&gt; port may receive Tokens of any type.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor is designed to be used with the DDF or PN director.&#10; It should not be used with&#10; SDF because the number of tokens it consumes is not fixed.&#10; It probably also does not make sense to use it&#10; with SR or DE, because it takes two firings to transfer&#10; a token to the output. In those domains, &lt;a href=&quot;../../../../../../ptolemy/actor/lib/BooleanMultiplexor.xml&quot;&gt;ptolemy.actor.lib.BooleanMultiplexor&lt;/a&gt;&#10;  makes more sense.&#10; Unlike BooleanMultiplexor actor, this actor&#10; does not discard input tokens on the port that it does not read.  </description>
  <author>Steve Neuendorffer, Adam Cataldo, Edward A. Lee, Gang Zhou</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 2.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (neuendor)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (neuendor)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="trueInput">Input for tokens on the true path.  The type can be anything.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="falseInput">Input for tokens on the false path.  The type can be anything.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="control">Input that selects one of the other input ports.  The type is&#10; BooleanToken.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">The output port.  The type is at least the type of&#10; &lt;i&gt;trueInput&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;falseInput&lt;/i&gt;</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="trueInput_tokenConsumptionRate">This parameter provides token consumption rate for &lt;i&gt;trueInput&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; The type is int.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="falseInput_tokenConsumptionRate">This parameter provides token consumption rate for &lt;i&gt;falseInput&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; The type is int.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="control_tokenConsumptionRate">This parameter provides token consumption rate for &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; The type is int.</property>
</doc>
