<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Interpolator" class="ptolemy.backtrack.automatic.ptolemy.actor.lib.Interpolator">
  <description>
&lt;p&gt;Produce an interpolation based on the parameters.&#10; This class uses the Interpolation class in the math package to compute&#10; the interpolation.&#10; The &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; parameter specifies a sequence of values&#10; to produce at the output.  The &lt;i&gt;indexes&lt;/i&gt; parameter specifies&#10; when those values should be produced.&#10; The values and indexes parameters must both contain&#10; arrays, and have equal lengths or an exception will be thrown.&#10; The &lt;i&gt;indexes&lt;/i&gt; array must be increasing and non-negative.&#10; The values are periodic if the &lt;i&gt;period&lt;/i&gt; parameter contains a&#10; positive value. In this case, the period must be greater than the&#10; largest index, and values within the index range 0 to (period-1) are&#10; repeated indefinitely.  If the period is zero, the values are not&#10; periodic, and the values outside the range of the indexes are&#10; considered to be 0.0.  The &lt;i&gt;order&lt;/i&gt; parameter&#10; specifies which order of interpolation to apply  whenever the&#10; iteration count does not match an index in &lt;i&gt;indexes&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; The Interpolation class currently supports zero, first, and third&#10; order interpolations. The default parameter are those set in the&#10; Interpolation class.&lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor counts iterations.  Whenever the iteration count matches an entry&#10; in the &lt;i&gt;indexes&lt;/i&gt; array, the corresponding entry (at the same position)&#10; in the &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; array is produced at the output.  Whenever the iteration&#10; count does not match a value in the &lt;i&gt;indexes&lt;/i&gt; array, an interpolation&#10; of the values is produced at the output.&lt;/p&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Output type is DoubleToken.&lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Sarah Packman, Yuhong Xiong</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 0.3</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (yuhong)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (yuhong)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="indexes">The indexes at which the specified values will be produced.&#10; This parameter is an array of integers, with default value {0, 1}.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="order">The order of interpolation for non-index iterations.&#10; This parameter must contain an IntToken.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="period">The period of the reference values.&#10; This parameter must contain an IntToken.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="values">The values that will be produced at the specified indexes.&#10; This parameter is an array, with default value {1.0, 0.0}.</property>
</doc>
