<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="RecursiveLattice" class="ptolemy.backtrack.automatic.ptolemy.actor.lib.RecursiveLattice">
  <description>
A recursive (all-pole) filter with a lattice structure.&#10; The coefficients of such a filter are called &quot;reflection coefficients.&quot;&#10; Recursive lattice filters are typically used as synthesis filters for&#10; random processes because it is easy to ensure that they are stable.&#10; A recursive lattice filter is stable if its reflection&#10; coefficients are all less than unity in magnitude.  To get the&#10; reflection coefficients for a linear predictor for a particular&#10; random process, you can use the LevinsonDurbin actor.&#10; The inputs and outputs are of type double.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The default reflection coefficients correspond to the following&#10; transfer function:&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10; 1&#10; H(z) =  --------------------------------------&#10; 1 - 2z&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; + 1.91z&lt;sup&gt;-2&lt;/sup&gt; - 0.91z&lt;sup&gt;-3&lt;/sup&gt; + 0.205z&lt;sup&gt;-4&lt;/sup&gt;&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The structure of the filter is as follows:&#10; &lt;pre&gt;&#10; y[0]          y[1]                 y[n-1]           y[n]&#10; X(n) ---(+)-&amp;gt;--o--&amp;gt;----(+)-&amp;gt;--o---&amp;gt;-- ... -&amp;gt;--(+)-&amp;gt;--o---&amp;gt;---o---&amp;gt;  Y(n)&#10; \   /          \   /                  \   /        |&#10; +Kn /        +Kn-1 /                  +K1 /         |&#10; X              X                      X          |&#10; -Kn \        -Kn-1 \                  -K1 \         V&#10; /   \          /   \                  /   \        |&#10; (+)-&amp;lt;--o--[z]--(+)-&amp;lt;--o--[z]- ... -&amp;lt;--(+)-&amp;lt;--o--[z]--/&#10; w[1]           w[2]                   w[n]&#10; &lt;/pre&gt;&#10; where the [z] are unit delays and the (+) are adders&#10; and &quot;y&quot; and &quot;w&quot; are variables representing the state of the filter.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The reflection (or partial-correlation (PARCOR))&#10; coefficients should be specified&#10; right to left, K1 to Kn as above.&#10; Using exactly the same coefficients in the&#10; Lattice actor will result in precisely the inverse transfer function.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; Note that the definition of reflection coefficients is not quite universal&#10; in the literature. The reflection coefficients in reference [2]&#10; are the negative of the ones used by this actor, which&#10; correspond to the definition in most other texts,&#10; and to the definition of partial-correlation (PARCOR)&#10; coefficients in the statistics literature.&#10; The signs of the coefficients used in this actor are appropriate for values&#10; given by the LevinsonDurbin actor.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;[1]&#10; J. Makhoul, &quot;Linear Prediction: A Tutorial Review&quot;,&#10; &lt;i&gt;Proc. IEEE&lt;/i&gt;, Vol. 63, pp. 561-580, Apr. 1975.&#10; &lt;p&gt;[2]&#10; S. M. Kay, &lt;i&gt;Modern Spectral Estimation: Theory &amp;amp; Application&lt;/i&gt;,&#10; Prentice-Hall, Englewood Cliffs, NJ, 1988.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee, Christopher Hylands, Steve Neuendorffer</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (cxh)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (cxh)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="reflectionCoefficients">The reflection coefficients.  This is an array of doubles with&#10; default value {0.804534, -0.820577, 0.521934, -0.205}. These&#10; are the reflection coefficients for the linear predictor of a&#10; particular random process.</property>
</doc>
