<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="Select" class="ptolemy.backtrack.automatic.ptolemy.actor.lib.Select">
  <description>
&lt;p&gt;A polymorphic select, which routes specified input channels to the&#10; output.  This actor has two input ports, the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt; port for&#10; data, and the &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt; port to select which input channel to&#10; read.  In an iteration, if an input token is available at the&#10; &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt; input, that token is read, and its value is noted.  Its&#10; value specifies the input channel that should be read next. If an&#10; input token is available on the specified channel of the &lt;i&gt;input&lt;/i&gt;&#10; port, then that token is read and sent to the output.&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The actor indicates a willingness to fire in its prefire() method&#10; if there is an input available on the channel specified by the most&#10; recently seen token on the &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt; port.  If no token has ever&#10; been received on the &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt; port, then channel zero is assumed&#10; to be the one to read.  If the value of the most recently received&#10; token on the &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt; port is out of range (less than zero, or&#10; greater than or equal to the width of the input), then the actor will&#10; not fire() (although it will continue to consume tokens on the&#10; &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt; port in its prefire() method).&#10; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; This actor is similar to the {  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Green (neuendor)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (liuj)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="control">Input port for control tokens, which specify the output channel&#10; to produce data on.  The type is int.</port>
</doc>
