<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="SequentialClock" class="ptolemy.backtrack.automatic.ptolemy.actor.lib.SequentialClock">
  <description>
A clock source for sequence-capable domains.  This actor is considerably&#10; simpler than the Clock actor.  On each firing, it produces the next value&#10; from its &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; parameter, and schedules another firing at&#10; a future time determined by the &lt;i&gt;offsets&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;period&lt;/i&gt; parameters.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor can be used in the DE domain&#10; to generate a sequence of events at regularly spaced&#10; intervals.  It cannot be used in CT, because CT will invoke it at times&#10; where it has not requested a firing, and it will inappropriately advance&#10; to the next output value.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; At the beginning of each time interval of length given by &lt;i&gt;period&lt;/i&gt;,&#10; it initiates a sequence of output events with values given by&#10; &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; and offset into the period given by &lt;i&gt;offsets&lt;/i&gt;.&#10; These parameters contain arrays, which are required to have the same length.&#10; The &lt;i&gt;offsets&lt;/i&gt; array must be nondecreasing and nonnegative,&#10; or an exception will be thrown when it is set.&#10; Moreover, its largest entry must be smaller than &lt;i&gt;period&lt;/i&gt;&#10; or an exception will be thrown by the fire() method.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; parameter by default&#10; contains an array of IntTokens with values 1 and 0.  The default&#10; &lt;i&gt;offsets&lt;/i&gt; array is {0.0, 1.0}.  Thus, the default output will be&#10; alternating 1 and 0 with 50% duty cycle.  The default period&#10; is 2.0.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The actor uses the fireAt() method of the director to request&#10; firing at the beginning of each period plus each of the offsets.&#10; It assumes that all of its firings are in response to such&#10; requests.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; The type of the output can be any token type. This type is inferred from the&#10; element type of the &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; parameter.&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; This actor is a timed source; the untimed version is Pulse.  </description>
  <author>Edward A. Lee</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 1.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (eal)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (yuhong)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">The output port.  The type of this port is determined by from&#10; the &lt;i&gt;values&lt;/i&gt; parameter.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="offsets">The offsets at which the specified values will be produced.&#10; This parameter must contain an array of doubles, and it defaults&#10; to {0.0, 1.0}.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="period">The period of the output waveform.&#10; This parameter must contain a DoubleToken, and defaults to 2.0.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="values">The values that will be produced at the specified offsets.&#10; This parameter must contain an ArrayToken, and defaults to {1, 0}.</property>
</doc>
