<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="ParameterEstimator" class="org.ptolemy.machineLearning.hmm.ParameterEstimator">
  <description>
&lt;p&gt;This actor implements the Expectation-Maximization(EM) algorithm for&#10;parameter estimation in graphical stochastic models. Two types of fundamental&#10;types of Bayesian Network models: &lt;i&gt;Mixture Model(MM)&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Hidden Markov&#10;Model(HMM)&lt;/i&gt; are supported. The input is an array of observations of arbitrary&#10;length and the outputs are the parameter estimates for the chosen model.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;&#10;The output ports reflect the parameter estimates of Gaussian MM or HMM. The Mixture&#10;Model is parameterized by &lt;i&gt;M&lt;/i&gt; states, each distributed according to a distribution&#10;specified by the &lt;i&gt;emissionDistribution&lt;/i&gt; parameter. Currently, the actor supports&#10;Gaussian emissions.&#10;The &lt;i&gt;mean&lt;/i&gt;  is a double array output containing the mean estimates and&#10;&lt;i&gt;sigma&lt;/i&gt; is a double array output containing standard deviation estimates of&#10;each mixture component. If the &lt;i&gt;modelType&lt;/i&gt; is HMM, then an additional output,&#10;&lt;i&gt;transitionMatrix&lt;/i&gt; is provided, which is an estimate of the transition matrix&#10;governing the Markovian process representing the hidden state evolution.&#10;If the &lt;i&gt;modelType&lt;/i&gt; is MM, this port outputs a double array with the prior&#10;probability estimates of the mixture components.&#10;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;&#10;&lt;i&gt;iterations&lt;/i&gt; is the maximum number of EM iterations until the log-likelihood&#10;P(observations | model parameters) remain within &lt;i&gt;likelihoodThreshold&lt;/i&gt; neighborhood&#10;of the previous likelihood estimate. The default likelihood threshold is set to 1E-4 and&#10;for precise applications, may be set to a lower positive value.&#10;&#10;&#10;The actor iterates over the parameter estimates using the EM algorithm. If, at any&#10;point, the estimates become NaN, the user is notified that the algorithm did not&#10;converge and is given the option to randomize initial guesses to reiterate.&#10;&#10;&#10; &lt;p&gt;&#10; &lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&#10; &lt;p&gt;[1]&#10; Jordan, Michael I., et al. &lt;i&gt;An introduction to variational methods for graphical&#10; models&lt;/i&gt;, Springer Netherlands, 1998.&#10; &lt;p&gt;[2]&#10; Bilmes, Jeff A. &lt;i&gt;A gentle tutorial of the EM algorithm and its application&#10; to parameter estimation for Gaussian mixture and hidden Markov models.&lt;/i&gt;&#10; International Computer Science Institute 4.510 (1998): 126.  </description>
  <author>Ilge Akkaya</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (ilgea)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (ilgea)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="input">The input port that provides the sample observations.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="likelihoodOut">An output port of type Double that contains the likelyhood.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="priorEstimates">The vector estimate for the prior distribution on the set of states.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="transitionMatrix">The transition matrix estimate obtained by iterating over the observation set.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="A0">The user-provided initial guess of the transition probability matrix.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="likelihoodThreshold">The user-provided threshold on the minimum desired improvement on likelihood per iteration.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="maxIterations">The user-provided maximum number of allowed iterations of the Alpha-Beta Recursion.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="nStates">Number of states of the HMM.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="randomizeGuessVectors">Boolean that determines whether or not to randomize input guess vectors.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="priorDistribution">The user-provided initial guess on the prior probability distribution.</property>
</doc>
