<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="BaseUnitConcept" class="ptolemy.data.ontologies.lattice.unit.BaseUnitConcept">
  <description>
A concept in the unitSystem ontology for a specific unit for&#10;  a specific physical dimension.&#10;&#10;  A unit for a base dimension is defined by the physical dimension it&#10;  measures and the multiplication factor and offset values required to convert&#10;  a value in its unit measurement to a unit measurement in the SI unit for this&#10;  dimension.&#10;&#10;  For example, to represent the units for measuring temperature in degrees&#10;  Fahrenheit, the multiplication factor and offset are specified as what is&#10;  needed to convert Fahrenheit to Kelvin:&#10;  &lt;ul&gt;&#10;  &lt;li&gt;unitFactor = 5.0/9.0&#10;  &lt;li&gt;unitOffset = 459.67&#10;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#10;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;To convert a temperature measurement value in degrees F to degrees K, apply&#10;  the formula:&lt;br&gt;&#10;  &lt;code&gt;value in K = (value in F + unitOffset) * unitFactor&lt;/code&gt;&#10;  &lt;/p&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;Inversely, to convert a measurement from the SI unit (K) to this unit (F),&#10;  apply this formula:&lt;br&gt;&#10;  &lt;code&gt;value in F = (value in K) / unitFactor - unitOffset&lt;/code&gt;&#10;  &lt;/p&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;So far temperature is the only dimension that requires an offset. All&#10;  the other dimensions only require a multiplication&#10;  factor, so their offset is always zero. For example,&#10;  To represent the position dimension units in kilometers (km):&lt;/p&gt;&#10;  &lt;ul&gt;&#10;  &lt;li&gt;unitFactor = 1000.0&#10;  &lt;li&gt;unitOffset = 0.0&#10;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;The SI unit for position is meters (m) so the kilometers unitFactor is 1000.0&#10;  and there is zero offset.&lt;p&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;This class is an infinite concept so that an arbitrary number of different&#10;  unit measurements can be represented for any physical dimension. All that is&#10;  required is specify the name of units and the multiplication factor and offset&#10;  needed to convert the unit to the SI unit for that dimension.&lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Charles Shelton</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Red (cshelton)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Red (cshelton)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
</doc>
