<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD DocML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/DocML_1.dtd">
<doc name="HTMLPageAssembler" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.export.html.jsoup.HTMLPageAssembler">
  <description>
&lt;p&gt;&#10;HTMLPageAssembler reads contents from its ports and appends them into the&#10;corresponding parts in the template file that must satisfy the following&#10;requirement: for each port, there must be a corresponding DOM object whose ID is&#10;the same as the port name in the template file, or in the content provided to&#10;another port that is created before this port.&#10;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;&#10;HTMLPageAssembler processes the ports in the order that they are added to it.&#10;Each port can consists of a single or multiple channels. In the latter case,&#10;contents from multiple channels are appended in the order that they are&#10;connected to this port.&#10;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;&#10;The content for a channel can be a string or an array of strings. HTML scripts,&#10;such as JavaScript, can also be part of the content. For a long content, it is&#10;better to first store the content in a separated file, then read this file using&#10;the FileReader actor to provide the content to the port. A demo is available at&#10;$PTII/ptolemy/vergil/basic/export/html/demo/PageAssembler/PageAssembler.xml. If the content is&#10;provided through a StringConst actor, only the tags defined in the standard Java&#10;library (javax.swing.text.html.HTML.Tag) can be supported. If the content is&#10;read from a file, then all valid HTML tags can be supported. Unknown tags are&#10;ignored without throwing any exceptions.&#10;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;&#10;The content of the final HTML page is sent to the output port and saved&#10;to a file if specified.&#10;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;&#10;For more information, please refer to &quot;Manual for Creating Web Pages&quot; in Ptolemy.&#10;&lt;/p&gt;  </description>
  <author>Baobing (Brian) Wang, Elizabeth Latronico</author>
  <version>$Id$</version>
  <since>Ptolemy II 10.0</since>
  <Pt.ProposedRating>Yellow (bwang)</Pt.ProposedRating>
  <Pt.AcceptedRating>Yellow (bwang)</Pt.AcceptedRating>
    <!--ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort-->
    <port name="output">The output port, which is of type String.</port>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter-->
    <property name="htmlTitle">The title of the generated HTML page.  The default value&#10;  is the string &quot;Page Generated by HTMLPageAssembler&quot;.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.FileParameter-->
    <property name="outputFile">The file to save the content of the generated page.&#10;  The default value is &quot;result.html&quot;.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter-->
    <property name="saveToFile">Specify whether the content of the generated page should be save to a&#10; separated file.  The default value is a boolean with the value false.</property>
    <!--ptolemy.data.expr.FileParameter-->
    <property name="template">The template file. The default value is &quot;template.html&quot;.</property>
</doc>
